[
	{
		"unique_id": "010101", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEh33y+ntNGeQF2cfpmvDXaU0dXLsWqjPZ+7tiZ5/Z13JgFp1/HPU47H49kdPga1Y7J2MeTYCao58iNHJ0+Hy1HRTc8VLl5Bg4ZIacudJwzPyNl7g5yl/ITMGazT5irRHt5w=", 
		"answer": "24a7aYPw2A3ztZNNEpXxewRV97Ab2jVkwQs=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxDn9pc5Ehj9xujsdWTWQ2cSrHGMX6p3YzHqR+fRbezsyp5lPhyIg187+nnR47b/9FoKm6Fe+s6ceC0MbY4v3N/J1uj7y3JAJ8MEiYNz9pkaPOZF3zK4ZtfeM756wS6NIkDkJy21AXlm1CbXhGhF6IK18We1Ud8z01d8u0Fkhvst3aFUie5mL8ww", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Maximizing profits for businesses", 
		"option_b": "Solving political challenges", 
		"option_c": "Scarcity", 
		"option_d": "Increasing global trade", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010102", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEhX33L38PWrcD2cfpHrDVKJ3dXWjVr6Ca+7xx5h8LlmazVJ1snDTr6P5+18Gga8b/YaaMCwGe498iN+Pl/D/wXhTc9ZLipV+5Y4Wc/ofjvTME4QyojzKGgToK8xWs94=", 
		"answer": "25y2bZf12Brj8os0Eg3n1e3zLCveBnYGrG2IQeFqFdIfokMTpK+n9Uidq/GJ", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw2Rjm+4AuVRvhhfL5dW3FD2QYr3OKXKQ0ZHnmFKnHa+ntiZh3Z0iBiBtr/WbTr6Tk/lwBz6lV7c6SdSwXd4Rh25Cd3+G3zXxRPNRQm45x4doQerRIzSuketObIb5+3GGQIlewYzCuEGJ9liTCg3NY6I2+4TC0RtF3xhog1oB34swvfNaR3eiA7V+ujwWHzzuBWrJgBFecsYwkU0sHyTgq+JHCNad2vho2", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Lack of natural resources", 
		"option_b": "Inefficient supply networks", 
		"option_c": "Competition from other economies", 
		"option_d": "Limited production capacity", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010103", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRzp+IsvXxfh0b32JivTEWcVqmuGVuNjeWXrFLPKa63pxoV6Z2DLuVN+skHDoqnk/xMAieh16JqWfywQQskvyd6Nl+3khHJOPdVNnoVg4Z5faPxFjDK/fdPSLv96wXzAKEOwczG4RHN4lSLFg39XpMOo9i+0W9Z3zxNyk4R348cxNdSMhurfafiCOoPcXQoyPxMweXww", 
		"answer": "25S8aZyz4hTj441ivGDnFKNoXakdjm7IENUvOw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwYYKzkRj+45cpUAvmwO6/CSnkC2dRlHqCXrd8MH7lFInDeuTxx4RNZRydghta9nfL45b9/kcHz6lV7c6XeSULcoJowMSal+z+1zFCPMhQiIlw8Y4Wc/oA2DLtYNzeYP1iz32TLkbxa3muB3h7mz2WhXoWrYC0+yi2XdkkgtCL9wBsX9ED/eBAiMKos1Q=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "John Maynard Keynes", 
		"option_b": "Karl Marx", 
		"option_c": "Adam Smith", 
		"option_d": "Milton Friedman", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010104", 
		"question": "25C7Z5/83BDp5MUzRgv2zPjsdX/YBiIUoHCNXa59czHiV7PLeOTqwJJiZ1OPzVZ6/H3PraG8t0QHhqtTqYeRZi0PaI4v9++26NvI+05+DIoElolk4ZYWdPtPyHHte9fYNe5v2mePKQmwcDi6ATw0kTzGhnNPpYa14Wv7Uc40gjIaqGcaCAkN6qfBTb9xd+M=", 
		"answer": "24WqZ5f6xVmst6kvQQ2wA5LEW6JhcSOEUJJuR2+COA==", 
		"explanation": "25C7Z5/83BDpt4QjRhfkzOn2MHiQAnAU42uLXbBxMGXrVbOCa+P9xpphJk+azVh0/HXDs7Hjt18GhK0b+ZyQdisXMstjx8Oam6T7zWdEP89MlY92qNoQf/dV3Dy5fdvVbL55z2mFawXxaT39AX1kmD7Ph3lYvMEvXMCdSUIrhagjsvooP45K", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "P,ro,fi,t & L,os,s", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010105", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kR/r9JEvQF7xyvPrJ2LSFnYUsD+XXeNgeHSjUK7Ua//twINoZ1WHzV54/XjJrqzzt1wam6tU5IuMMCMOcYVoiNSA0eLy1nRPJ4ZHlZV88IgWeecAyjKheNvMKfBpjn2JKkz8Ziv9AXN7mj7bg38WuIy3/CSyUclogkavuhydVzFe7DW9WJqILcE=", 
		"answer": "24O5epjy0xDm/pE5Ehf8hfTxIW7CDWMd436NVuNxaGXmRqnDYq34yJRlKE6az8qCC/F3dggDFJ3l9HJPVtE=", 
		"explanation": "25C7Z5/83BDpt5EoVxHgzPjsdWbRGiIIqnqPVuNweWfmRrTHLuLr3ZR+KlmazV9u9zbSrOX29lAbgLpIqYKWeydDcIp73cKI26TlwWJOJtRHn5M+pJIKcfVOjC+oZ9vOMv1r3SLAL0zjczavDXN1mHHUi39dr5G04Cm/GJoy1BZw4gKn5NYIJyRddewNeDlBXA==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Similar socio-political conditions", 
		"option_b": "Homogeneous human behavior", 
		"option_c": "External economic challenges", 
		"option_d": "Variability in internal and external factors", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010106", 
		"question": "24GwbdH+0BDkt4YoUxL+wPP4MCvEC2MF43qAXa17fXjmR+fEb+77iZ5iZ0iGzV514WPUpuXk/1ZPjr5a4IKecisPd592iN+Pl/by1WRIIcNA2od9654MPPVOyH2+ccbNKf1r3S6UL1f/cj61RGBmmyHTmDxGuoy/4CSvXdU5gBYzhoZ75NwlfNaR3eis13KHuTm940SuClxPFI2YYfMRbTBm+TNOp/w=", 
		"answer": "25Gxe4Xh2Bv/44wvXF7cwOnoOnnbQdU8Imr2WYNjpLWQf6ZT0xw=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHixBz544wvXF7gwPv6J3iQF21Rt3eGEqB8cX3vUanFa637yph/KFGAiEg79HfFpuX5+RMJmqRd4IKTeSwEPp9nzZCH0uHz1zFONYZQkoV79toPc+RVwDy5fdvVYNd6jmaJIE38bj61EGM0gDnTynVbuIyp4Sa1V993zxNylJJx4cw1MtDfybqc7Fi7kg+N0juSSa1lEl2NrI685AORpYcs9cmIvDPV8Oe5m/bXsNsYdglQs49sa1KykOgI9mo9V869axtO//CQZV3+NDqqJRsJ8MTtlnps0pUmT2J04BAGhoZaa9Z2xNjjsz00LI1rGzf6sEFS0Z1/WgTUHqdqVkusgXJg5G05UwzzCQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Di,st,ri,bu,tio,n N,et,wo,rk", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010107", 
		"question": "24KxfJn631n+/4BgQBvzyfC/Om2QBmEerXCOW6BnPDH0XKbWLuLozIVwNV+BhFV8smbUqqvz/kMDiuhP6IWaY2ITbI5szdSM2efyhGZJNsgEnoV+8pMRe7RJwimiNMDTJb5nwHqSLkbxZDC4FzB7knHen3FXpsO4+im/QdkjgBQ8ksd86Ms1L96Q1+We6UaxiAHdnh+UVeTqIQ0w1FiDfKRkhe4=", 
		"answer": "24e5fJj83xjmt4ElURfhzPLxeGbRCGsfpD0H5qfcZdAXkmjzycqYeXgN", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20hbk+IgpUV7mzfjwJ2LVECIQsXrDUKJndXWjW6mCa/XuzJRlJkiAglVosnnA47fx41oAgalXqYucfywMc4JsiNKM3+XhzX5Tc8Rd2ol84JMJdfBVzTG+NNXVJL5h3GmBKUzqZi20C35n1gfjcLHj4muvf80038HSjXw=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Psychological motivations", 
		"option_b": "Rational decision-making", 
		"option_c": "Social interactions", 
		"option_d": "Genetic predispositions", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010108", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0hbk5JEpRgv3y+m/MGfVDmcftz+QV7FidWKjVbSCb639yINwK0WamRt9/WSGt631t1oBm7pS6o+LdWICcI8vzcaMxany0n5NJc9KncBx7JsNffdUyS/te9KbJf1hwGGNLkbjOHvlpBVYSRwzow/A2FjsRzTf", 
		"answer": "25a3ZoX63wzl4pZgdwj9yejrPGTeQ20X42+RU6BgeXLmFK7MeuK+3Z90KE6Qz+pLNpvF9UpQ+K7S+/GTdrM=", 
		"explanation": "25C7Z5/83BDp5MUoUw2ywfjpMGffE2cV43CWRuN7djHxUabOI+H3z5IxN06Ijk9y8XPV46T+8xMHjrsb6oGRZCsNa4R629yQl+Hhy31XNsIEmIFh4Z5fc/oAzzKjYNHWMPF8z3yZZ1f1dCyxEGM0lT/SynlOuIap/CK1V98kggUi5ZCoZs7rpVxeIy86ndw=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Fixed set of principles", 
		"option_b": "Consistent government policies", 
		"option_c": "Continuous Evolution of practice into theory", 
		"option_d": "Predictable human behavior", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010109", 
		"question": "25y2KIX71Fnp+Is0VwbmhfL5dW7TDGwernaAQe80Z3nmWufNYOi+yJt9MliMnhtv/TbSq6Cw9FwBjK1L/c6QdmI/PJhsycKK3vDuiE0Dc9FMm5Qy6Y8TaP1GzT6oYNHfYP1hwGCPM0TkbjazRHR7kSKWg2gWq4Kp5z73FN85wxQihZJ07Nw1MtDfzaCWqEirlQOM337RR7skA1GKutu66EbcoY40us6MpTvU+qu7QiA9g2ca8whvs9dJWwH12A==", 
		"answer": "24C2ZJj+2A3v88UoRxPzy73oNGXEECIGqmuLEq99fXj3UaOCfOjtxoJjJFmaz1+mDKJ81VwvEgFo0Xp58FI=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH83xyq+INgRhb3hfb6LCvZB2cQsD+KXONxc37tW6rLbf6+wIQxM1SMzV168WKGrKOw5FAOnatS/ZfTMCsNeoJsycSA2eO30HlAJ4ZMj41z6toIffpU332sZtGbNfBix2OJM0D0Jy61DXxx1CPTmXNDuoC+5me6Rt93zBw/n5N96YqFyth4xRQfg6cefyouccw2", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Limited demand for goods and services", 
		"option_b": "Equilibrium between wants and resources", 
		"option_c": "Abundance of resources", 
		"option_d": "Unlimited human wants with limited resources", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010110", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr+9pElXxv80b39MHjEQ3EErnKCQKpudWKjQK/HLv/7xZZlLlOHnlNy4jbEprHn8lYBz61Y5oCQfSsAbctuxtTJw+zyhHRCPMhLl5ktps4Hfkh1gSwbg2z3XKN/Jsw=", 
		"answer": "25C7Z5/83BDp5MUpQV7mzfi/IWPVDHAI7z+CXKc0ZHnmFKLBYePxxI4xLk/JmVN+smbUoqbk/lAOg+ha+Z6TeSECaoJgxpCG0aTjzHBVc9JMn49g/diO4+VilVv7IjKl+Z/wdawb", 
		"explanation": "25C7Z5/83BDp5MUhQV7mzfi/MWLDAGsBr3aNV+NnZGTnTa7Maa37yph/KFGAjht5937Htaz/5R9PmKBS5YvfZCoGPo5sx96G2v23zWIBJ85B2pJ35ZZfbP1D2Ci/cZTPKP96jmuNIlf3Yir9BXZgkSOWi2xGpJqy+yD7Udk4zho/n4Q4+cA5M8WW3LvRrThJAkGIhS/lfEd6AEnNeQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Economics is the theory, and the economy is the practical application of that theory", 
		"option_b": "Economics and the economy are two unrelated fields of study", 
		"option_c": "Economics studies theoretical concepts, while the economy deals with philosophical issues", 
		"option_d": "Economics focuses on political aspects, while the economy studies social interactions", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010111", 
		"question": "2523f9H+0ACq+IslEhv+0P72MWrEBiIFq3rDVqpnc3TxWq7Maa34zJZlMk6Mnhtv+nfS46H1+lIdjKlP7M6acy0NcYZmzcPJw+z20DFJMtBB2oFx7JMaavFEjDyjNNXfNv9gzWuEZ1bkZi24RH9y1DXTnHlap5O28CmvFNwlzxhygo93/s18KN+ezeiS+kj4lRKL0HfRQbMkBVyc9d665ECZs5F4usvNlCTU+OHtk/fdsN8FZkhVrYlod1P8gKEd8CM2Edy8bVJZ9OXcbBTiJmimJAET9sbq1TR635E9WGQnq118KqTECBcgTFcGhw5bWXsA", 
		"answer": "24O5epjy0xDm/pE5Ehf8hfj8OmXfDmsS42uMXa9nMHDtUOfQa/7rxYNiZeFCtqgmgMtWttTdL+Smt40=", 
		"explanation": "25ysKILm1h7v5JEzEgr6xOm/MH3VDSIYpT+XRaw0dXLsWqjPZ+jtiZFwJFnJnlJ2+3rHseXz/1IDg61V7ouMMCMNest8zdyM1PC30HlEc9VFl4Uy4ZkQcvtNxT7tYNvULO0ijnqIIkziJyu4F2V4gCKWh31P6JW65z77UM8ygAE91o52+c0uMtaTmamd7A29nhKHznWQRP1iEFeNuty7qQWdUdObSDGgVl3Xd1WPTRI=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Similarity in economic challenges", 
		"option_b": "Homogeneous human behavior", 
		"option_c": "Socio-political conditions", 
		"option_d": "Variability in economic tools and results", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010112", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MUUWhfhhb32OHvcGiIQoXCWRuNgeHSjWqbWe//7iZh3Z1mKglV0/3/F47X/+1oMhq1ItsxMDlOwhOWhiG2IomG7Tvk5", 
		"answer": "24GwbdH63Anr9JFgXRiywP7wO2TdCmFRs3CPW6B9dWKjQqbQZ+jtiZNkIhydght/+2DDsbb1t1UOjLxU+53fcSwHPohgxsSMz/DkhvW0XjGCxd+oNvqNX6GwoeE=", 
		"explanation": "25C7Z5/83BDpt5UvXhfxzPjsdWbRGiIZommGEqd9ZnTxR6KCYfjqyph8Ik/JiU5+smLJ46z+41YdgalXqY+RdGIGZp9q2t6I26TxxXJVPNRX2ol84pYKefpDxTOqNNzOLf9gjmyFL0TmbjavRHF6kHHTiXNYp46y9me4W9QzyQE7mYlrr5gqN6Z5DB8cOPsdHZJ7oSw=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Economic policies have a consistent impact on all economies", 
		"option_b": "Economic policies are predictable and deterministic", 
		"option_c": "The impact of economic policies varies due to diverse factors and contexts", 
		"option_d": "Economic policies are always successful in solving challenges", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010113", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RD544wuVQv71vX6JivVAG0frHKKUbA0dmPsWefNeuX729d1Lk+KhEt3+3jDsOX8/lgKz7hU5YeLeSECcst8y9mM2efyiDFSPMVNlYx944NTPPVOyH29YdbXKf0uz2qNLkv5dC2vBWR9mz+JyC24GtSX5L/YnsZCRAL2siY=", 
		"answer": "24asfZXqkRbst4EpRBvg1vi/PX7dAmxRonyXW7V9ZHjmR+V9wWWhDdbjXZONT5vAxrLc", 
		"explanation": "25ysKJLyxRzt+JcpSBvhhev+J2LfFnFRp3aQUapkfHjtUbSCb/6+wYJ8JlKAmVJ+4TbEpqbx4kAKz7xT7JffYzYWepIvzNmP0eHlwX9Vc85Rl4F8pJscaP1WxSmkcceXYPdgzWKVI0z+YHm4B396mzzfiTxXq5ey4y6vXd8kgAYmg4Nx6Mx8Ps7f3Kuc5kK1jwWRnr+GoEE5o8I1R2DO7BWLqpo=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Different theoretical foundations", 
		"option_b": "Study of diverse human activities", 
		"option_c": "Emphasis on governmental policies", 
		"option_d": "Focus on individual behavior only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010114", 
		"question": "25C7Z5/83BD545ZgXxH2zPvmdX/YBmsD43aHV6JnMHDtUOfWZujx2550NByGm15psmLPrqCw41xPjqxJ7J2MMDULf58wit2aNQhb5y0rcsuILT8Jh+0=", 
		"answer": "24G3KJP2xQ3v5cUhVhrgwO7sdW7TDGwernaAEqB8cX3vUanFa/68sF8p/M/qkcgTuVeRbFmV7Q==", 
		"explanation": "25C7Z5/83BD545ZgXxH2zPvmdWreByIDpnKMVqpyaTH3XKLLfK33zZJwNByLjEh+9jbJreXz+F0biqVL5pyeYjtDbI583dydxKT2ynUBNt5Un5J74ZQceecA2DLtdtHPNPt8jm+EI1f1dCr9AWZ7mCffhHsWrYC0+yi2Xdl3wx0zmot94885L5VnjwBjFlkEDdEBR4dxHItc", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "To cater to political ideologies", 
		"option_b": "To better address economic challenges", 
		"option_c": "To align with changing cultural norms", 
		"option_d": "To conform to international standards", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010115", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg7gzPD+J3KQAHAYt3qRW6x6MHfsRufBb/n7zphjLkaAg1w783XSqrP541oKnOha+s6acy0NcYZmy5CI1PD+0nhVOsNXxcKhj7uU2I1GLrJA0RNTwzD9", 
		"answer": "25y2fp7/xxzn8os0EhH0he3tOm3ZFyD5y5vQYqmVyYDxM8y1++75", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20hbk+IgpUV7zxun2I2LECmcC436QErd8f2LmFK7MeOLy355/IByZn1R9+2KK46n/5EBDz6RS/4uTeSoMcY8jiN+K1PHnxWVIPMgI2pdz459TPPFN3DGibdneLuoijmuUJAd9mLVO3r8dcEE5EcNQ4Gqu", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Involvement of profit", 
		"option_b": "Government regulation", 
		"option_c": "Technological complexity", 
		"option_d": "Societal importance", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010116", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg37wvP2M2LTAmwSpj+MVONgeHSjQKLQY63Ci5JyKFKGgEJHsDbRq6D+t0Yciqwb4IDfeTEMcop7wd+HiKZruWg/BG/jLBXlu2h4mzPb", 
		"answer": "25ysKJnywlnk+MUtVx/8zPP4dXzZF2oetmvDUax6ZHT7QOUK9s45FCzlayTHr0GKS73s", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Avnt7liVx39y/LyLFeSQ2UQqnGQEq5xcX/qWqCCYePy0NdmL1mHzVJvsn/V46Tj5FwMhqlP7IrfZysXdst7wNXJ2eX6wTFONYZF2oN98ZQLbu0MjC+oc93ULrIuwXzAJUn/ZDL/ho1gzsJ/tYblMWXPhbQtGg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "It represents the global financial system", 
		"option_b": "It describes the overall state of an individual's finances", 
		"option_c": "It has no meaning without context", 
		"option_d": "It refers to the stock market", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010117", 
		"question": "24asfZXqkRbst4AjXRD9yPT8JivTDGwCqnuGQKZwMHX6WqbPZ+6+yJl1Z1+GgEt3926Gp7D1t0cAzdrtGm7IhD0844a2SW776KI=", 
		"answer": "25y2KIP2wgnl+ZYlEgr9hfjpOmfGCmwW43eWX6J6MHPmXKbUZ+LsiZZ/IxyMjlR1/XvPoOXz+F0LhrxS5oCMMr2hDQFECHBAGoUgrXT/uEM=", 
		"explanation": "27C7Z5/83BDp5MUpQV723PP+OGLTQ2YEpj+XXeNgeHSjV6jMeuTw3JhkNFCQzVhz83jBqqv3t1sagqlVqYyaeCMVd4R9iNGH06Tky3JIPItBmY9865cWf7RGzT65e8bIYvfXFZrCaOydf9NT6WUm2hc=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Due to constant government intervention", 
		"option_b": "Because of changing political ideologies", 
		"option_c": "In response to evolving human behavior and economic conditions", 
		"option_d": "As a result of technological advancements", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010118", 
		"question": "25C7Z5/83BDp5MUjUwr3wvLtPHHVByIQsD+CEqdtfnDuXaSCffj8w5JyMxyNmF475nmGtK359FtPgK4b/YaaMCQMcodg39mH0KTlwXBSPMgb2FVcPNvjY/JbI3Q2fpJamYQ=", 
		"answer": "25ysKJjgkQr+4oEpVxqyzPO/NCvDE2MSpjKXW65xMHLsWrPLYPjrxNdwKVjJhFVt/XrQpraw+1oZhqZcqYaKfSMNPolqwd6OxKZ7tKxbV3USQnHLKOxJA/Li", 
		"explanation": "27C7Z5/83BDp5MUpQV723PP+OGLTQ2AUoH6WQaY0eWWjXbSCffnrzZ50IxyAgxtv+nOGoKr+41YXm+hU786LeCdDbZtuy9XEw+36wTFCPMhQk45n8ZdfffpEjDSjYtvXNvt9jnqIIgXjcyy5HTB7knHag2pfpoT7/TK2VdR3whA7mIBrr7rXJFHyE1nPTFI2AEvP910=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "It involves complex mathematical models", 
		"option_b": "It deals with historical analysis of economies", 
		"option_c": "It is studied in a space-time continuum and involves living human beings", 
		"option_d": "It exclusively focuses on monetary aspects", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010119", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3v5YhgUBvh0b37MHjTEWsTpmzDRqtxMGHxW6THff6+xpExN06Agkly5n/cqqv3t1AKnbxa4IDfficGepgvx8aMxaT40HlEIdUEjYh36toKaP1MxSeketObLPdjx3qFIwXiYiqyEWJ3kSKJyMNx+ZnuYnE3WOImm13+YQ0=", 
		"answer": "24e9e57mwxrvt4QsXhHxxOn2OmWSHv+hG1SI9uClh7xp5iqdrw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH63x3j4YwkRx/+1rG/JmTTCmcFujPDU61wMGXrUefFYfv725l8IlKdzVZ6+XOGs7f5+EEGm6FB7IrfcyoMd4hq25CA2aTjzHQBI9RLmYVh99oQerRV3zSjc5TII/98zWvANUDjaCyvB3Vn1CXZyntEqZey8z77QtslyRonhcd26M04L5ee16zT/0y2khXAT6kcAtYH43aCGNlPxVy1tg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Resource allocation", 
		"option_b": "Demand-supply equilibrium", 
		"option_c": "Profit optimization", 
		"option_d": "Consumer surplus", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010120", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3v5YhgUBvh0b37MHjTEWsTpmzDRqtxMGHxW6THff6+xpExN06Agkly5n/cqqv3t1AKnbxa4IDfficGepgvx8aMxaT40HlEIdUEjYh36toKaP1MxSeketObLPdjx3qFIwXiYiqyEWJ3kSKJyMNx+ZnuYnE3WOImm13+YQ0=", 
		"answer": "25C7Z5/83BDp5MUmXR3n1vjsdWTeQ2sfp3aVW6dhcX2jVqLKb/v3xoU9Z0uBhFd+smXJoKz/+1wIluhI/ZubeScQPphgy9mMw+X7hHhPJ8NWm4Nm7ZURb7YOY92I6svQ6AYTSWSilOKw", 
		"explanation": "25C7Z5/83BDp5MUwQBf/xO/2OXKQBnoQrnaNV7A0eX/nXbHLavj/xddzIlSIm1J04DbRqrH4/l1Pm6BeqY2QfjYGZp8vx9bJ0uf4yn5MOsUEm4Nm7YwWaP1F33HtfdrYLOtqx2CHZ0H1ZDCuDX962TzXgXVYr8Op8Cu6QN8zgAE91pdq4swpP8OW1qbfqE63iBWX0WuFQbJqXRSYu8ro+UaPr5cqtsjNsD7X+/f4jvHc/p4kbEhGt4M/bE+0krpJ8Cs2VYT0ex1I+OvcblP0YDivJg0Y6ovqwmcpw485VWgn/QwGjY0Wcc9w353wvT5wNsN+ECG7oFBJyJpvE1eFYK+t03zx8lAsOToqa44tuDQ7oAKVK0c8UIHhpldkAv6Axe47gOqgRw==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Economics focuses on individual behavior, while sociology studies societal interactions", 
		"option_b": "Economics solely deals with monetary matters, while political science studies government structures", 
		"option_c": "Economics studies government policies, while sociology focuses on economic behavior", 
		"option_d": "Economics emphasizes psychological motivations, while political science studies human behavior", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010121", 
		"question": "25C7Z5/83BDp5MUhWxPhhenwdWLdE3AetXrDRqtxME7ca5j9UdLBiZh3Z1ScgFp1snrPpaCw9UpPnLxO7ZeWfiVDe4hgxt+E3ue3xnRJMtBNlZJhpJsReLRQ3jK9e8fSLvku2W+ZNAXkaHmwBWh9mTjMjzxTq4y1+iqyV5onzwE3mJNx7MR+Gvt405Fg53LQtdHS52tswA==", 
		"answer": "26StaZ36xQCogX15L1VdFuMj+aa8am+qpA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwYYKzkRzn540hQRfowO6/IWPRFyIFq3rDR69geXziQKKCaeL/xdd+IRyMjlR1/XvPoLaw/kBPm6cb7ICXcSwAe8t7wNXJxvH2yHhVKoZLnMB68ZcecrRMxTuoNNbCYO1622qZLkv3Jzy+C357mTjVyn5ToIKt/CipR5o2zhFykI526cEyO5eI2LGAqFm3xgmSyHKcQadhUUCRsI69/0qQqZg5ocSCv3LU8rTrn+vc5cwIZxsQ18x+Ixz9KqxIUcNTuVkYJw==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "qu,al,ity", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010122", 
		"question": "25S2KJTw3hfl+pxgXwvh0b3vJ2LfEWsFqmWGEqJ6dDHiWKvNbezqzNdjIk+GmEl492WGt6qw5FIbhrtd8M6cfy8Te59mxtfJ6NvI+05+DPkEm452pI0ecuBTjvkvGe8KdzTivl+nOad0Ue0=", 
		"answer": "27u9bZXgk23KblZNInKV0fE+aw0AQQs=", 
		"explanation": "25y2KJD9kRzp+IsvXwe+he/6JmTFEWEUsD+CQKY0fHjuXbPHaqG+yJl1Z1WHiVJt+3LToqnjuxMcgKtS7JqGPGICcI8vz9+f0vb5yXRPJ9UElIV34NoLc7RNzTaoNNfTL/dty33AM0qwdyu0C2J9gDjMjzxQvY+9/Cu3XdQwgBAhhYJ2+cE9MJeR3K2X+w23kAOQnG2QWrRrBEfZos+m/1DcpJc99dmC8SbT8bTqmfnB89cfe0hducZtZkizgroK/Tl6lWmKzJmrCVcYY+8lkUh2yQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "ne,eds", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010123", 
		"question": "24GwbdH32Arp/pUsWxD3hfL5dW7TDGwernaAQeN8cWKjUbHNYvv7zddlL06GmFxzsnvJp6z2/lAOm6FU553feSxDaoNqx8KA0ve3xnBSNsIElY4y55URaPFN3DK/dcbCYMFR8VG/GHrPJzizADBxjCHTmHVTpoC+5me0Upoywxo8mYpx6Nt+VxwTdBf8CeotwMM8Ik8LQw==", 
		"answer": "26e9e4T/xQqolasm+Q+OzBc2zNWC3eXueQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH32Arp/pUsWxD3hfL5dW7TDGwernaAQeN8cWKjUbHNYvv7zdd+MVmbzU9y/3OGobyw9lcOn7xS54nfeTYQPp9nzd+b3uHkhHBPN4ZNnoVz99odfedFyH2iepTPKPsu3GuBKwjnaCuxADBmkSLDhmhF6IK18We0Qc40zxg3hcd379s5LsGa3eia5g2uhxSL026CCLhnHlqWuMet+AOJroY9p42JuDTd8eb8lOyT89EFZgFGtolxcBkYUTXdZ3bNj8ds3pwMk3RE", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "re,su,lts", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010124", 
		"question": "25C7Z5/83BDpt5EoVxHgzPjsdWrCBiIepWuGXON9fnfvQaLMbej6iZVoZ13Jm1pp+3PSuuX/8RMJjqtP5pyMPGIKcIhj3dSA2eO3+05+DPl7pb8y9p8Mc+FSzzi+OJTTKe16wXyJJET8JzqyCmRxjCWayn1YrMOz4Cq6Wpo1xR0zgI53/4pyn2w45+qew0XQJJSnULnL", 
		"answer": "27mxZZjn1B2oR66oDaG6qdbZWKPIbYpUPA==", 
		"explanation": "25C7Z5/83BDpt5EoVxHgzPjsdX/RCGdRqnGXXeN3f3/wXaPHfOzqwJh/Z0iBiBto8XfUoKzk7hMAiehJ7J2QZTAAe5gjiMeB3uf/hHhSc8cEmYV88IgecLRDwzOuccTPYPdgjmuDKEv/ajC+FzBAnDSWi2pXoY+69y63Xc4ugBo01otx4MEoOdPfy62A51iqhQORnHieRql2GFaMocu7q1eT4JYwsI2DtDfftPL2iLje8dUCbA8SvI5wali5hOgI9i54Rdq1bBcG/uLWchTkLmimJAET9sbq1TRtw4EgTmA7+lJLg4hfbMcxaltZEldWHoNhkov+7bIY5A==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "li,mi,ted", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010125", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3FKbMaq3tzJt0JEjJmVN+snXJsbf19EdPjqZI/ouNMGJDPssviJDJl6S3hDEBc4YE2sAypNpfPLQAjH3tNJSbYMJg732TIlfkbjazXjBRlz7YhXFfq5D75jOuUNMy01U6mZA4/sc/NdKL0K2AqFirg0aR33qDS7gkA1GKutu66EaP4JY39d2fvjbO9/G5jPnf5d8Jbg0SvIlyblS4nrwA/Tl4UMawKBZC4vDCaFb4NC3jMwYY9Ivi23tnwcItVG8y8Q1DjJcWcsV8xpTh/HJwf40qVXP64wQAh9Q8H1fWNP34kCikoBV/NTprJbZjgCMHpA6PJ1p3lGzGDB9SlZJo98QA1Q1wPW4AmmPuhj6GhWubfZ+j6I/yhu3gtPlq/OMiKk6OOlHRVZ5QJbLOIydh3vyfFK9SNN9vGDWmL9A98yzrI5OHnzgf1ZkhI3vo9yuNl8m1LWr6vpf8mpRjGrMJO9jR7M/3uEnKYC2hNnydcti0UBuwTjzz1hclsRcm3TJQ52SYHIF6tSkEjX25WUhtnCKifWvN4CcV+pFFwSpkyDXVcg==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxP78IHnRF2cduj+HV7B3YnjhUbSCYeP7iZh3Z0iBiBtw92+Gparz4kAKnOhU786acy0NcYZmy8PFl/P/zXJJc89X2pR64doMaOFE1X2icpTTL+ku3WGDLkDkbjyuRHF4mD7Vi2hT6JC49DW4UZolxQY9g5V76Nt8KNjf1K2W/A2tiAqL0XKFTbkkGUGUtMDo/EKStJF4icOxvwbT8bTrn/nA/9ACbA8SuZNtd1O5hegM4Do0UMG6e1Jf+eXEIUfuITqgLhoEucLwlnUpxYcnSXs1+F9FjY1VZ9BnlpHq/DczMMNlGDq5sARByZA8VgTWfbO81W3goEE3cDo5YIt+syN1tgeFaEB2nyuPWDlVjcBk+JALkBdsaH1DmTbhjjOEg2SbdZztq4nvxe3js7xt5qomJQGJOxzMXohcY7rFK2MwEE5NhiXsKryilDagff2RFA==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true and R is not the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010126", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3FKbMaq3tzJt0JEjJmVN+snXJsbf19EdPjqZI/ouNMGJDPssviJDJl6S3hDEBc4YE2sAypNpfPLQAjH3tNJSbYL5SwE+TNEDiczCyCio0sTLZhHNboYD7+jKvV9U6xQZylYZ2rd49Ls7f2KWc5kr4hQmX0m+DQbh3UVKWucKn/EqSp8IrvMCEvTPJtPH6lfbc/dcIIhhds498al6v16wc/WosXoigYBcL5OrAc1HpKSu3JgwU9cL3zzRmwMIhSGQ1+l9Eh4tXdMl8xNik/HJwf40qVXP643hOh9Q8H1fWNP34kCikoBV/NTprJcot/G114U/caBQ+2ivcDGwR1MArvpBZ1URfc11FnWXvjDaFhz/PWZDs5Y/xjOuwtLFm/bEuLFLANE7dFo8ddrbEZ2h8iuyDHaNfJ55zHi3oLpUh+nnxNZuV0XkP1dEhOX7o5mbZhcX8Om36sJP3ztZzVLYOMN3Q7MW0tViHYzqhN3yBb8ThSkj5QWj9wQBku1gkxiVQ7XrMDZtx9CFNmH+zXUt2gWugYHmgkrdS7cKacM412uPpzyEV2Ptti5j42RgvBYXWTQFMFq4HUNaASzzhttk=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyxvLtJ27TF24I42yXU7dxYzH3XKbWLv73xJ59Jk7JiFh0/HnLqqaw51wDhqtS7J3ffSMaPodqydTJw+u3wHhHNcNWn45mpJUKaPdPwTi+NNDOJb56wS6UL0CwcjetFnVwnTLCi35arcO19DOuRt93zxNynpJ17MZ8PtKX2L6a51+EiDqMnE+ZTf12FFWKusCh5UTcsJA3o8SJtCGb8uHrjvDW4p4YdxhCsJRrI1ml160R6CY5WMa9ZhUL5ezRdRToIyetKAMU+ov33nFm1IssTik15hoGgIJFZ8Qz2ZaktCc9PsMqFzayolJJyIYwHwCefb6wkGH3oFwxc3Y+YIRuuSl1oxbcKRRom3mVSThI1I9tvtYYlhBsb3wM3HvhiTaFhyWGaNPn4ob6jOvlrK0j5qxnOVOFMVXbQs0Md7bDLnR3iuaOGaVTPpp0VehNsyXosN9WEaRcxa5Gh7s=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true and R is not the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010127", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3FKbMaq3tzJt0JEjJmVN+snXJsbf19EdPjqZI/ouNMGJDPssviJDJl6S3hDEBc4YE2sAypNpfPLQAjH3tNJSbYL4uji7AG0vRdCq4FmR9mz+MykhercOu+TOyWdsjxVU1mYZ0rcc6fNKc1qac5US7lUaLzzuFR/1pEEyQuMey7gOMso0+vNme8TTU5rT7j+va/tsYcQ1B/4dxZxu5mbsc6i94VMu7Zh1G+OeQZkbiNzyrZ05duYujljQphsIVUyl0tF8GwsMWIoAzltik/HJwf40qVXP64wQAh9Q8H1fWNP34kCikoBV/NTprJcot/G114U/caBQ+2ivcDGwR1LxlzNUYhgttdGFHxjbFgTCFj2iGf4Cj+5L1iOniqbV6sqUoKlSTME+YWYNcbL7QNWhkw+ecTbJUNt9rHjTvM9Ju/zb3JJ+A1jYDw5kvKTfv4SeYnMThICW7p9L1j8ZxEf8BONWF78K5tFXJZmP2IGSAJt/7GQ3+R3320AsluA4g2iAc5CLPDYVzuC8Il3C3C9rESaUBC/zTg3sJL5oi+iw=", 
		"answer": "25T4YYKz1xjm5IBgUAvmhc+/PHiQF3AEpj1H3esm/O0e/DyDhrhK09GF", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzPP8OnnCBmEFr2bDQbd1ZHTwFLPKa63rxYN4Kl2diBt8/XfK46r2t1YMgKZU5IecY2I/cLdh/9iA2+G3wXJOPclJk4My44gQa+BIjDyjcJTLMvFox3qTZ0TiYnm0CWB7hiXXhGgWq4y15i6/Ucg21Bw9mJQ0rdw0OZePy6Ge6V+hxgGN3XfRR7skFFeWu8Gl4kCP7MI5po2AtDzP/fv3n/yT+dBLdgBX/5R6YkizmaEH/2Z4WNv0fB0L9OrYYFruJWi3Lwtd9t3mxHVlysI+WGU4uR1Di41RIsF90tjotSQ5McoqFjy0p01UzptyTFeZcv2wxWXl7lwrbDo/bZhiqSo94QqaLl19k26SWGxDkZNk68IakERicWNPn3f0izCFwGSBeNPi74TugPvjqbdksqYkJk+POFXbFo4UZL/MIml1z/rZJuEJn7QiJh+ZJDTMF3AaJg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true and R is not the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010128", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0Avvt5EoV17mze/6MCvADHECqn2PV+Nmf33mR+fNaK3qwZIxNEiImV409XnQprf++lYBm+hS586efmIGfYRhx92Qm6T21zFMNshQk4984Z5fdfoA+DWkZ5SEYsP/5bg1kwkRsRyc8pgzWQ0=", 
		"answer": "24e9b4T/0A3l5clgYQvi1fH2MHmQDGRRk22KRKJgdTHEW6jGfaG++oJhN1CAiEk7/XCGk7Dy+1oMz49U5oqMMqJL2IaHftG0dF6DxtCqhlI=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn2Qvv8sUwXQ3hzP/zMCvCDG4UsD+MVONgeHSjR7PDeuixzphnIk6HgF515jbPreXx+RMKjKdV5oOGMCMRe9EvgNnAl9byw2RNMtJLiMB94toLdPEAyT6ietvWKf0u3XeTM0D9K3n1DXk91AHEhXhDq4aptSa1UJU40lUhg5do4cE5LpeQ3+jU+F+xkAeW2TuWR7JgAhSYu8ro+EaOtos7sN7B9nLa+vC50vHa+ZdLUhpdu5N8Zkn8lqYNtyUqEduheAJH+OHCIVvrYG+zMgwR8Mij0XtmwpFuHWYmtFhVjYBfY8wz0ZfruCF3fdy0NG3K13E4cJocFufR9xA=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Regulator, Supplier of Private Goods, Supplier of Public Goods", 
		"option_b": "Producer of Private Goods, Producer of Public Goods, Regulator", 
		"option_c": "Regulator, Distributor of Private Goods, Distributor of Public Goods", 
		"option_d": "Supplier of Private Goods, Regulator, Producer of Public Goods", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010129", 
		"question": "25y2KIX71Fnp+Is0VwbmhfL5dX/YBiImomyLW61zZH7tFITNYP77x4RkNBDJmlN65jbRoraw41sKz7hJ4IOeYjtDd4V7zd6d3uv5hHNEO89KnsBm7J9fb/FUjDKrNMTULPdt1y6SIkP/dTSuRGBmmyHZmXlS6IGitQ20XNR39xw+mo554NszMojdS/QkebmjVL3ZgreIi9x+GA==", 
		"answer": "24G3KJD31Qvv5JZgRhb3hfj8OmXfDmsS42+RXaF4dXzwFKHDbej6iZVoZ3CImVJ1slfLprf59FIBz6tU/ICLYisGbcnVsJkAoAH2Rr5HUItAugps", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxDn9pc5Ehf80fjxIWLfDSITpneKXKc0ZHnmFJDDfeX3x5BlKFLJrlR14XPIsLDjt0QOnOhP5s6edCYRe5h8iMSB0qTlwXBNc8NHlY596ZMcPORSwz+hcdnIYPhvzWuEZ0fpJxW8EHl61BDbj25fq4K1tSS0QdQj0hw3hcd5+YgoNNLfzaGe7QH4lAeW1H6DCKlsEFrZvMO45FCVroV4u8iC/D7S9vHrm/ST4NEHawtbupU/bFX8k60f/SY3QcG6b1JI/vHedUbkJTvhOKbXFbz2rxUp8bbUcy1IZQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "To promote market fundamentalism globally", 
		"option_b": "To impose neo-liberal policies on developing countries", 
		"option_c": "To address the economic problems faced by Latin American countries", 
		"option_d": "To advocate for a development state in the Western economies", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010130", 
		"question": "24KwcdHa3x3j9otgVx39y/LyLCvZECICt3aPXuN3f3/wXaPHfOj6iZZ/Z32On1pp+3fI46Dz+F0AgrEEq3AHhOWE1y1FTf6A0TecqNw=", 
		"answer": "252xb5mz0hbk45cpUAvmzPLxdWTWQ3YZpj+TQKp5cWP6FLTHbfnx29dlKByuqWs5OgNkeH+3kWWZ+Gy0gTubow==", 
		"explanation": "25S2KJTw3hfl+pxgWw2yxvzrMGzfEWsLpnvDU7A0cX+jVaDQb//3yJkxIl+Gg1R26zbPpeXk/1ZPn7pS5I+NaWIQe4h7x8LOxKT0y39VIc9Gj5R765RfaPsA2DWoNMDUNP9ijmGVM1Xlc3n1I1RE3XHfmTwD+Mb7+jX7WdUlxVfUdYIxzxVLqswqABMMkTUC", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "High contribution of the tertiary sector to GDP", 
		"option_b": "High contribution of the primary sector to GDP", 
		"option_c": "High contribution of the secondary sector to GDP", 
		"option_d": "High level of industrialization", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010131", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrv9JEvQF79w73rPW6QBmEerXCOS+N9fnLvQaPHfa3/yoN4MVWdhF5osmTDr6Tk8ldPm6cb7IqKcyMXd4RhhJCL1ur8zX9Gf4ZQiIF894oQbuBB2DSiepibIfBqjnqPMlf5dDTiRor1ghuIedZYerOxpJZBZVU=", 
		"answer": "24G9eoX60Avzt7YlUQr9178Ia0HhusKMdP35p7ndRNry", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg1Br++JdgRhbz0b32O2jcFmYUsD+CUbd9Znj3XaLRLuH3wpIxIlicjlpv+3nI7+Xy9l0EhqZcpc6LYiMNbZtg2sSIw+34yj0BMshA2pR98YgWb/kAxS7tYNzeYOpr3HqJJlfpJyq4B2R7hn2Wi3BFp8Ow+yisWpo201UmnoI4/s0uKt6c3LvT+0i7kgmQnswymclobsmhC+b3tD6HCQw=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Primary Sector", 
		"option_b": "Secondary Sector", 
		"option_c": "Tertiary Sector", 
		"option_d": "Industrial Sector", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010132", 
		"question": "24GwbdHn2Qvv8sUlXhv/wPPrJivEC2MF41SGS61xYzHhUavLa/v7zddlL1nJnVR3+2LPoKT8t0MdgKpX7IPffyRDc4phw9mH06T+1zFVPIZHlY1w7ZQaI7aqaZpcj9AHNSEt/8FxF6jO", 
		"answer": "25C7Z5/83BDpt4AmVBfxzPjxNnKcQ2sfp3aVW6dhcX2jWK7Aa//q0NsxNFOKhFp3snzTsLH59FZN39WaZ1PP8S4ubmBdI6mIoQ==", 
		"explanation": "25S7a57h1RDk8MU0XV7ZwOTxMHicQ3YZpj+TXa99ZHjgVauCfv/xy5t0KhyGixt283jNqqv0t1ocz7xUqY2QfSAKcI4vzdOG2ev6zXIBNsBCk4N74ZQcZbgAxTOpfcLSJOtvwi6MLkf1dS2kSDB1mjWWmXNVoYK3tS2uR84+wxBwVdR9EvtkUAFbpSBTL/b15A==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Economic efficiency, social justice, environmental sustainability", 
		"option_b": "Economic growth, individual liberty, technological advancement", 
		"option_c": "Economic efficiency, individual liberty, social justice", 
		"option_d": "Individual liberty, social justice, cultural diversity", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010133", 
		"question": "25y2KJCzwhz44YwjV173xvLxOmbJTyIGq3aAWuNndXL3W7WCbeLw3YV4JUmdiEg75n7D46358FsKnLwb/4+TZSdDaoQv3NiMl/D40HBNc9ZWlYRn559APrtMxMAHuEcG5CkR8waktZw=", 
		"answer": "24G9eoX60Avzt7YlUQr9178Ia0HhusKMdP35p7ndRNry", 
		"explanation": "25y2KJCzwhz44YwjV173xvLxOmbJTyIFq3rDWqpzeHTwQOfBYePq255zMkiAglU75nmGt631t0cAm6lXqZ6NfyYWfY4vy9+E0ve3wmNOPoZQkoUy8J8NaP1B3iTtZ9HYNPF8jiaTIlfmbjq4FzBnkTLChW4f6hlH5aUJS1FAm/NEJ4vDqOk=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Primary Sector", 
		"option_b": "Secondary Sector", 
		"option_c": "Tertiary Sector", 
		"option_d": "Industrial Sector", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010134", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEgr31/C/IHjVByIFrD+HV7B3YnjhUefDYK37yph/KFGQzUxz92TD47H48hMciqtU54qeYjtDbY5s3N+bl+f4ymVTOsRRjoVhpM9PObRP3n2ge8beYOphjnqIIgXkaC28CDBkhj7Sn39T6JW6+TK+C5j4lWmrq04Dtkrw1B/5TUJi", 
		"answer": "25y2bITgxQvj9olgdx39y/LyLClGop652UcOkqliQ4a8yVYA", 
		"explanation": "25S2KJTw3hfl+pxgRRb31/i/IWPVQ3EUoHCNVqJmaTHwUaTWYf++yph/M06Aj05v92WG9vW1t1wdz6VU+4vfZC1DaoNqiMSGw+X7hGFTPMJRmYUy8psTafEAxS7tf9rUN/Auz33AJkuwbje5EWNghjjXhjxTq4y1+iqiFgHXpDWEePrM669FssBV8jo=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Agrarian Economy", 
		"option_b": "Industrial Economy", 
		"option_c": "Service Economy", 
		"option_d": "Manufacturing Economy", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010135", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0Avvt5EoV17mze/6MCvDF2MWpmzDXaU0d2PsQ7PKLuL4iZZ/Z1mKglV0/2+GrqD+41oAga1fqYeRMBYLd5gvl5LVuDAD8kNe6qPCP5+Hzwa9", 
		"answer": "25S/epDh2Bjku8UJXBrn1untPGrcTyIipm2VW6BxMrWlAlCZ9RhH/BIHqw/FpKI=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn2Qvv8sUzRh/1wO6/Om2QBHAetGuLEqxyMHDtFKLBYePxxI4xJk/JrFxp82TPoqu8t3oBi71I/ZyWcS5PPophzJC60vbhzXJEcXOLviI1TvWTRLCdGBkks5s=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Pre-industrial, Industrial, Post-industrial", 
		"option_b": "Agrarian, Industrial, Service", 
		"option_c": "Agricultural, Manufacturing, Tertiary", 
		"option_d": "Early, Middle, Late Development", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010136", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3v5YhgWw2y0O76MSvEDCIVpmyAQKp2dTHiWufHdvnszJp0Z12HiRt//XHLorH59BMMgKVW4JqSdSwXPp9giMSB0qT1wX1INsAEjohz8NoSfeZLySm+NNfaLr5mz2CEK0CwYi+4FmlgnDjYjSMUQq47kncnLoraYsettnGn5g==", 
		"answer": "25u9Z5360xz49okpQROwr9oJfiSAs2g4WtRxVGJ8Rw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHn1Avnt5AzVxqy0fK/MW7DAHAYoXrDU600dWn3RqLPa639xpp8LkiEiFVvsmLJ47H48hMNiqRS7IjfZCoCastiycKC0vDkhHJAPYZMm4526J9feeJF3iS5fN3VJ75n3S68ZWv1aDW0BnVmlT3fmXEUTaqpDCkmNQPkr+IZS2czAA==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Keynesianism", 
		"option_b": "Liberalization", 
		"option_c": "Washington Consensus", 
		"option_d": "Neoliberalism", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010137", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg7gzPD+J3KQBWMSt3CRErd8cWWjWKLGLvnxiYN5IhyahVJ95jbAsar9t1IBz6lc+4+NeSMNPo5sx96G2v230H4BMoZXn5Jk7ZkaPPFDwzOiec2bKfAu+WuTM0DiaXm4B396mzzfj28J6uFcY3HKnlx9Ug3sEOh7Tzc=", 
		"answer": "252xb5mz0hbk45cpUAvmzPLxdWTWQ3YZpj+XV7FgeXDxTefRa+7qxoUxM1PJqn9LsHTgrFqQtsPmyQu5UmVAd2Q=", 
		"explanation": "24GwYYKzkQr/8IIlQQrhhen3NH+QF2oU42yLW6VgMHfxW6qCb+O+yJBjJk6AjFU793XJrar97hMbgOhaqZ2aYjQKfY4vzdOG2ev63TFIPYZzn5Nm4YgRPPFDwzOied3eM755z33AN1f5ajivDXxt1DXEg2pTpsO57GevXN93yBw1nsd74sYoLt6dzLya50P4iQDCyHOUCKlhA0CQtNyxq1CZo5Y3p43FojfJ4v36n+uT49sIdgdA9sZrbBubs5hJ+SQ8Ec25eB5E6OnVb0Cvybg0dv0Dh4R5czpM0PCAlA==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "A decline in industrial activities", 
		"option_b": "High contribution of the tertiary sector to GDP", 
		"option_c": "Dependency on primary sector resources", 
		"option_d": "Dependency on secondary sector manufacturing", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010138", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0Avvt5EoV17mze/6MCvYCnEFrG2KUaJ4fGijUb/Lffn3x5AxKlONiFdosnnA46H55EcdhqpO/YeQfmINe594x8KCxKT6wX9VOslKn4Qy7ZRfSPxJ333yNh5ObToop74kj2V8B0hvNeM=", 
		"answer": "24asaYX2nVnH9pcrVwq+hc7rNH/VTm8QsXSGRuN5eWmh3DY14yG0HTrUdKPLU4NhLw==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX2nVnH9pcrVwq+hc7rNH/VTm8QsXSGRuN5eWmjYK/Lfa2+xoJlK1WHiEg75n7UpqCw/1ocm6dJ4I2efGIHd5h72tmLwvD+y38BPcNQjY9g79oSc/BFwC73NMfPIeprgi6XL0DiYnmpDHU0kz7Aj25YpYa14WeoQconzBw3hcd/4sc4L5ee16zT+0iqkA+B2WjKCLBlA1+coYLo/EuZsod4pd+EsjfItPD8jv3B/dcFZ0hWtpVrcVK+grwA9yRjEcm6bFJY5eXEZBngITqoIhpd9ML7mjRohoEmUGs9+h5Si4xYIs91lovwvSY1f8xkEXO3olZLwoA8Wx6FYK+x0n3w6VoxN2dgoghLL7eT2MzxZKPh7xw=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Capitalism, Socialism, Communism", 
		"option_b": "State, Market, State-market mix", 
		"option_c": "Free market, Planned economy, Mixed economy", 
		"option_d": "Private sector, Public sector, Cooperative sector", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010139", 
		"question": "25S7a57h1RDk8MU0XV7TwfzydVjdCnYZ7z+LXbQ0Z372WKOCb63zyIV6IkjJiFh0/HnLuuXx9FsGir5eqYuOZSsPd4l9wcWEiKbrcdvfJRPwm2tffEN0QYLB", 
		"answer": "24Gwep7m1hGq440lEhf80/TsPGncBiIZonGHEqxyMHziRqzHeq34xoVyIk/LPFj7uPWhUNtUn9P97cTqrA==", 
		"explanation": "24Gwep7m1hGq440lEhf80/TsPGncBiIZonGHEqxyMHziRqzHeq34xoVyIk/JrF96/zb1rqzk/xQcz7xT7IGNaWIGc5tnycOAzeHzhGVJMtIEl4Fg758LPPJP3j6oZ5TaLvou2maFZ0z+cTCuDXJ4kXHei3JS6JS04Cu/FNQ21AAgl4t09IgwOdabmbycqEipkw+O1XmDQahpUV2X9c/o5kKOq4cs9ciOvjzU+e27KF82oL9X3KhrqW0DQjWvKw==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Through government regulations", 
		"option_b": "Through centralized planning", 
		"option_c": "Through the invisible hand of market forces", 
		"option_d": "Through collective ownership of resources", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010140", 
		"question": "25a3ZZP63xDk8MUtUwz5wOm/OG7TC2MfqmyOQeNjeWXrXamCb63txpR4JlCAnk8793XJrar9/lBPibpa5IuIfzAIPpxu25CIl+f4ynJEI9IEk45m9pUbafdFyH2vbYuZ7Y6wCfqWPt1Ht0zX/l+55g==", 
		"answer": "25qra5DhkTXr+YIlEK3EaloNjs0uF+j7kS1oNdM=", 
		"explanation": "25qra5DhkTXr+YIlEjHhxvztdUfRDWUU43aNRrF7dGTgUaOCeuX7iZR+KV+MnU87/XCGn+f99kEEirwb+oGceSMPd5hihOzLl/P/zXJJc9ZWlZB9958bPPdPwT+ket3VJ75jz3yLIlGwajy+DHF6nSLbmTxBoZez/Cn7VZokzxY7l4tx/tx8OdSQ16ee4U74gBSD0X6GR69vU13LWg/yrhsQX270m3upL0c=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "John Maynard Keynes", 
		"option_b": "Karl Marx", 
		"option_c": "Adam Smith", 
		"option_d": "Oscar Lange", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010141", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEhPzzPO/MWLWBWcDpnGAV+N2dWX0UaLMLv7xyp5wK1WagBt6/HKGoKr9+kYBhrtWqdHdIHFHsu7ZJ9agBhXyu/fmyQ==", 
		"answer": "24asaYX2kRb9+YAyQRb71b3pJivTDG4dpnyXW7VxMH70WqLQfeX32dVEc+bY/n3la/VRo4t3j3XQ", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX2kRb9+YAyQRb71b3pJivTDG4dpnyXW7VxMH70WqLQfeX32ddCKF+AjFdy4XuGqqvm+F8Zirsb+pqeZCdDcZxhzcKa3+3nhH5Hc8tBm45hpJUZPORSwzm4d8DSL/AijnmILkn1JzqyCX1hmjjFhzxXrJW09iavUcl3xhog1oR34cQ5P8OWz63T51q2gxSR1HKBCLJiUVWVuY64+UyMpZAsvMie88PK8cGmtsdZ5xFfjptWKXU=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "State ownership vs collective ownership", 
		"option_b": "Private ownership vs public ownership", 
		"option_c": "Laissez-faire vs government control", 
		"option_d": "Market economy vs planned economy", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010142", 
		"question": "24GwbdHUwxzr48UEVw7gwO7sPGTeQ24Upz+XXeNgeHSjRbLHffn3xpl4KVvJgl075n7D47Xi/l0MhrhX7J3ffyRDaYNmy9jJ0uf4yn5MOsUEiZlh8J8SI7aDOCEOhipjGOTuvBiWg39J", 
		"answer": "25a5eJjn0BXj5Ihi/upSf4PeC9i1ia+40400VQ==", 
		"explanation": "25a5eJjn0BXj5IhgZhb3hdrtMGrEQ0YUs22GQbB9f3+jRLXNY/3qzJMxNkmMnk9y/XjPraKw+FVPjKlL4JqefCsQast/2tmH1O3nyHRSc8dX2o1z9pEaaLRNyT6lddrSM/N9jmiBLkn1Y3mpCzBkhjTAj3JC6Jez8Ge4RtMkyQZw2HLa8uGaRk5olv3+n+OXtg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Capitalism", 
		"option_b": "Socialism", 
		"option_c": "Communism", 
		"option_d": "Mixed economy", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010143", 
		"question": "25S7a57h1RDk8MU0XV7ZwOTxMHicQ3UZuj+KQeNzf2fmRqnPa+PqiZ5/M1mbm1515n/JreX+8lAKnLta+5ffeSxDf4UvzdOG2ev63S4Dxu4FcUUAWYJBPqFsXMKDdw==", 
		"answer": "24G3KJD31Qvv5JZgRxD3yO3zOnLdBmwF436NVuN2f37wQOfGa+D/x5MzDtoNI78UQCBbHwMddIMiRQ==", 
		"explanation": "24G3KJD31Qvv5JZgRxD3yO3zOnLdBmwF436NVuN2f37wQOfGa+D/x5MxDFmQg15osnfUpLD18xMJgLob7oGJdTANc45h3JCA2fDy1mdEPdJNlY4y8JVff/tNzjy5NMHVJfN+wmGZKkD+c3m8CnQ0hyXfh2laqZe+tSO+Wds5xFU2g5Vx4898OdSQ16ee4U74ggmV0m+EWrN3UzgiWY/w+1o4wT7q2JHaD+I=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "To promote inequality", 
		"option_b": "To enforce strict laissez-faire policies", 
		"option_c": "To achieve equilibrium through market forces", 
		"option_d": "To address unemployment and boost demand", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010144", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoV17Fyu/zMSv0BnQUr3CTX6Z6ZDHRUbfNfPm+xpExdgXQ1Bt4/XjFr7D08hMOjadO/c6LeCdDc4J3zdTJ0uf4yn5MKpkGZ8eTa5BIKO3EW9Mtxrok7g==", 
		"answer": "25ysKJT+wRHr5Iw6VxqyxL38OmbAD2ccpnGXU7FtMGPmWKbWZ+Lw2p94NxyLiE9s93PI46jx5VgKm+ha54rfYzYCao4tfghMf6kKIJRrMOjMjxOLUw==", 
		"explanation": "25ysKJT+wRHr5Iw6VxqyxL38OmbAD2ccpnGXU7FtMGPmWKbWZ+Lw2p94NxyLiE9s93PI46jx5VgKm+ha54rfYzYCao4v/NiMl9P41n1Fc+JBjIV+64oSefpUjA+oZNvJNL5hyC7RfhypJzG0A3h4nTbennlS6IL79ya3VdQ0xRFyl5do/8c9P9/Tmb+b7V+9xgSNyHPRRbx2GlGN9c+m7wOPtIMssI2Evybe5uL8lOza/9BLcgRTpsZ8bFasm60E/SQsUNqtKABE/eHDIV3jYCnjKgcF/M+j03dmyI0kRCs1Um5PXJ6FhQejnpEWoalc", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "It rejected both market and state economies", 
		"option_b": "It favored complete state control over the economy", 
		"option_c": "It endorsed a pure free-market economy", 
		"option_d": "It emphasized a complementary relationship between market and state", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010145", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrl4os0QAeyxPnwJX/VByIQrT+/EKxkdX+jUKjNfK3uxpt4JEW1zxt6/HKGqqv541oOm61fqY/ffS0Ve8t7x8eIxeDkhHxAIc1BjsBh65kWffhJ3zDyNp2K4G6PWJM4ubsdY6KPLRw=", 
		"answer": "25awYZ/yk9BH1YaxDsp+xF4cFnm7jI0=", 
		"explanation": "25awYZ/ykRDk/pEpUwr3wb3+OyvsQW0BpnHDVqx7YjHzW6vLbfTCi9d4KRzY1AMuvjbLrLP5+VRPm6dM6JybY2IOf5lkzcTJxOv0zXBNOtVJ1sBl7JMcdLRDwzCvfdreJL5jz3yLIlGwdyu0CnN9hD3TmTxBoZeztTSvVc4ygBw8gIh0+80xOdmLm1nLbUJfib/NYAUqu6j+88Q=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Soviet Union", 
		"option_b": "United States", 
		"option_c": "China", 
		"option_d": "India", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010146", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoV173yPjtMm7eAGdRrHnDRqtxMEbsRqvGLtnsyJN0Z3Obilp1+2zHt6z/+RNHuJx0oM6dYisNect7x5Cd3+G3035TP8IEn4N96pUSZasCtJlWt086DQigEPDvsQZ0gQ==", 
		"answer": "25y2a5363xj+/oouEgr90vztMXiQBXAUpj+OU7F/dWWjUaTNYOLzwJJiZ0uAmVM74XnLpuXj41IbiuhS55qaYjQGcJ9mx97LhSU4dBrNu8bHd1BMuheN+w==", 
		"explanation": "25y2a5363xj+/oouEgr90vztMXiQBXAUpj+OU7F/dWWjUaTNYOLzwJJiZ0uAmVM74XnLpuXj41IbiuhS55qaYjQGcJ9mx97J4+z+1zEBOshAk4Nz8J8MPOBIzSntYNzeYPtjy3yHIkvzYnmyAjBgnDSWvXNEpIf7wTW6UN937wc1l4lx98koNdiRmeCk3GLxxgqH2DuFR/1lUUSLsMit+UaSo4d4s8Kf8TTJ8fG5l/nB+9sfIg1RsIhwblK5hOge8T4wEcS9ZRtf9OCQckDsNC3jLgAJ/Nn103p9z40nH8mgmEJ4Ms3dlllHrdH9Jk0=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Greater emphasis on state-controlled economies", 
		"option_b": "Rejection of market economies", 
		"option_c": "A shift towards a purely planned economy", 
		"option_d": "Inclination towards free market economies with some state intervention", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010147", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2hzzt5cvXhuywfT7dX/YBiICt36XV+NkfHD6FK7MLvn2zNd8LkSMiRt+8XnIrKjpt14Ai61XtsyL7G4yGNl5gg39lO7/KXdj", 
		"answer": "25KtaYPy3w3v8owuVV7/zPP2OH7dQ24UtXqPQeN7djHtQbPQZ/n3xpkxM1PJjFd3snXPt6zq8l0czTdmHMm4uYoHFdxawaafUu8=", 
		"explanation": "25KtaYPy3w3v8owuVV7/zPP2OH7dQ24UtXqPQeN7djHtQbPQZ/n3xpkxM1PJjFd3snXPt6zq8l0cz4FVqZqXdWIOd5NqzJCM1Ov5y3xYc8tLnoV+qNoLdPEA3ymsYNGbMPJv12uEZ0SwdTaxATB9mnHGmHNAoYey+yD7UckkxRsmn4Z0rdgpPtuW2uiU50K8lUaRyXiZCLx3UVGdoM2p/0qTrs54vciMvSbT9/Xrn7ST8dAPIhtdvI9+bxuvkqsc6iMsSIigZ1JO//fFc1GtNCCmZxkY9ceu1HFgyIVpUm904BdDwpNZctV/14ztszxyHDaS2FJA7hV66nEqw1+3aw==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Complete control over all economic activities", 
		"option_b": "Guaranteeing minimum levels of nutrition to all citizens", 
		"option_c": "Eliminating private ownership of resources", 
		"option_d": "Promoting pauperization of the masses", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010148", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUlURH8yvD2Jn+QFGsFqz+XWqZ9YjH0W7XJNK/atmSN3B4+f0AqBMRmUVse", 
		"answer": "25S8aZyz4hTj441gH17Gzfi/Am7RD3YZ43CFEo11ZHjsWrSOLsb/25sxCl2blRs2slLHsOXb9kMGm6lXpc61fyoNPqZu0d6IxeC373RYPcNX2s0y0JIaPNNFwji/ddibFPZrwXyZZ0r2JxywFHx7jTzThGgWgY2v8DW+R853wRs21qp3480lfo5NE2a8Lp0i3vRCngCFzk4=", 
		"explanation": "25S8aZyz4hTj441gWw2yxO7sOmjZAnYUpz+UW7d8MGXrUefVYf/1iaszE1SMzWx+83rSq+X/8RMhjrxS5oCMTGBDSoNm25CAxKT0y39SOsJBiIV2pJIWb7RNzTqjYdmbL+573SLAME31dTz9DHU0mDDfjjxSp5S1tTOzUZoxzwA8koZs5McyL5eQ3+iQ5EyrlQ+B3XfRTb5rH1uUvM27q0KSpMI8vN6OpCHI8fC5mffd89sbdhsSs490Zhuon61J8SQuWNu9ah5OsezRb1ChYCyqMQcO8MTtlntvho4oX2YmuF9HjIcWZNJ209jpvSA7OtkqBSGzrUdJ15h5TFeqeoG2+2n27BUSdGgzJZ1/szkw4TPeDFVt2kCdXCVFlYxXvJxZlERweGJJknfswiiEkm7PdZ2j/Ij1huCwqLwj9qYxLE2PJVncFoUVdvPUL2J92OCeHuZTNd9vHjHyMscn/zj1YJuVyzwf2dgsJmTqtCuXlo32K2yuuoPsi9A2ALcFdtLE+cKjsVDOcjehMmSAcs75GTz4Sjzv3Bxu9xwgxDcV+yLRBp1wtSQejWu1WgRrlGfsbX6uhPIc/IOCaot9k/Ti2XIEkPE4kZrjwQ85Bwu9zXxCoo2LTlBG3lmWIsM7yiMhBLpBOZfI/GyEkTb7TmUDet22AL2TyyNa3+exsiNJt5VOcomAKQvahp4SwBK+E+Q5WmGtjYvpMfMMB2Ei7v4x4+O1sti+ZufobGQka1qaVuFc6qkTKDZzGBidBytAa/inRd0fAeNAwHvPhRRcSHFMRVXKu4MNRAqvuc3JYCrbYL4SARPrYKBJU8f2WlXAMeSqwT7ORquUkAe9UEomSyqJYb8LpQb3fZ73IxKnlihg/MzkPFUbRY0TfCb3YmS6pLeKBQF6eSM3aI1IbELHRR0hmiqDLvdziLUWdRY5SKepWVQDhBhBmH7XDVdLv0EXXOWpT0QpPrxXLkhR2Tj1EKQbThnZlXofgFOR0i7jMPdOP11jemqXz1/0mpBvk/bzh86VAtGiKL4U3IIOMfSZPpffanmNHYshxlJEKGVh", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "John Maynard Keynes,The General Theory of Employment Interest and Money", 
		"option_b": "Karl Marx,Das Kapital", 
		"option_c": "Adam Smith,The Wealth of Nations", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010149", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sU0Vwz/her2IWOQCnYC43uGQaBmeWH3XajMNK94eE5yKwTaFqyJGkq1Js+Z", 
		"answer": "24a7aYPw2A3zt8hgZxD+zPD2IW7UQ2oErn6NErR1fmXwFLHRLuH3xJ5lIljJn15o/WPUoKDjuxMqjKdV5oOGMG9DX5t/xNmK1vD+y38BPMAEn4N96pUSdfcA2DWoe8bSJe0ux2DAJgXiYj60C3441BLXmnVCqY/78yipWdsjyRo81so43dozP9KMyuic7g26kw+O2HKfT/10A1udoM284kyS4IE5pcyOuCbCtODxiPfG99ZLawZEupVrbl6yg+RJ0ysqXYiZaQBTsamQRVX+YAOiNwcJ+MehcBpa7BS53SFoIPdaputs9w==", 
		"explanation": "24a7aYPw2A3zt4wzEgr6wL38OmXTBnIF42iLV7FxMHn2WabMLvr/x4NiZ12HiRt193PCsOXx5VZPmqZX4IOWZCcHMstt3cTJw+zyhGNEIMlRiIN399oeavVJwDyveNGbNPEuyHuMIUz8a3mpDHVnkXHBi3JCu8O65yL7WNM6yQE3ksdM5cEvfNSN3KmH7V74kg6HnH2ERrllHFGXoc+kq0afr4w3uMSO8SLJ+/b1n/WT/9hLbwlZtoh4I1i0mKEK/Tl4Vd2xKAZEsfDYZBT+IymxJAcJ4Ivs0DR7w5EmSHs38QwGvo1qbOF9lp3nszw/MtQqBza8plZTh4BzHwOecf2ryXvw5Vh/enxrdZhiuDg2tQaTJhg+nmKPWD5YlpV/998X2URic2sAn3nukSqGkHGGc52j5Ia8guf/pKoj860jaVKFJ0rRVYgPJaTJM297xKmaTbRZNJZoGWLpL5UvvDr2NZiAzSBN+c1gKnnk+yeJk97mPHb6p5r8ztV1ALYWP8XM7Nj3olnLYDfkJT2HaYv5WAbxSHX21E53sgsq3TMT7XGYHIY/+CgIij6kQUEknCLlaG/hl7BYqpWPcZoik/rqnSIVl+R0mtvL2iEyZAWrhGtCvsSZQE5CzEDfEcNHzRpuGLwEVIbD/W6ThmWQRHpNfdv/DayOzSsIz/Oxmml4/4AcWoibLw3ShdBmyxahAP5wQX6tp4C5PPJVD2cj9L180621v9i0YPSsbGwkeR+kTeJc/YERYQw7AQPEFi1MYbTuV5MaAeha33TE1wRJV3ZdBFaM0rxIVAq8pcjea3mecLAKBxDlI7ILF47xQFHKJuWgxjeJD7HcmEa9V00rSyiEbfAE6wHie5/mNgawh312/I2lN1VOR4IDNSj9OCu4q6fDBBIyej5lLotEbkjHWFAwnD/XZ/pog7MSeRo4Va3nDV9WkxJAkTHfB1sFt14RSLGlAFIpLulBJU0UwTilHKURSF7UoGxcgWP33QF5yjzP/Dvn", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Scarcity,Unlimited human wants vs limited resources", 
		"option_b": "Economy,Application of economic theories in a region", 
		"option_c": "Capital formation,Process of building production capacity through investment", 
		"option_d": "Karl Marx,Das Kapital", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "010150", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUFURH8yvD2NivjGnEFpnKQErR9ZHmjQK/HZ/++6p9wNV2KmV5p+2XSqqbjrRF0Ye60k/azFKGNxWYPYDi3", 
		"answer": "25a5eJjn0BXj5JEpUV7XxvLxOmbJQy9Rk22KRKJgdTHmWrPHfP3swIR0NByEjFB+snLDoKzj/lwBnOgdqYKWfSsXe48vz9+f0vb5yXRPJ4ZWlYx3qNosaPVUyX2Id9vVL/N3jiPAFFHxczz9C2d6h3Hbj31Yu8O082erRtUz1RYmn4h2rckyOJec1qaH+kK0lUaH33SfR7B9XRS0vNat7wO5o402usCU8X+b1vj8lPyT/9hLbwlAtINrI1i9h6Ed+SYxQsX0aRxPsffEYEDoYCGtMwsP787twn1myMB+gfLjaudQC0V8ed4hR4nJ", 
		"explanation": "25a5eJjn0BXj5JEpUV7XxvLxOmbJQ2sC43yLU7F1c2XmRq7Ya+m+y44xN06Am1pv9zbJtKv15UAHhrgb5ojfYicQcZ59y9Wal+X5wDFVO8MEl4Vz6olfc/IA3C+icMHYNPdhwC6pKQXkbzCuRGNthyXThzAWuJGy4yavUZoyzgE3hJdq5Ns5L5ee16zT4UO8jxCL2G6QRK4kHFWSsI6l5FCI4Ic7usOCvDvYtPD8mfHA+dEFcUQSvoh7I0+0kugO9zw9Q8a5bRxftveQc1vhJWiqNE4R8MbqwnFthpYmHWw68hBUgYpYZYB/14/38HIiOsp/GTKuqktO1Ng8XhmSNLi2w3326Vs4NXwqbJgtvyI4sQqIIUB3lWXcZSIRlcBY6tENkERGfmBOk3v5zn+fiGDPe5z17pLyiO3+tPls5a00aUCOMRzbWYMId7zMNCdmwuzbAKNdPYwnGCSmLcch+Cz6NJ+b0XkM3t1gJ3b0tCvZkcj7LXe7v9LrgdhzVLYOdtTG5sW4vVXEITPtIHOdb8XzGQn+Szz81g1spBEqxmwd6WnRBo4/wSUI3nm/X0F2nCrlYmjhmbhI74zObYs2xvntyTcD2PV2m9vz3Q85RBCozXpAvYqQQlVMjVXVCsQRzR0nCadBFZXS/X+SnHjXC2gCP8fiEuiIwSZN2ff4mGRu/70HTYmKbDzYhdApxQ7xCO45VCfvpIP3ObwaDCQh+6B6z/nhtMurfOelIGw5Ylq2V+sZ4IFQfAc7GAXJADZZZba6X5IQAclbknbFmgVBSXpaRV/A/qUNUxC56svOLmjRd7lcHgzrdbIRFo73WUnKJ+KhwSCJB7GY1UCxSUE3QDeYL6RN5gj+bp79KFOHm20k/s7zN0NVSYYZKGf+dXL5rK2XDhQseiIgaJ5IOkbRTwIhhy2DKvh1hqIUMB4sSKSyC1UF2lFfjTHEB1xA8FwLXamkQxMgJaZBMxdRzDmxUaURTwnYg3oZgVWVwy6sPv9HN0gxfijTmETpl5cmj+3glI+VD5TnI6kewJ0RIaVeV9rFC1IQlrPr/+TyEHg8Rnp+OvDBUKLFuEq2B8v7rMzX3B4HD34WtCVqrvhD+gByNBIp", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Discipline to Type of Economies", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Capitalistic Economy,Private enterprises make decisions & limited government role", 
		"option_b": "State Economy,State owns means of production and controls economy", 
		"option_c": "Mixed Economy,Blend of market capitalism and state intervention", 
		"option_d": "Mixed Economy,Blend of market capitalism and state intervention", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020101", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg7gzPD+J3KQEWcQsHCNEqV7YjHgW6nRZ+n7255/IBzOhFV4/XvD5OXx5BMOz65U6o+TMDIMd4V7iN+Pl+Dy0nRNPNZJn45mpJsReLRXyTGhOdbeKfBpjmeOZ0vxczCyCmMr1ko7Hu25lxXCw0yHO3ZbIBw=", 
		"answer": "25ysKIHh3g/j84AzEh+yxvLyJXnVC2cfsHaVV+N5dXDwQbXHLuL4iYB0K1DEj15y/HGEJeuYKU7CXvOglNJOxrccNQ==", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kRDk9IotV1771r3xOn+QF2oU42yMXqY0eX/nXaTDeuLsiZh3Z0uMgVc28HPPraK8t1obz6Ba+s6ddScNPpxmzNWFzqTi13RFc8RBmYFn959fdeAA3C+iYt3fJe0uzy6DKEjgdTy1AX5nnSfTynFTqZCu5yL7W9x3wVU8l5Nx4sZ7L5ea2qed50CxhUaRyGmURrpwGRSYu8ro6EqIqZg9u97K8SXe+Pi0mP3a/tlJ177gUy2EEZeZxR6rZeyZWw==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "It is easy to calculate and compare", 
		"option_b": "It provides a comprehensive measure of well-being", 
		"option_c": "It is the only measure that matters", 
		"option_d": "It directly influences government policies", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020102", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17wwPHwIivDF2MFpnKGXLdnMHDtUOfSZ+71iYN5IhyKgklp93XS46r+8kAzgYlI+ouNZCsMcNEv4d7J2eXjzX5PMsoEk45x65caPPVDzzK4esDSLvkijmeOI0ziYjqpRGR1jDTFyn1ErcO/8COuV84yxFU0hIh1rdw0OZeR2Lya50O5ikaL0nieRbgkEEDZs8+r/0yO4IE3ptnNsyfPtPr2jrjS5J4GYxpZupI/YFSvg5QHxCQKVMmnZxxC/+OKIX3jJCGxIg0Jud/iznF6hoM7WCk3+xNKh4BCZ8Qz14ykqjMiNsJ/BnOqrE1O04c8VhnWYLW9kHj271Eqdm4iaoQtvSMx4QuVO0Bsk2mJWCVemsB77N8akBdwMS9MmXfkizGMwHGAPJfs/oLwgKjzr6xt5qopLgGJMxzWWZlcZLfKMnRmz+3bHbRTI5p1GzukPCTB+aUk+E32TZvZIzn9Yw==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6eX/kFKbQa63q24J0axyIg1875n7D47f19kAAgaFV7s6WY2IXdo4vy9+bxeH00DFEK9ZIm45z8JMQcrRPyn25fNGbIe19y3yULkr+JYNDSmA1hIpPagJTUP2Ha1E=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiITpnyCR7BxMHjtUK7Qa+7qiYNwP1mazVpp9zbCpqHl9EcKi+hd+4GSMDYLe8thycSA2Or2yDFIPcVLl4Uy5Y5fevVD2DK/NNfUM+ou2mHAJlP/bj39AH9hlj3Tyn9ZvY2v/Cm8FO4/xVUgk4Zr4sY1MtDf0LvT/EW9xgWNzmmUS6kkFEyJuc+m6leVr4x4t8iOsCfI8bTwlPza4tsIdkhGvp56cBu9ha1J+SYqVMmwcVJC/+fcdFDoJGiqKU4J8c6jwHVl04dpUm908xBJhpAWY853lovhriQ5PMh5VSOorEBVxJF4E1eXern4xGDh+RU+Z39rZoVhsCg2tQqYaFJslWbcRSJVnZZi+sUYmRcjfGFE3HXvjy+KjmyKb9Pi+MDoje3p4Kl24KAvKFKFdUjQU54ZJbTPKGNhiuiVCeZPNo1xHiHjLpUa9CzqbNaHyjsZwtgjO37p82qQnMn8K2C5p9Ltj8xzB/8GJN7IqcW2pFXIbyLtYXSdZcT5XEjxWzz+0g1xuAplyy4D/CLKDYRw4yge3mq4TARgnTLiYHnhlbFJ5JaHcYlzGc5DXtakY2SC6xDZMIu/Rg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reasoning are true, and the reasoning is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reasoning are true, but the reasoning is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reasoning is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020103", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRqmzDfIxAMHjtV6vXauj6iZ5/Z0iBiBt483rFtqnx41oAgehU7864VBJcPPtBTdI1/wVWm2nBg69FN7E=", 
		"answer": "25y1eJ7hxQqo3M+PR86OqeAkxqgeyddi4w==", 
		"explanation": "25y1eJ7hxQqq9pclEhD90b32O2jcFmYUpz+KXONgeHSjV6bObfjyyIN4KFLJgl071VL244LUxxMCiqlI/JyaY2IXdo4v3tGFwuG3y3cBNMlLnpMy5ZQbPOdF3iukd9HIYO58wWqVJED0Jy60EHh9mnHXyn9ZvY2v5z78R5o1zwc2k5VroYgyM8PfzaCWqFu5ihOHnHSXCLprHlCK9c+m7wOPpZAuvM6IonLP/PXt2vnB9Z4CbxhdrZJ6Zxu1mbwGuD4wVIi3ZwdF5fbJXVrRLh+rIgBd+Ivg2WFn0pAwHWA55BBUlpAWZc980oukvTw0f95vByWzoEFTi9R1S1efZ/29w3vh7kE2dHYnfMpvqTQ8rwjcPFxxiW7cSyNekJMr/94d1Rdmb3lJn3PzwjmZj2jPfZ3s/4j5l6jzr6xt5rE+aXWIMBzOV4EJYPPPISdmwuaICOZbPJBjBGLnM9Fu7zzrNp+X2ipN2cpgLHjy+j6clo38NyWuu5e5qfBGVLAGdsXN7IuyqEzIczfoL3rTZcThVxziVjC43QFx9wwtzWEZ5XLXGp12+ypNnXGlR1B2i2X+PEgPwF2x/OucRCKvyLkA", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Government spending", 
		"option_b": "Net private remittances", 
		"option_c": "Exports", 
		"option_d": "Imports", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020104", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq2YA0Ejr9yPjsIWLTQ1IDrHuWUbc0OF/HZO6dLK+9f0wGy5aL1uRkj4EFo50=", 
		"answer": "25KcWNH+2Bf/5MUkVw7gwP72NH/ZDGxT+5Dhu6N1VEeHbQE5dji4/g==", 
		"explanation": "25ucWNH6wlnp9okjRxLz0fj7dWnJQ3EEoWuRU6BgeX/kFLPKa63oyJtkIhyGixt/92bUpqb59kcGgKYb75yQfWIkWrsv4cTJxeHn1nRSNshQicBm7J9fcvFUjCuseMHeYPFojmmPKEHjJzizADBnkSPAg39Tu8Or5yi/QdkyxFUzkJN9/4g9P9SQzKaH4UO/xgCNzjuGTbx2UVWXsY687kKO4l2ITD3S3g9BBRRqhL3Y2Sk=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "The total value of goods and services produced within a country", 
		"option_b": "GDP minus depreciation", 
		"option_c": "GDP plus government spending", 
		"option_d": "Gross National Product minus taxes", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020105", 
		"question": "24GwbdHw3hfp8pU0EhH0hcLAClTvPF0unEDDW61if331UbSCbeLzy55/LlKOzV54/XjJrqzzt1YJiaFY4IuRcztPPphgy9mI26T90WJVOsVB1sBz6p5fdfpExSukcMHaLL5ix2yFNVHpJzCzRHF61DTVhXJZpZr5162yPAlVdbJTNzWIcKosGg==", 
		"answer": "2569cZ/2wlsBv+GCcSZNfaxbi12poz3L", 
		"explanation": "2569cZ/2wlno8okpVwj3wb3rPW6QE20dqmuKUaJ4MGHxW6XOa+C+xpExKl2HhlJ19jbPsOXk+BMMgKVZ4ICaMDYLbI5qiMSB3urw1ysBNsVLlI9/7ZlfefJGxT6kcdrYObIu3WGDLkT8JzOoF2R9lzSayn1YrMOy+yOyQtMz1RQ+1otx780uKM7f7aCa+w27iQiB2WuFCLR3UVWNodyh6VaIpYZ4ocLNmjfC+vHq2vnd9J4ZZw5euoVrcBuon61J8S49UIigYBNfsfDYZEfoYDyrNQsYuc7v03lsyJY6HWcx8RsGlowWYMUz1JnovTwzOskqHD36ogRXwphwEhGDer6s2Wfq6Vs4NX8oaoRisTR3pKhahDA+O3agfY1eVHS9HA==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Ke,yn,es", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020106", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq/osjXgv2wPm/PGWQF2oU42yGVa5xfmWjE47MbeLzzNd3NVOEzXp54HnHp+Kw4FsKgehY6IKcZS4CaoJhz5Cu+dSohptQCysdjO3X+eGvWDVFGRM=", 
		"answer": "24WqYYfyxRyq5YAtWwrmxPP8MHiS67hWIEguRaPCMCaZRVBHlA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHg1B7n8os0EiKw7PP8OmbVQ2QDrHLDc6Fmf3DnaOWCeeX7x9dyJlCKmFd65n/IpOXX2WNPhqZY5ZubdTFDaoNqiNaG2+j403hPNJx4lKl855USebRFzS+jcdCbIucuymGNIlbkbjr9FnVnnTXThGhF6IWp+ir7XdQhxQYmm4J2+dt8PdWN1qmXsg2Mjg+RnHKfS7FxFVGK9cqh/UqYpYw8poHNuDzP8eb8ieyfsN8FZkhAsJ9+b0+1krtJ/SsqX82wKBBSseDfbFH+NCGgZxwY6sLn03p91cIvT2Y5tBZIlIZFds122Iz3/Ds+f8tlBzazpEoAxJtpUQOEfbir7GbW5Vg2YW4qa4lor20zswCRaFl3nXmdQjgRg4959dULhl4jSWdJjzbpjDyHlWGKb9Pu5I75nKjjpbd3sqsoJETAN0WYW4Qbd7LOMydlxfuQCLRPc4toVzbuONw8vD/4LZ+Y1jwekNAub2Pv8SOL0sX6NGD6sJ3sgMBkHboTCt/1+8SxuUjUISznYXucdM79Xga9QGv21goltBco2CAe4WfLUslL/SQe3ne+SkhxliLzLGyzmbhV/pHOco811rXuxHIWl+Z9lpz5mRIrSQG/zXxMv5SeQVVK3hTCFswThAY+CaYAAJOR+2PWgX7VC3gCcsvlFaGEgylL1e3+g3hBsbYBR4mHKxebi9cikleFCfRqFW7jq4rsOfkGSmM++7xl2a2guc77efylInZqaBOhXOEZ8YwRbg1pFALaC2RIb66rRJMTRO5bwTXLmQMISG1OBFTF4akcVAukuYTcYSrKa7RcChHvZqARGs24SUjZMOOnxTXHEv2e8AauSHYHVNlA8PZx+xVc", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Government grants", 
		"option_b": "Domestic consumption", 
		"option_c": "External loans", 
		"option_d": "Private remittances", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020107", 
		"question": "25ixcJT3kRzp+IsvXxf31r3rLHvZAGMdr2bDQKZgcXjtFKbWLuH7yIRlZ1OHiBt+8XnIrKj59BMdgKReqYiQYmIXdo4v28SIw+G7hGJUMM4Em5My948PbPhZxTOqNOvkH8FR8VG/GHqwYDayAGM0gD6WnnRZu4b7/Cn7Wt8yxFdt0tIuzPcnBsbSvatfSCW9", 
		"answer": "26Wtap360lvmv982GW6h6gwSK5OXW4hW", 
		"explanation": "25ixcJT3kRzp+IsvXxf31r3yNGLeF2MYrT+CErF7fHSjUqjQLvn2zNdiM12diBty/DbVtrXg+0oGga8b+ZudfCsAPoxgx9Sal/D4hGVJNoZUlZBn6JsLdftOjA24dtjSI75pwWGENAmwcDG0B3g0nT/VhmlSrcO+5jS+Ws4+wRlyhYJq+8E/OcTf1aGY7Q29ghOB3W+YR7MoUVyctMK840Cdsod09d6MvzvP9eDwlfafsN8FZkhfsJR6Lxu9ha1J9i87VNunaQBSseLfcxT+LyuqJgJd7s7v2jlrw4snWik1+hsGg5FTIs91wp3q/CIiMNtjETa+40ZZh4B0WleFYLys1Sjw7xU6e2k+d48tuTwgqBudKlh72mqfTylCh8Bt8cJZlAhvPWxJiH/6hzGYwrMTg7/Ln3MrnxXpnACQx3M=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "pu,bl,ic", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020108", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg7gzPD+J3KQB2sXpXqRV613dTHhUbPVa+jwidB3Jl+dgkk78XnVt+Kw9l0Lz+9W6JyUdTZDfYR83JfWlU+EAbY6uReBoqG8hcIXJsk=", 
		"answer": "25O5a4X8w1np+JY0Ehfhhen3MCvAEW0VtnyXW6x6MHLsR7OOLvr2wJt0Z1GIn1B+5jbFrLbkt1oBjKRO7YuMMDYCZo58ijcSVY6iKjWgA33ohGBHwZk=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxDn9pc5Ehr7w/v6J27eAGdRoXqXRaZxfjHlVaTWYf++yphiMxyIg187/3fUqKDkt1AAnLwb4J3fZCoCastpydOd2Pa3x35SJ4ZNlIN+8Z4ab7RPwjG0NMDTJb5twX2UNAX/YXmpDHU0kjDVnnNEu8O082erRtUz1RYmn4h2oYgrNN6T3Oie6V+zgxLC33SCXP1tH1eVoMqt+AOIqId4tsKepSGb+/K5jvDWsNgKYRxdrZU/bF38h7oG/D87RcG7ZlJb/fHDIUDsOC2wZw8T/Yvww3Z6z4YgWHoI+iNIpIJVds9hlpvrryZwNt4qATu/40dP1IA8UBHWZK+31H3n6Vs4NXtrYoViuG06s0+PLUZok2iZAGxUjINn69QQmwMjaW5YmWWggzGPwHaafoDq74n5lqjZtPlq4eMzIUTANFHXQ4MIJbzGZ2p9xOyCTbJUMosnFTf1NNsr7yr8M9ac3i8IkM0vb2fm7WqNnY3hMWD6tZP6mttkB/8PMJHV+8SzpV/TaCzvbT2Ac8j8GQnjD3D50QF3+1gmyTEZ/GPURMl++ylNkn++TXhqvybyZ3m11r1T+ZbOdp1xx/3pnTEfi+A4kJ23xA8zQxG4hHFE8oXfSFNAyRTZDI0UwRs4BbcEWNbY/G6agHLZRXtNa8/uBLvHwiJMmvDkjHJ0u5kLRsynOFnSmZ4ywBLxAPB2QGn56In/ffEaBGE1uqZ5y/nhtMW1ZuapKXc5LxK2T+oZ55oReANiUQ3SF2ROIL+hWZleTvIPwXDYgQ5LQjMJDFTP970MVAqt6tDJdm/NI7ASCl7xdrEWGsrxS1SNKi+F6AEpLEMlOfSL9XP4Qg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Factor cost includes taxes, while market cost excludes taxes", 
		"option_b": "Factor cost includes labor, while market cost includes raw materials", 
		"option_c": "Factor cost is the production cost, while market cost includes taxes", 
		"option_d": "Factor cost is the market price, while market cost is the production cost", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020109", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MVnURH81un+O3+QE3AYoHrEErFxdnTxFLPNLuTwiYN5IhyKglVv927S46r2t10Om6FU54+TMCsNfYRizZCK1uj00X1AJ89LlN8wVlR8lIisUOrycJh8AYiMoA==", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHjwxDp8sUvVF71yvL7JivRDWZRsHqRRKp3dWKjVbOCb63t3ZZ/I0+dhFd3sm/Dore35BMGga5X6JqWfyxDbIp7zZJLnTdI3inDxJnpxha3cxha", 
		"explanation": "25a3ZoLn0Bf+t5UyWx33he/6M27CECIFrD+XWqY0YGPqV6KCYeu+zph+I0/JjFV/smXDsbP59FYcz6ld/YuNMCMHdJ583NmH0KTxy2MBOshCloFm7ZURPPZB3zipNNvVYP8u3XqBKUHjczCxCDBtkTDEyjRUqZC+tT6+Vch+/BsOmK52rdw0OZec1qaH7VWsxgmEnHWQXLRrH1WV9cem6EyRpcI7tMGOpD7a4P32lLST89EFcRxTsZI/c0m1lK1J6i8+VNqnKAZEsfDYZBT9MiGgIh1d9s2j0XtmwpFpXGcwtAxDkJVfYcVglpHq/DNwPcx5EHOjpkVSh6B0VgTWfa74xXvh5BUrejooaod9vT8w4RuULRRom2eJSWxeksBl/8QQmgpicS9JknXvjzrLj3OKbtP34o35yajnqa1r/bYzaVWIMBzdUIsZZqfTZ2h0iuCVC6pdJ5ZoGR7oAdsI8yu5JY6V0ikB1ZVgJnGn4CKc0sP0LWy1vZP1zt14F7ANM5HM54vl4A6UISryYX6SasjhVQnkSni40holtBcr2zUR5naYGJt29ige3nG2CRY0wHWsLHW11rNZ64ydP5o50uGsyToV2ORqlpjyx10zQUS8gnBHocSeQVgP3lHECMQEwRpuGacEENbF/S2VlHrTXnAMa8u2FaCCgyJJzur+gGBx/5kAVoODKVnShJ50mEXiQfxrUCf5oIO5Lv0YDyQt6fJlwujhp9iydva3bGosLx24VutKs5RfbEJoFBnLDCdKc/inWN1MEbIdkkHCnhQIRnNFCk3fu70bHRCl6sfHY3rfcbRcGhbnI6EAEsK4TU/OO/asiDnHRrGdgU6xUUUpDjOTIr8A4Efyf5jlIRa90zo0q5OlM19fBNFHbnS/NHm4sauGGUYudy0raIBSaVOVXxgh1DDMKvBpjKtAcxAsT6+iW1tNjC0iZpocDKpVkG6mCmo=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "The price of goods and services after including inflation", 
		"option_b": "The price of goods and services at the maximum retail price", 
		"option_c": "The price of goods and services at a standstill year's inflation rate", 
		"option_d": "The price of goods and services at the factory gate", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020110", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17wwPHwIivDF2MFpnKGXLdnMHDtUOfSZ+71iYN5IhyKgklp93XS46r+8kAzgYlI+ouNZCsMcNEv+8WLxO3zzXRSc8dWn8Bz4J4aeLRUw325fNGbLv96x2GOJkmwbje+C31x1DDCynFXuoi+4We4W8kjgBw81ohq6c0ufMOQmauS5E6tigeW2TuFQLgkH1WNvMGm6k/cqYw7usCI8TPPtPL4mezc4p4IbRtGg4hDbWm5lrsG9iM2VpL0WwdJ4u3UaFH+YCmxIk4N68T133BswsIrRCkg/BoGhYxAZ9J9253qqHIkMI14EDevoEEA05x5HxSZZ6n4326k51owcWlrZIRp/D4wsxmVK1Ft1iudQigRgIhu98JZnApgcXpTlXnuwjaFwGiObpjm/8D/ivvk4Lhg8awyJ1WTdVrXRM0IbbbJNSd7x/maDrIcPJEnBzDpOcAt6DD2LtaV0T1N1NAzO2Xu9j+Nm8L7e6NWEEkDytODFPAlI87+NUw=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6eX/kFKbQa63q24J0axyIg1875n7D47f19kAAgaFV7s6WY2IXdo4vy9+bxeH00DFEK9ZIm45z8JMQcrRPyn25fNGbIe19y3yULkr+JYNDSmA1hIpPagJTUP2Ha1E=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiITpnyCR7BxMGL2VrTLauT72tdwNVnJhFV/93PC46T081YLz7xUqZqXdWINf59mx96I26T+ynJOPsMEm5Qy6ZsNd/FUjD6iZ8CbN/ZrwC6DJknzcjW8EHl6k3HCgnkWpoKv/Ci1VdZ3yRsxmYp9rckofNGe2ryc+g27iRWWnE+ZTf12FFWKusCh5UTcqZF4ocWI8THU5ub8meyT9cYbbglcvpJ2bFX8la0K+T8rVIinfRBY+ODZZEetITqmZx4P9t3q0nFthoAwHX088V9BjZVTcM5+05bw/CY/f8FlAjao41BIwtR/UASCNLK+kG/r71EsNXslYcp+uT8jqAyZOxg+m2WYDCVfl4x++tkXkkR3dWpN3H/uwjKKkm6KaNPg5JPoxen0qqxw5rBnL06SdUjQU4QOJbrOIWtnz+eYCOZTPd93BS3iKNY69Tb3YJea23kJ2co0PX7l4T6QncO39xC+8R4pzJSf2pQXNBnKvA==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reasoning are true, and the reasoning is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reasoning are true, but the reasoning is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reasoning is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020111", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrl+pUvXBv80b3wMyv3LVJRonyAXbZ6ZGKjUqjQLuP73dd4KUiMn15o5jbWorz98l0bnOhU586aaDYGbIVuxJCF2OX51y4Dr8oxM90hswHPi4ObPXit0A==", 
		"answer": "25y2fJTh1Ar+t4ouEhvq0fjtO2rcQ24eonGQEO88vkjegvbJI4NVManosf8=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3hT6+IslXAqyyvu/EkXgQ3YZomvDU6B3f2TtQLSCaOLsiZl0MxyAg09+4HPVt+Xg9koCiqZP+s6QfmIGZp9q2t6I26T7y3BPIIZNicBm7J9fUvFUjDusd8DUMr5nwG2PKkCwYSuyCTB1liPZi3gW4K2d3AbyaNQZ5jwT1o5rrdw0OZeb0K6V7V+9iAWHnHmUXKphFFrZocatq0qSo401sI2ZuTPPtPD2l/3A5NcIIhpXrI97ZlWohOgM+Tg2Ec6mZx8L+OrGZEf5LS2tMx1d+Mnx2XVthoMnWSkg/BoGi41Vbc12lozsvSZwOcJ4EDq9rQRSwod1WxKYYK741Wn27hU5Z3UmJYNjqigmtQKZJkBt2mKSDDhZkcBv8d0chhBqfi9Fn3nujTKSvGumaNPq+MD/hOTztbVi5qYjaUCTdVrXWoETcqCaG2lc7MC6TfscGpFkGC/jfdM88zS5IZSG0DgJkJRgBnnk+yec0tn6eWS4oZ34ipbrD6RCRS24MKcFyXM2PY4M", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Private remittances", 
		"option_b": "External grants", 
		"option_c": "Interest on external loans", 
		"option_d": "Net trade balance", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020112", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17wwPHwIivDF2MFpnKGXLdnMHDtUOfSZ+71iYN5IhyKgklp93XS46r+8kAzgYlI+ouNZCsMcNEv/NiMl8b213QBCsNFiMB064hff/VMzyihdcDSLvku52CELkS3dHmzBWR9mz/XhjxfpoC0+CL7Q9skgAc3gI5r6Mx8OsWQ1OjBuB3sy1bXnG+eCO80QAXU5Jzo4k3coYE7ut+JsDzY8bTuk+zbsNcFdg1AsYdralSylqRJ6z45X8y1ehZYzersb2boITusKQcT/pGj4nxshrEwTn0x+V9JhMN4Y9R62ZblsHIRPM5lAD2usAQI9LpdFlrEJO3gkHrh41oyeH8lYZktrigjqByVJlM+jmOZDC5Qh4Ur59UYh0Rsey9Fn3nujTKCgyWGcpfq6IXvxe3mpat6sqUuP0TALFnZRJ5cY7zSZ2ZxyfyJDKVFc55pE2L0ONkr6jj3I5PW6A5qA+F+GLP0ypx7SxypTw==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6eX/kFKbQa63q24J0axyIg1875n7D47f19kAAgaFV7s6WY2IXdo4vy9+bxeH00DFEK9ZIm45z8JMQcrRPyn25fNGbIe19y3yULkr+JYNDSmA1hIpPagJTUP2Ha1E=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiIQsD+XWqY0UnDwUef7a+zsiZF+NRygg19y8zHV46vx41oAgalXqYeRcy0Oe8tsydyKwuj20HhOPYZTm5My7ZQbefFEjC+oYt3IJfou2mHAdRWhNnTsVjBAnDSWmHlXu4y1/Cm8FNMkgAE6k8d74touOdSLma2L+EG5iAeW1XSfBP1lAhSNvcvo2FqPtIc19cKL8Rza4P32lPnfsP8IYQdHsZJsIxOPuYlAtXhoAZD0ewdM9uHDdUetMC2xLgEZ8MijxHF/z5EgUmcntBBAwoFXccUzz53lriFwK8IqED2ptlZFh4B0XgPWcb633mfp6VZ/fHQvbIlor20npAKdIVo+m2ifWT5QgIUr/94d1RZmcWpWnXj0wLRsuYOoDEmm3fDhfmYapnw=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reasoning are true, and the reasoning is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reasoning are true, but the reasoning is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reasoning is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020113", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MUHdi6y1/jvJ27DBmwF/D2jHMbiRJ9tiFWgA2rVCi9E", 
		"answer": "24O5ZIT2kRbst4MpXB/+hfrwOm/DQ2Mfpz+QV7FieXLmR+fSfOL63JR0IxyAgxt6sm/DoreyelFqUQsaSlE2qtMjBqaVpw==", 
		"explanation": "25KcWNHh1An48pYlXArhhen3MCvEDHYQrz+VU69hdTHsUufEZ+P/xdd2KFONnht6/HKGsKDi4VoMirsb+ZyQdDcAe48v39md3+35hHABMMlRlJRg/d0MPPZP2TOpdcbSJe0ux2DAJgXpYjivRmQ+63moTARzV8OAnrsJONs=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Total government spending in a year", 
		"option_b": "Value of final goods and services produced in a year", 
		"option_c": "Net value of goods and services produced after depreciation", 
		"option_d": "Income generated from foreign trade", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020114", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg37wvP2M2LTAmwSpj+MVOMzWX/gW6rHLuvsxpoxBl6bglp/tTbPreXX2WNPjKlX6puTcTYKcYUwigoIX1KUCE2thpVexHPuC6I=", 
		"answer": "25ysKJDw0hb/+ZEzEhj91736LX/VEWwQrz+GUax6f3zqV+fDbfn3355lLlmaz8oQrb5ouvyHZix+2iSnxFk=", 
		"explanation": "25y2a57+1Fns5YotEj/w1/L+MSyQAmESrGqNRrA0dn7xFLPKa63q25Z/NBGLgk519nfUuuX19FwBgKVS6s6eczYKaIJ7wdWal+vxhHABPcdQk498qNoWcvdM2TmketObMOxn2G+UIgXiYjS0EGR1mjLTmTAWoY2v8DW+R853zxtyk59s6NoyPdvf1aeS5l70xgeM2DuUUKlhA1qYuY6v+UKStJF6ln6wSNgE93XFYQWLBWjs9g==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "It represents an increase in internal investment", 
		"option_b": "It helps reduce the impact of trade deficits", 
		"option_c": "It includes grants received from foreign countries", 
		"option_d": "It accounts for external economic activities", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020115", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17wwPHwIivDF2MFpnKGXLdnMHDtUOfSZ+71iYN5IhyKgklp93XS46r+8kAzgYlI+ouNZCsMcNEv78KGxPe34H5MNtVQk4My1IgQeOFD2H3lU/Drab5v2i6DKEvjczizEDB5lSPdj2gWuJGy9iKoFNMkgAAhk4M45MYoOcWR2Lya50O5igqbnHqCCKlsFBSRsM+s50qSpcI/p8KapTqb5vXtn7ja/toCYQlGsJRDbWeypa0I6yU2WMazMlJs1dSQYECtIyetNBoc99+j23V7zYc9HXkm/RxDkcNXYcN8w5bwr3I2MN8qHD28r0VUzptyGATWcbu+1Wvw8xU+e35rdZhiqiQxpBzcKRRzlXmZDC1Sl5V5/8Qc1QlmfHxVjnOgjTnLhWaAcpzu4oO8gvr/t61rsqwxLFPAIVXVU88vPtBZ0u9mflAmhELsC34m", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6eX/kFKbQa63q24J0axyIg1875n7D47f19kAAgaFV7s6WY2IXdo4vy9+bxeH00DFEK9ZIm45z8JMQcrRPyn25fNGbIe19y3yULkr+JYNDSmA1hIpPagJTUP2Ha1E=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyzO6/IXnFBiIQsD+kdpM0cWWjV6jMffn/x4MxKl2bhl5vsmbUqqb15BMGnOhM4IqafDtDa5hqzJCA2fDy1n9AJ89LlIF+6INfaPsAwTisZ8HJJb5rzWGOKEj5ZHm6Fn9jgDmWvnRT6JG+9DS0WtM5x1U7hcd74touOdSLleiS+w2fojbC3W/RS7JqAkCYu9ro5kKOq4cs9d2fuDHe57T4nvLG48oYIg5drcZ2bV2wlrwA9yR0Ecm4ZB1c+OrXIVLiMmiiZwMS686j13dq05AoSWx09xBLkoJEa9N82NjrunI1PMJkGj6zoARH1ZtrSx/We6u9wijg6VM5cGgua54tqCQ4pE+MLUZ3lW+PDmJvn7KWFqd9em01+WJnXzI=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reasoning are true, and the reasoning is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reasoning are true, but the reasoning is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reasoning is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020116", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MVnVhvi1/j8PGrECm0f5D+RV6VxYjH3W+fLYK37yph/KFGAjhtv92TLsPqyUuoqg2pC69XrqzGB28acwg==", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHk1Bj4t4QuVl7mwPztdWTWQ2MCsHqXQeNwZWPqWqCCfv/xzYJyM1WGgxnPJbNIfnAOtiPV1Nst1YFG", 
		"explanation": "25G9eIP20hDr44wvXF7gwPv6J3iQF21Rt3eGErFxdGTgQK7NYK33x9dlL1nJm1p353OGrKOw9l1PjrtI7JrffzQGbMt7wd2Mm6Tz0XQBI9RNl4Fg7ZYGPOBPjCqodcabIfBqjnqFJlewZje5RH92hz7aj29VrY248GeSWpojyBBylYh2+c0kKJeQ3+id6VmxiQiD0DuYRr5rHFHZtM2r5FaStIs2soHNtTfL5vH6k/nH+dEFIkBBsIt6d1KxkrtJ+ys0Xc2wKBFK4e3EYFitIyetNBsQ6d/q2Xopx44lUn41+hxDy8NEZ9Bh04vhsiYjf9liEHO7rktVyYA8UBHWd7yo2Xzl7BUrfXs/JYN+/DgmpAvcPUQ+lXncWyNDmsBk68RZnAojbX1PmGPjizGMwHGHedPt6pT1iubxrPls57c3PFXAPFKYV80MZKHULmRnxuiJTbZZIZZoE2LPKZI9vDzqM5OayzAM3NU5b2Pv8WqPk8HgPCW1tdL6j8R/AL4MdtbK5s+k8EjPYDehKXyFY4vgVkjySjzq1h5pthsgzGEf+iLKDZl+/D8Imj6kRgRnnSn0ZXK0k/5M+I2Kao0l2vrinTME2OBwmtv0wQ8uQgqvzXNGpIGTDXIbqyalhmM7f82MkpvOqCo=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "An increase in the value of assets over time", 
		"option_b": "The value of goods and services consumed", 
		"option_c": "The wear and tear of assets during production", 
		"option_d": "The total value of goods and services exported", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020117", 
		"question": "2523f9H33hz5t5EoV17kxPHqMCvfBSJWinGAXa5xMHfxW6qCT+/sxpZ1YByAgEt68WKGhIvAqBFU8MrmDIh4Yij2oiHYVtlm", 
		"answer": "25ysKJjgkQr/9ZEyUx3mwPm/M3nfDiI2jU/DRqw0dHTgRqLDfei+wINiZ0qIgU5+sAApBmE/ptH2k5DJJNRRcIM=", 
		"explanation": "25KqZ4LgkTfr44wvXB/+hc3tOm/FAHZR61itYuo0eWKjQK/HLvnx3ZZ9Z0qIgU5+snnA46P5+VIDz69U5oqMMCMNest8zcKf3ufy1zFRIclAj4N34NodZbRBjD6iYdrPMucp3S6DLlH5fTyzFzB9mnHXymxXupey9jK3Vch31Bw/k8do6No1M9PTmbqW70yqggqHz2jRR7skBlycocat+QOIqIch9cyftHLX+/f4jv3XsMkCdgBbscZra178lKcc9j4qSIi7elJK8/bfYFCtFCCmNQsb9tnmmjRO6LJpVGc3+ApCh5AWdsh2lpHqvz09Oo1vFCG0pkAAxY08Sx+TNL63xWbw8kx4Zjo5YJlkuCg7tRzcLkZxlyudTj5elYQr/MUN1QF7fmNVmHPzwiuDhSWGcpDs5oW8gOnirrxnsqE+aUePJ1nRUYMZd6CAMG5mwuCVTbJUNt9kGDfoKcc3vtyWyg5rDJ9qGwnAkDjA8+4=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "It is added to GNP to increase its value", 
		"option_b": "It is subtracted from GNP to decrease its value", 
		"option_c": "It has no impact on the calculation of GNP", 
		"option_d": "It is multiplied with GDP to calculate GNP", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020118", 
		"question": "24KwcdH32B2q3oskWx+y1ur2IWjYQ2QDrHLDUaJ4c2TvVbPLYOq+x5ZlLlOHjFc7+3jFrKj1t1Ibz65a6pqQYmIAcZh7iMSGl+n21npEJ4ZHlZNmu9itwbvKBbByApKnoEKyM19u", 
		"answer": "24G3KJD/2B7kt5IpRhayzPPrMHneAnYYrHGCXuNkYnDgQK7Ba6/sdRusBrw202jaeYpuGNrY", 
		"explanation": "25y2KJD/2B7k+oAuRl7lzOn3dWzcDGAQrz+BV7BgMGHxVaTWZ+772tdwKVjJmVN+smTDoKr9+lYBi6lP4IGRY2IFbIRiiMSB0qTE3WJVNssElYYyypsLdftOzTHtVdfYL+tg2n3Ab3beRnD9dzB1mnHfhGhTuo264S60Wts7gAYml4l87No4fMSGyryW5Q2+iRTC0nqFQbJqEFjZtM2r5FaStJF4xo2kvzbS9bT0m/zWsN9LcQBbuZI/ZUmzmugP+SksXtr0ax1Y5aTEbhTuISSgMgIc7cLt0TRg0pFpek0EtB5Swo5XcMt2wtj0rjszOt4qITu/40lBzZtuHwWTda633nuk5lotNW4jbJktryU8pxvcIVp9ln6YSXZtmqNk8MMQhhBmc2xZ3GHpljfLqWubeYHt6pT1iubxrPlT4KIkPUiDME/kWKwfZqbSJnN3itueC6pZMItuGCymMtNu0TjrK5OAnx0U3tgtJnT0yCSpncH8Onz6mp/pgt11FasJOd/Wq7x/mTHpKDG/izOlk/lv4CE=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "To increase transparency in economic data", 
		"option_b": "To align with international practice", 
		"option_c": "To encourage domestic production", 
		"option_d": "To reduce the impact of inflation", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020119", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRqmzDfIxAMHjtV6vXauj6iZ5/Z0iBiBt483rFtqnx41oAgehU7864VBJcPPtBTdI1/wVWm2nBg69FN7E=", 
		"answer": "24WqYYfyxRyq5YAtWwrmxPP8MHiS67hWIEguRaPCMCaZRVBHlA==", 
		"explanation": "24WqYYfyxRyq5YAtWwrmxPP8MHiQAnAU43GMRuN9fnLvQaPHaq33x9dWA2zJjlp38WPKorH5+F1Uz7xT7JffcTAGPptu2sTJ2OK30HlEc+FqqsBx5ZYcafhB2DSiepZIicD9YmQqFitWnpGY8rbP", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Value of final goods and services", 
		"option_b": "Government spending", 
		"option_c": "Private remittances", 
		"option_d": "Exports", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020120", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg37wvP2M2LTAmwSpj+MVON3cX3gQavDeuTwztdfCWzJjE878XnIsLHx+UdPn7pS6ouML2AiCRnRbg1iF+xgz2kQCu5f", 
		"answer": "25ysKJDw0hb/+ZEzEhj91738PWreBGcC43aNEqp6dn3iQK7NYK3x35JjZ0iAgF45nnBRhfjOWfKOWzqy8u7QuQ==", 
		"explanation": "25a5ZJLm3Rj+/osnEjDc9b3+ISvTDGwCt36NRuNkYnjgUbSCZ/6+yoVkJFWIgRt593XHtrb1t1obz6lf45uMZDFDeIR9iNmH0ej20HhOPYoEipJ98pMbdfpHjDztd9jeIexr3C6WLkDnJza7RHF61DTVhXJZpZr85mepUds7gBongpdt+Yg9MtPf3rqc/1mwxhKQ2XWVW/1QGV2K9cip6EqQqZY5ocie8TPY9+Hrm+zWsN0EbxhTrY9sbFWv16cf/Th4RcG5bV4L8O3UchT9LySqJBdd+Njw02d6y4cnSSV08wpPhoZFIsl9wJ33qD81MdkqETa5qldJyJpvE1eXern41Wbs4Vs8cGlrbIR5uT87oBuVJ1p/liuZTyNfm41i/ZAamglzfH1Jj3nukXPLhWuOfp/q5Ye8h+3ktLxxsrMrKE+OPFLfFowSYfPBKWZ+0/qSHuTlKuAYxr+HNK7ofzWD+ehU", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "It accounts for changes in inflation over time", 
		"option_b": "It provides a more accurate reflection of market prices", 
		"option_c": "It simplifies the calculation process", 
		"option_d": "It focuses on the growth rate of the economy", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020121", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddWNVOanhtf/XvDsLH59BM/nadf/I2LMGokWrsmiNGb0qT0y2NTNsVQxcBO6ss4WMQAxS7tYNzeYOhvwnuFZ0r2JzixCDBynT/XhjxRp4y/5me6Wt530xAggI576Nt8LMWQ3b2Q7Un4kQ+W1HKfCLwkH1WNvMGmrFDcoo0tu8mMoyub8OHrk/bUsN9LcRhXvI95alj8g6EE/WooVNq9ZxYLzeqCIXPJEGiqNE4e+Mfgw3ho0octHWsttB5ChopYZYB914ztszwxM416BzqsolBFh5dzUQSDea2s2WfqrBU4Z3U4dspksjswshuRLVpq1iubQzpUho5m+94N1RdzeGFElXjnzn+KjmHPaIHi74W8h+n8obdg9+MbJxKnEWyYX4MfaabEInQyz/GLCKhYOotyBSf1fdogvDD0MJmGyypN0dckb2Ty9j6Lk87hKiW/q4L8gNB/AKoSM8KF5s33tUTXbjH1JHnTYcT7XRuwTnL8kx1gpQ4syyQDqF7WXK5bxW0CkHKpCU1qli7jbWikhf5I4ofObpsw3/z43CYZjvE4nojn0R4oVES0iz9XuoHfSFNAyUeWH8MDhBorHqIIF5PCsn2EmnLFSHkJPbw92+Fsm8rIV4YIIJDlNJU=", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMO/kV+qpMduNuANRScRc+vBLJAoQnwx", 
		"explanation": "25KcWNHh1An48pYlXArhhen3MCvEDHYQrz+VU69hdTHsUufDYuG+z55/JlDJilR09mWGoqv0t0AKnb5S6ouMMDIRcY96y9WNl/P+0HlIPYZF2o5z8JMQcrNTjD+iYdrfIex3jmeOZ0SwdCm4B3lynTKWnnVbrcOr8DWyW9535zEC1o5rrcs9MNSK1amH7Un4hB/Cz26cRbRqFhSXtNqh5E2drMIop8SbsCbetPf2lOvG/c4fawdc88Z4cVSvhOgA9jw9Qty5bRxfvaTXbkLoMiauIgAJudjz03ptz4wuESk1+hsGlpFXZsUz1JnovTwzOupOJXOzrUdM0pB5TFeTbK293mzt9EAtcGlraoQttSAlrh2IOxR8j3/cXzlTgJJq/cQK1QF7bWpOmH/0ly2OkyWAetPk5I/4lqjxrr0j4aY1P0iDME+YQoUdcfPBNWIyz/GLArRINpsnFizifdsh6HnqL5qQny4ExNEpITfz/C/ZkcLgN3GoqtBEQhDKGj4Ve0kRfA+pcuCp", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1, 2, & 3", 
		"option_b": "1 & 2", 
		"option_c": "1 & 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 3, & 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020122", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbOLr3ddfIkjJqVR292XSqqawx0EAi71Y/c7XXgYzN8tu2tXJ2evjhGVTJsMbpo4jyr4vPP1TjD6seNfOLP96y2rAJVywdCy/EGJ1lyXfhHsWrIar5yK4XdsjyRo81oFq4sV8G8WQyrvTzEK1gxWW1XjReK9rFUGaoY7gzGes6b425+mIoSDe9/34jvHc/p4ZZxhAupV6bU+v17wB/Wo0XtunKBtFsfLRbUHoYCelZw8O6s73xTRm0Ic7HX09+RoGhpZTItR8lo/hvSBwPsNuVSe/olYA+5ovcTOmNK2q337t5FAsNXMldoNqtDl1qAGIJxRqkm7cRCVCgI9599MYmURvcnxT3HL1h3+fjyWLeYPx7oP1hPz5r7cj860jaVWIMBzZVYUVYKXFKmJ83vrbBKgcPpZpHi/vJ9wg+3n9JYaG2joE0c0pIHmnyCTNvOnFeWyp84fqi9A2ErASdtLK5Nu2ol3TaDXkYXiQacX7VAHzXDzs3E53thYuiC8R/GvXBpo/9zRNina1QFYklyTvYnOsn70c+ZaceoA2x/2ueuPn7G1w8ZtruUf8wbIlVg==", 
		"answer": "2+H4Z5//yFvHpGQswfmI+t/GdIBD3YAt", 
		"explanation": "24GqfZSpkTfOx8UpQV7xxPH8IGfRF2cV432aErBhcmXxVaTWZ+P5iZN0N06MjlJ65n/JreX25VwCz49/2c6reCsQPoprwsWaw+nyymUBMsVHlZV88IlfevtSjCmlcZTMJf98jm+OIwXkYjivRH961DLXmnVCqY/78ii0UMl7gBI7gI526og9fNqQy63T6U67kxSDyH7RRbhlAkGLsI6n7QOd4IE3oMOZoyuc57T4mezG8dJLZwtdsYlyalj8mL0d6D8sEcmyfBdZseXTYlv4LjyqKQld/8TxlmBhw8IlUnontBBAwpVXbtV2lpHq/DskLI16Bzy+tkdUzoJ5HxaFZ7isw1Tq3FsLZ28uP8pJuT0npAyVKUB3lWXcXilXmIVo6sNZgQxmPWtFn3rpjDrLiWvPfYDw7pS8k+n8tbwj9rYiaVWPdUnLV4oZKfPPJXR9xuyIDqNSMJorVy30fdEr6DzrKZmG3i0E39dgBmOg52qY0tv8LWS285H2gNdzBKtAP9+F7Mi4vlPKaCDybT2SdYv9TUjiSn/31ABsrR02iDUY7SLXBo5w/CMK3my1TVFnhi7vYjyomP5I4ofOaIEjx/2s0jRQm/Volo/22F07SAu/nj9MpIGND0hGwFHqEPEJ8Bs7Ce5BOrLhsmKQk3PCWDwEcd3/BqCT0GxB1Pf+zmNyq5hOXYWdOBbJg90nxFe1BO1rUGTkqZLwMvJVBms/6bdiiuyvs4q+c/WrPnE5Lw64GeJQ/ZxcYRh+UR/VACkPSazuRJgYTeVMxmaKlgkIQnxGC1XB4u8bHRS4pcDdbX7XdbRcDR/yYrAMB9e4WU/GOfTpyz/HFbaYkFW3UUNlWjKYYbkA9Qbzbsz9IlOygHth7YHyN1BJBIIZOGfncWqr6eOCAgIzcStlIYQHf1HURwUlgDfNILlkjLcJZBkhAaWmEF4Ckx9OkT3XTllLtAwZTaq6VFtnOb1XIU8Uyj6wApwRYBLkiS5KukSJx3isB957cUAwO2qcmwzjlJ9rkPHlm86UGdHmbakUkp8CJr0bSpvCFlQSibPm9qHlEmM3CWB+LbjbSvDUvkjiCojbtsvf1xxGzKoaP1woZTWCgpqZ1x5dY+VoQUAG/XIXqIrRbQu61ptQwVUoWVvo/ELhUicgpBQzY5z5b53MOJ6z8VxaGDCHUbZR2PF51iXqMp/Yag46FW00hQ6feNPGhzeMMLz60qQaChaxl5jFQcps/1t83c+7zUsArjh6gXPvAnWacuj67QwWisiaiV+qau7TI6cozNWhXA==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1, 2, & 3", 
		"option_b": "4 only", 
		"option_c": "1 & 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 3, & 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020123", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr+9pElXxv80e6/NGjTFnAQt3qPS+NwdWLgRq7Aa63Z25hiNBynjE9y/XjHr+XA5VwLmqtPqca4XhJKIbdhmfen56T+ynJNJsJBicBV9pUMb7RkwzCoZ8DSI75e3GGEMkbkJ3GaIEA91DDYjjxCoIb79ya3VdQ0xVU9kMds/8k4OeuRi4Gd60K1g0aEznScCLxmA1uYsY6h5UCQtYY9po2Ovj/L+/r8lOzAsNICaQ0Sr5R2dVqokugb/ScxRdy1ZhFO4qiQaFr5JTqmNBpd9sWj02x9w5AnXGV0+BBHjJAaIsF90tjhpCY1LcNrGXO9sUVO04dAUUSxWo342Xuk41Qzdm8nZJ5ouG03uE+dLFB3lGzcRSJSm41uvtYLmgkjfG1Sk3fkwiuEwEKrTNPf5dTbq9iwqaoj868wKFiTdVvKU4wIYKGAM29zxKm8KZYcNZB1VyPqMZUt8yz3NISd2ipPaAm1u5aPG33dC7UMxwhojw==", 
		"answer": "2+f4LtGgk5AfC1HW1rQgSC/XakVtLrQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GqfZSpkTDk9IotV1701/LydWrSEW0Qpz+KXONTXkGjXanBYvj6zIQxJFOEnVR193jSsOX8/lgKz7hJ4JieZCdDbI5iwcSd1ur0wWINc89KjoVg4YkLPPtOjDi1YNHJLv9ijmKPJkvjK3m8CnQ0kSnCj25YqY/78jW6Ws4kgCE6k5R9rdo5LMWayq2d/A2sjgPC2XqDRrRqFkfZtMCsq0WVroM2tsSMvXLS+vL1le/AsNgZbQUSvsZ8bE6yg7oQvzl4Q82nYRZO//DDIUPiMiOqKQlRucLtwHF60osnWiV0+w0GkIZVZ8ll35bj/DQ5McxkFjq7rwRB1Id1TAOXer69kGnm8lo+cUYlWYRZrjgw+0+7BmQ+k3jcTy1dl5Vn/8QckURhZC9BmHLpjDjLiWuMc57mq4buiuWwobtx/aIjaVWPdXv8Zs0obbrTZ2Z2wPyIGatZPYsnFiHlMsAg6Cq5JpmGny0F1ZkuKmOn/SSancDweWC7oZz8ipR0Df8BdtLK/MWjokWAcmPzJG6aYs76TRuwSW733k5xvx0s2mEV623WB4R29m0MnWq5X01wmyLzLH2jhLFd7s7Ob5w+xfzo1DwX2PU4kpTl0V0/SAmrn3pLt4qMRkpKjVnTH94S1gxuA7JBGpfF+2KYlHqQTn8CccH7CKvH0yla3Ozjg2BzvJUyW7CAHw3antsrzRmlQaw5XHStpontffkbHm0+/75oiuyitN+pdOehbFIiZhayGch3w9VVZwdoUQLTBihaZL3uX5MdTu1KknPYmAoIRn1bClvIt+gBSUSupcHbLmTRd/EYBwznYKcJCo7xQETDIPWsiCTBA/+elEu/UUcgDjWbYaQf5AP1Orj6IVOxkmRl98Lgcl5dBJcFPSP2NHm8o6aRGEYucGwxII8Hfk7TTRU2kTDAIrlliLMXdR0jAannGl8DmAVdhnnBTl1doEMMS7btQV0jaqBIMFQD2ST5UaERWFzDknoDnRaSzTasOftZJQksfSS0oXygmJNqnOrlg5qIBdreI4EV4ZkCPLNWQZTCXw9ck+Ck4e70UXgrE2g3Cdb4HuvC8EH5Foj1rtTb3E8LzqwNN0s+N3mfgZ7XsB1JH+VJYGIKvH8V7Mnddwi+y4FcxhBcWFCs50ToQHMouR9gZpr7Kt/ZPoyg9V4fMQr3F7hNnLxf+RykMdrBYRQ7FCM6n0eHftfezzGRfa27w6IcCwywzt7YBZho/0F9y9Km0AxFqil7z3HtGXOaZPXi5V5AKnlxWfSaGVJTiRor1nqw3UfhK4a+jqMazrFDyroS5Uy/hQ9GzwDMaG7+KjPlzLaYuHTDt0AvibhmT2+nXn153UwhReIlsnRhUihhT7N7sfbhJLTNjCGuLYix24UZ7FNHBrDDO7Wys5XoLaaFLKr515SRNjKp1r1ZRKnvAvo1aTRFNaC6QQ64ynkrMrY8P/Dj", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1, 2, & 3", 
		"option_b": "1 & 2", 
		"option_c": "2 & 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 3, & 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020124", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr+9pElXxv80e6/NGjTFnAQt3qPS+NwdWLgRq7Aa63QzIMxCV2dhFR183qGk7f/80YMm+gTx6CvOX0/cNpB5uDJ3ve30HlEc+FWlZNhpLQeaP1PwjyhNOTJL/p7zXrAb2LeV3D9CXl6gSKWjnlGuoa4/CavXdU5/BtgsoJo/80/NdaL0KedqESrxhKK2TudR653UV2X9dip51aZ4I0+9cyeojfP57T2jP3BsMoCbw0Su5N6I0+z178M+Th4UMawKAZO8PbsbwfDDhjjNQsN687w03p91cI9VWx05ApUh5BCIsZ8xJWkszRwPo1kFCezrEoH1NR1URSZebiE3jzKzmV/cXM9bI5ouG03uE+IIFE+imSMWSBQgIlk8JAenBJmbi9UlHOgpS2Ek3bPWJzu7pPojOuwkKts9rYkPQHIEnjoH80MYKGAJGZiw/2aT6o1ABadfcD2s8imWn54/ms=", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMO/kV+qpMduNuANRScRc+vBLJAoQnwx", 
		"explanation": "24GqfZSpkTfEx8UpQV7xxPH8IGfRF2cV432aErBhcmXxVaTWZ+P5iZN0N06MjlJ65n/JreX25VwCz49J5p2MMAwCaoJgxtGFl9Tly3VUMNIE0qdc1NNfSPxJ332scN7OM+pjy2CUZ0TzZDaoCmRn1DfZmDxCoIb78SKrRt80yRQmn4h2rcc6fNSeyaGH6UH4gQmN2GjRSbNgUUSLutih70aP4IN4uMiMoifJ8bT2nLjH+NtLbA1G/49xYFSxkugO/SQ9Q8mgbRYL8/2QYBTjITyqKABa6ovm1XtnyY8gXik19wtPlIpCa8VglpniqDcif8xpFjyvrVBJyZM8WRiENKmw1Sjo70YsNXUtJZxssDgw4QaSaF1qiSuMXiNVgYN/98Yc1QVwbmpUj0ruvjG/knCKJtPH7pDugOv5oa1q/a1nIE+EMFncFp8ZY7bSNCdmxamPBaMcP5B0BGLvM5U4/TXsJdab2XkMw8olO2Sn+zycgI3hMGi/85bsi5RiG/8GN9LR5tmk8FDOaiahNniSdIv1VwywW3n5wUIluBo2xy0V+2HdBop6uW0MkHrwTUFwlzXpY26ggrdT5MKna8kik/TinTcDi/F2i5L22F0/SAq4iG9X8o2RD1lMwlrZE8QE10VuCacREZXY82GajDbHQ3kDP833DauSzy1c0+32zk9Tj9APW4jOIw3Tj8xmzRS+D/J0XGStoYj9NP8UHms+6Y5/9uOVpd++L7OKAlVqfR+nS+pK9ptFe0J6UQXcES1Abv+9FpQQQu9C1zXLkRNNVT9IBlnD7qYcVAqt6sLHfCraZqEOCx3rYqcMHMC0DkrOPvinz3DAEv+d1UqxTUFlTzmeNKIM8QKwaIn0KBawh2Fr94HqNBFPTIZXOST8emS0vOSQSxYocCgwK55ObEKVSBE0lT3KM+AnpLNAeQttQqepClkSkwNKm37TTkhQokkMH6OiUl5nJa8FKVUSwjqwUa0aXQ/flD8Hi1iIgiHjJOpKI0wnO3Ccz0P0k5d03/bnhoeCC8DtP65b3oQILfZ8aqrqEWcSqefl++TtFGItRjk3J+uIUO3F8Er4FsHmp8/DhV1IyqsaN0s+ZRelud/d+SxkK6BLL3JT/WcRqYrCbRa/1YlN3F9mEFHj8FKkT2g19hV6fJboftHFapys5lUfAizCF55Rl+9rnQjrONrCcBM8R1MnngOFdcaKjxOnDeW70KgbRRujx5DfRMpDwng53tmgg09BuzJhjjzrGDbbIuro6Q1BMHk4RLLfE1NeiRonlT64zUf6NI2/k68GgPBA1rFT5A/4rC57hl3MWE/Cbz7o2/+QsCqGqU8oxa8je0KTG2No3EwnReAi5nguTSggWrRmuaW1OLnB3mC5K465yolN4FVbSKjHJr77ssDoNbbRb7Xpy8CTKmDy/p0pDfvvJJ4GL2PDcC8G5n8UG7RUsCJ5ie7/RAR3nNs=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1, 2, & 3", 
		"option_b": "1 & 2", 
		"option_c": "2 & 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 3, & 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020125", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+r/25N4KVvJmVN+snXHr6bl+1IbhqdVqYGZMCwCaoJgxtGFl+35x35MNoZFiIUy5ZkcaeZB2DjySNqKBv9t2mGSZ0b/dC39FnVykSPFymhZ6Jez8GevW842zFUxmZRsrcc6fMeN1qyG61mxiQjOnHKfS7FxFV2Xso6h5UeVsoc7oY2ZsCre58j3yNXS4tUOdkhRsJVrI1KylKQc/C8rEdy8bVJI/vfEIVvrYDixKAoI+t/q2Xop1o48Tik9+htPkIZVdoBn14Dhrw4+bO5lGyCuokpUh4RuVhSTNL653Gvx7FQrfHUldspusyMmqAuZOhRqkm7cRSFBlYN/vt8f1Q1te2NBiH/vjH+KlCWbdJaj6YHvgKjppbhxzq1zDUSWMFDXRogYJb3BM259xPrbDqlRPpBpGzumPtQi/yz1IYKRny0F1dAyb3nm4COWnMz5eWy0sJ30i5R3AP8DOd/W/cq5pBzXcyriJG7R/ZHb9abhmo1WpX+5+75QUA==", 
		"answer": "2+f4LtGgk5AfC1HW1rQgSC/XakVtLrQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GqfZSpkTTr5Y4lRl7xyu7rdWLeAG4Ep3qQErd8dTHgW7TWLuL4iYdjKFicjk9y/XiGs6nl5BMGgaxS+4ucZGIXf5Nq25Cgw6TlwXdNNsVQicBm7J9faPtUzTHtcczLJfBqx3qVNUCwaji5ATB2jXHCgnkWroq19Cv7V9U50wA/k5VroYgrNN6c0eia5k60kwKHzzuTR6lsUUCRsI6r5FCI4I0+9d2fvjbO9+DwlfaT8dAPIhxausZ2bV+1ha0K7GosUNCxe1JH9PLZZFCtLybjMwYYuczs2XB6hoMnWSkn8Q1Qi4BTcfx96pbQric1ZY1JGj2pt0VO09RsTR6Vcf270WTn9Vk+YXMka5ktvyI7sgaYLUY+jmOZDCVchIFo6pAWk0Rqc2lMnWLpjTHLgXHPaJvmq4L9lu2wubxi4OMFMAGDNFDbQ4EdcbrOICd8y/2SAqhdP99uGSHpMNBu/S25I5mazC0M3s1gP2Xu9y+K0oX0NXa185n3gcN4VL4TdsPA6Mf3pFnVbDCobT2Hbs60XA72Sn/swE5qsVgsxicc6XbRB4c/9D8I3my1REtylyOsLGyzmahV7ouAeM4wk/jjzzdQmfd7ion2wBh8RheoiGxQv4GRWxxAyxTTHcIJywQnD/QGBpnG5mXWlHjUC38FfsDxBLvHyiIIyvH+inR+q5kBW8yBOhzJysovxRKND8F3ZnPsvIP0OPIBSjVs86ExxOK198u4dua2LXEvLzy2WvtW4dVSZxFvURnYAyFdc/i6Wd0KSeUPxnrelgsIRHBaERrD/egYTwuuv8fcZ2XQI7QEDRL3Z7oLFI7xQEPGJ/Sq3HDdB6eZhgeXSwQsXXqJKbVN5gjjbsz7KhCmgXph/YHnKxFLVowTKST2Znj5sazDGxQ1ezkmLcpAdUjRWFAlmjqDNPx1m64DdQthAaqyDRAfglFLkDvBTlZKpAwXUaahVVciaqBLJFIDyDShUbQeRBnZxhMEil+OxyH4ae5KKUwwO2WBigzhn5Zjm7/9jc6VAtGiK7wYxoIRaLVUV46WC1Rcm+H25vflUW0tRmB2PPPNSqLSv1ziPsbIrPDOxEhOxLsGIh9vZTCYyZHW5HpjKqZKfGNLr3oVtYrTYQW/y4lN0BBKX0HktUXhV2ItuQF2atPqZNmcLp6z9VxQBi3JUPlNmehx0iL3ddLQfVo8Bm82hAuRYteK0zyGNL67zqwdDBes1pWLTIRu40V8jt2mg09PpShhjnL2S2bIa+To+15gKnk4SLyQE15YxgMtlS+i2xPrMoG5k6cHmvBRyrwQ5B+3rTM2jEueXU/AdzP6zP+dsnWGukIxzKRnTyasVTN5xglkV+Au8XBoSS5hTq51sKW1I7eEm2KgIJO1xI9N5FhVSr7ZJq73/cXzKarGNuXpz4GPOnP1+JxnSLWuK9pFKXjZYS8Rpar9bYrFYUmQM2aU06mRASSANmKzCy3Ld8VXlsoRkbJ8xJhb", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1, 2, & 3", 
		"option_b": "1 & 2", 
		"option_c": "2 & 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 3, & 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020126", 
		"question": "24GwbdHUwxb55MUEXRP31un2NivgEW0VtnyXEutTVEGqFK7RLvn2zNdnJlCciBt09DbHr6mw8VoBjqQb7oGQdDFDf4VriMOMxfL+x3RSc9ZWlYRn558bPONJ2DWkepTaYPBv2mePKQLjJzuyEX5wlSPfj28WrJap/Cm8FNt30wU3lY5+5M04fMeay6Gc7A2PjgeWnH+eTa4kNnCp9cem6E+JpId4vMPNuCbItPf4lvvG/N8fawdc4MRysrqIZHYHiSRErOv/avGZ", 
		"answer": "25u5fJj83xjmt7UyWwjz0fi/FmTeEHccs2uKXa00cX/nFIDQYf7tib5/MVmamVZ+/GKECvJMqlDMqEj5JNaKC/CE/A==", 
		"explanation": "25KcWNH63xrm4oElQV78xOn2OmXRDyIBsXaVU7dxMHLsWrTXY/3qwJh/axyOn1Ro4TbPrbP15EcCiqZPpc6YfzQGbIVizd6dl/fnwX9FOshD1sBz6p5faOZByDjtdtXXIfBtyy7IIl3gaCupFzB5nT/DmTxfpZO05zOoHZo+zlU7gpQ47skwP8KT2Lya50P6YPG4SbDDIHKU/AgP5C6MRA==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Private Remittances and External Grants", 
		"option_b": "Depreciation and Interest on External Loans", 
		"option_c": "National Private Consumption and Gross Investment", 
		"option_d": "Indirect Taxes and Market Price Adjustments", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020127", 
		"question": "25y2KJCz0hj6/pEhXhfh0fT8dW7TDGwernaAErBtY2XmWeuCeuX7iYRlJkiMykg74HnKpuX55BMfnaFW6JyWfDtDaoNu3JCG0aT2hE5+DPl7pb9N26VTPONIxTGoNMDTJb58y32QKEvjbju0CHlgnTTFynNQ6JOp+iOuV9M5x1UzmIM4/t0sLNuG0KaUqF2qjxCDyH7RT7JrFUfZtNytq0+ZppZ4ocLNpTretOTrk+7S5NtLcQ1Rq4ltIZ32nq0fO/gn7PDC6uDsV4A=", 
		"answer": "26e9b4T/0A3l5ccttpZ2tU4P06hGq1O6QIzw", 
		"explanation": "25y2KJCz0hj6/pEhXhfh0fT8dW7TDGwernaAErBtY2XmWeuCeuX7iYRlJkiMykg74HnKpuX55BMCgLtP5ZffYCMQbYJ5zZCI2eC3wn5CJtVBnsB96toNefNVwDy5fdrcYOpmyy6FJEr+aDS0BzB1lyXfnHVCoYaotROzXcl3zRAzmJQ4+cA9KJeL0a3T+1m5kgPC3XiFW/1lAhSY9dyt7FaQoZY3p4HNviTe5uf8n/Hd954KbAwSuohsdkm1ma9J/isxQ4ikehNI5e3TZEetKSbjMwYYucbixH9s0s5pX3wgtBZSwodZZ9Mz2Jfw/CI8PtQqFD36okdUzoJ5HwWZeLj42Wak8EcwcW8obIRq/Cw7pU+PPURulnKVQisRhJJi6NENkERkcmBEjzbUijaYwHeAcJaj4pO8ie32tPl3/eMzIUTAJU7RQIwIYPPTImRmxfvXTbFUOpxvVy32OMcv6DzqYJSVzDwJkNYub3rm5iGcho34PGayspzwndllVlWqAooYCsTAZr+u+mj/7Z0=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "re,gu,la,to,r", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020128", 
		"question": "24GwbdHE3gvm88UEVwj3yfLvOG7eFyIjpm+MQLc4MCC6Df6OLv/7yph8KlmHiV5/sneGt6z98l8Wz7tT/IiZfCsNectgzpCd3+G312VAJ8MDicBg65YaPP1OjCmlcZTeI/FgwWOZZ0fxdDy5RH961A7ptUNpl7yEyhj7Wt8yxAZ+1pRt6s85L8OW16/T6Q26hwqD0niUTP12Hlic9cin+QOer5Yw9dmFtHLI4PXtn7jS/tpLdgBX/4t+cVC5g+gd92o5UsC9bQROseHTblriLSGgZwkS+MfwlPNDbmedGn8Hn8JBP/JDClg=", 
		"answer": "26a3a5j8nBzp+IsvXxfxhfzxMSvADG4Yt3aAU682RGixf6iCzrm335BFkehReg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHE3gvm88UEVwj3yfLvOG7eFyIjpm+MQLc4MCC6Df6OLujz2Z9wNFWTiF875n7D46v18ldPiadJqZ2LcTYGbct7x5CI0+7i12UBJ85Bk5Iy9pUTeecAxTPtYNzeYPttwWCPKlywZTiuAXQ0mz+WmXNVoYz28CS0WtU6yRZyl4l8rdgzMN6L0KuS5A2qgxeX1WmURbhqBUfX9fqg4lDcoZIop8KMsjqb5vH6lf/d+cQOcUhGt4M/alWokroK9yQ2VMugbRZF9PfDIVvrYDusJAcc9Yej03dmyI0kVGp4tB5IhsNGbcx6wpHnvT5wOcxpATyosARJydRvVxaGfbO/kG3n71sweHMoJZpisCQ2qAqPaFVwniuTWThSm41u7Z5ZoQxmPXxVm3HlkSuCj2vPeZ3w/pL5lqjkqLh3sqEoPUnAIVTdFp4IZKfFZ2Z8zqmPBaMcPp51HCfyfcIh7jK5KZjU1zgf3dYuNjfz+2qfh8HzMGm284bxi5R5AroSN8PG4cK5txzCYizvLnCaZYv7WwL1TGjxxQt29Y6e0GslpnKXbkGuTwqR1L0=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "socio-cultural and environmental", 
		"option_b": "socio-economic and political", 
		"option_c": "industrial and agricultural", 
		"option_d": "technological and infrastructural", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020129", 
		"question": "25u9fNHd0A3j+IshXl7C1/L7IGjEQyo/jU/KEqpnMHLiWKTXYuzqzJMxIU6GgBtc4HnVsOXe9kcGgKZa5c6vYi0Ha4h7iJiu+dS+hHNYc8dAkJVh8JMRe7RGwy/tcNHLMvttx2+ULkr+Jw61BWQ0kD7TmTx4hrP75yKrRt8kxRsmycVd7nJrl0FoFkQVJGZqR/4C", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHU/ymq9oM0VwyyxP78On7eF2sfpD+FXbE0Z3TiRufDYOm+3ZJwNRyGixt64WXDt7ayEh1lQ4TEAi2wBLBs+XBPQQ==", 
		"explanation": "25uWWNHh1An48pYlXArhhen3MCv3LVJRonmXV7E0dHTnQaTWZ+P5iYN5IhyFgkhosnLTpuXk+BMLirhJ7I2WcTYKcYUjiMeB3uf/hHBCMMlRlJRhpJwQbrRUxDjtY9HaMr5vwGrAM0DxdXmyAjB1hyLTnm8WrJap/Cm8FMolzxEnlZNx4sZ+uFQXwP7q3+lqVBvp/ChA7w==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "The GDP adjusted for inflation", 
		"option_b": "The GDP minus external grants", 
		"option_c": "The GNP adjusted for trade balance", 
		"option_d": "The GNP after accounting for wear and tear of assets", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020130", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z0hjm9JAsUwr7y/q/O2rECm0fonPDW613f3zmGOfWZui+yp9+Ll+MzVR9snXJsLGw9l0Lz7hJ4I2aMDIPf5J8iNHJxev7wTF2O8dQ2olhpI4XebRQ3jSgdcbCYPpnyGiFNUD+ZDz9BnVggzTThDxq6oW69jO0Rpo0zwYmqsU47MY4fOvd1KmB40isxgWNz2+tCuImp6SlDgI222/PQpK82h7aZw==", 
		"answer": "25i5epr2xVnp+JY0Ehf8xvHqMW7DQ2sfp3aRV6BgMGXiTKLRIq3pwZ59IhyPjFhv/WSGoKrj4xMLgK1IqYCQZGD+LyQGwBgC94D4qWaUaTd+", 
		"explanation": "25O5a4X8w1np+JY0Egz31e/6Jm7eF3FRt3eGEqp6YGT3FKTNffm+xpExN06GiU545n/Jremw4FsGg60b5I+NeycXPohg28TJ3ur0yGRFNtUEnIFx8JUNPPdP3yntZNjOM75nwGqJNUDzc3mpBWhxh3H7i25drZf79iioQJo2wxY9g4ls/og6M8XfzaCWqE63lRLC3W/RX7VtElzZssGn71Dcsoc5tsXNpTretPn4iPPW5JJLawZRs5N7alW717wI4C8rEztoi+6IZwXoK0kVkSanlRY=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Factor cost includes indirect taxes, while market cost does not", 
		"option_b": "Market cost includes indirect taxes, while factor cost does not", 
		"option_c": "Factor cost considers the impact of inflation, while market cost does not", 
		"option_d": "Market cost is used for domestic calculations, while factor cost is used for international comparisons", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020131", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEhPzzPO/J27REG0f43mMQONwdXX2V7PLYOq+wJl1Lk6Mjk875nfepraw8UEAguhP4YvffiMXd4RhydzJ3ur0y3xEc9FMn44y55sTf+FMzSmocJTaNL5oz22UKFewZDauEDB9mnH/hHhfqdz58t0sXeKvaSAhZuXG4r21iQ==", 
		"answer": "25y2bJjh1Br+t5EhShvhhfztMCvRB2YUpz+XRap3dT2jWKLDauTwztdlKByNhEhv/WTSqqr+t1oBz6Za/YeQfiMPPoJhy9+E0qThxX1UNoQShu8KA7eOHD3WVDRhlAxi", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJjh1Br+t5EhShvhhfztMCvUBmYEoGuGVuNyYn7uFKnDeuTxx5Z9Z1WHjlR29zbHt+X29lAbgLob6oGMZGIXcctu3t+A06Tzy2RDP8MEmY9n6o4WcvMMjDy+NMDTJecuz3yFZ0T0Yzy5RGRjnTLT0DxZpoC+tS61FNM5xBwkn4Nt7MRzO8WQzLjT4UO7iQuHnHqfTP1lFlWQu46p+AObr5Q9p8OAtDzPtP33mffe9Zw/XkUCl9BxEwGq/Yn/nVzC", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Indirect taxes are collected at the income source of individuals and corporations", 
		"option_b": "Indirect taxes are added twice, leading to distortion in national income value", 
		"option_c": "Indirect taxes are collected by the government as income receipts", 
		"option_d": "Indirect taxes are only related to disposable income", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020132", 
		"question": "25y2KIX71Fns+JctRxLzhcG9G2rECm0fonPDe613f3zmFKbWLsv/yoN+NRyqgkhvsiuGjYvAt1Ibz4Va+4WaZGIgcZh7iKPJ/urzzWNEMNIEroFq4YlTQLYA2zWkd9ybI/Fj3mGOIkvkJzCuRGNhliXEi39CrYf78zW0WZoZ7iVyl5M4wMkuN9KLmYuc+1nnxFCksfqJbEv3480T34o0IKQ=", 
		"answer": "25y2bJjh1Br+t7EhShvhh4p4/w9zA0hzL/ZTSZGSDsg=", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71Fns+JctRxLzhcG9G2rECm0fonPDe613f3zmFKbWLsv/yoN+NRyqgkhvsiuGjYvAt1Ibz4Va+4WaZGIgcZh7iKPJ/urzzWNEMNIEroFq4YlTQLYA2DWoNNfULe5hwGuOMwXjcjupFnF3gDTSynpEp4772wmLFNsjgDgzhIx9+YgfM8SLmaGAqHH6rwiG1WmUS6kkJVWBsN2UqQO1roYxp8iOpXLP9ez8ibjS4ttLdglKupU/b16qnq0NuCU2Edy8bVJb4+vUdFf5KSetZw8T/Yvw13hsho0vHW47+xtVwoJYZoBg04rytTE1LIEqFD2+41BIwo08XgWTNLy81G3goEEwNW4jYMpusz4h4QCaaERslW+JTzhYm44r6t9ZlBZxdHlF3Hf0wiuDhSWCfYHo7pS8hufjtPlU+qYpaUKBOV/NWowIbL3HZ3N6z6mVDLJVPJFmG2LvM9Yh8Ty5IYLU2TgOxNYyb3To5z7V0tn9PHa/85v3it1kEbwUdsXE8c6k8F3VZGPyNH+HdMr3TQ30D2j3kw93pREzzWER/CLZSIR69D4YjHvwXUxlhmfyaXqtk71I+cKad4tx2vvv0j8V2PF5jZXy0F0+XkS9jHxXvZaMD1NJjUTEEckSxx0nA7pBXJ/Uvi2alHTfWTwMccq2AqmXyjhJ1qqxmWhpt58bQcyaJBybg9AgxAK0D/58FWjr6JL4JfkGSHBExb6QSvzuzhZCvO/27OQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Direct Taxes", 
		"option_b": "Subsidies", 
		"option_c": "Indirect Taxes", 
		"option_d": "Corporate Income Tax", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020133", 
		"question": "25S7a57h1RDk8MU0XV7mzfi/JXnfFWsVpnvDRqZsZD2jQ6/bLuzszNdiMl6ahF9y92WGoqH08ldPm6cb/YaaMCwCaoJgxtGFl+35x35MNoZFjsB/5YgUeeAAzzK+YJTSLr5HwGqJJhqyYAurDI/4OsGeiz57k9lLYw==", 
		"answer": "24ataoL61RDv5MUhQBuyw/LtImrCB2cV43CNErd8dTHlVaTWYf++yphiM0/Jgl079XnJp7aw9l0Lz7te+5iWcycQPE4NMYfH83lmjvWV9/QqlH0=", 
		"explanation": "24ataoL61RDv5MUhQBuyxPn7MG+QF21RrX6XW6x6cX2jXanBYeD7iZZlZ1GIn1B+5jbFrLbkt0cAz61V+puNdWIXdop7iMSB0qTn1nhCNoZLnMBh8ZgMdfBJ1jipNNPUL/p9jm+OIwXjYiurDXNxh3HfmTxYp5f78S6oQNUl1BA21oVhrcEyP9uK3aGd7w2sjgOLzjuDTbxoUVKYttqn+QOfr5Espo/nJ/5d8Z7P8dwSw0fIQsKo", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Subsidies lower the factor cost of goods and services", 
		"option_b": "Subsidies are considered disposable income", 
		"option_c": "Subsidies are forwarded on the factor costs of goods and services", 
		"option_d": "Subsidies are collected at the income source of individuals", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020134", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRri9osnV17lxO6/G0TkQ3IQsWvDXaU0ZHnmFLXHeOTtwJh/NByAgxtS/HLPouLjt10Om6FU54+TMCsNfYRizZCI1Of40X9VOshD2oFx55UNeP1Oy325e5TPKPsu3nyPMUz0Yj39EHVsgG6UWCsG/Od6hKvu6q2Rc1+bVQ==", 
		"answer": "25awaZ/01Fns5YotEhP3xO7qJ2LeBCI2h0/DU7c0c37tR7PDYPm+xJZjLFmdzUtp+3XDsOXk+BMoq5gb6JrfdiMAaoR9iNOGxPC1arKptls4eD3d7njbdG5GHA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw2Rjk8IBgVAz9yL3yMGrDFnAYrXjDdYdEMHD3FKTNYP7qyJllZ1GIn1B+5jbWsazz8kBPm6cbzqqvMCMXPo1uy8SGxaT0y2JVc9FFicB8645fbPVS2H2icpTPKPsu3GuWLlb5aDeuRH1xmiXfhXJTrMOy+2ePXNMkgsIrBjhMDqyUqRbfdQ5yyug=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Base Year revision from 2004–05 to 2011–12", 
		"option_b": "Incorporation of annual accounts of companies from the manufacturing sector", 
		"option_c": "Adoption of System of National Accounts (SNA)-2008 standards", 
		"option_d": "Change from measuring GDP at constant market prices to GDP at factor cost", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020135", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17wwPHwIivDF2MFpnKGXLdnMHDtUOfSZ+71iYN5IhyKgklp93XS46r+8kAzgYlI+ouNZCsMcNEv78KGxPe38nBNJsMEu4R24Z5fNNN27XTtdcCbIv99x23AN1f5ZDyuRHln1DjYiXBDu4qt8Ge0Upon0ho2g4Rs5McyfMOewa2AqEy2gkaO2WiCCK12HlCMttqh5E3cs5c6psSJuDfIyPrFlMrW8c0EbAFcuNw/RG2d16kduCg5QsG3KAJZ+OfVchT/JTixIh0Y99/wlmBhw8I/XGUh8V9Bh41TcMFn05ykvitwPsMqHD2+tldU1Y08UAXWZ7i7xGf2rBU2e3kncI5ksip1tQ6ELUc+m2WYDD9ElpNi+tkchkRndH1Fn2Lsm3+ZhWmOaJbnq5Tzxfjir7128bcuJk/CbF5uWmCsjPdIWkAo/2tbwA==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRsXqCQax6eX/kFKbQa63q24J0axyIg1875n7D47f19kAAgaFV7s6WY2IXdo4vy9+bxeH00DFEK9ZIm45z8JMQcrRPyn25fNGbIe19y3yULkr+JYNDSmA1hIpPagJTUP2Ha1E=", 
		"explanation": "25KOSdHgxRjk85ZgVBHghdrtOnjDQ1QQr2qGEoJwdHTnGOfVZuT9wdd4NByIzVZ+82XTsaCw+FVPiqtU54GSeSFDcZ572MWdlXaF7iFNgDU+sAp766O4GJY=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and reasoning are true, and the reasoning is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and reasoning are true, but the reasoning is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reasoning is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020136", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEgz3yfzrPGTeEGoYsz+BV7djdXTtFID0T63/3ddzJk+Ajhtr4H/Fpra8t3Q5ruha/c6ZcSEXcZkvy9+aw6i3xX9Fc+FgqsBz8NoSfeZLySntZMbSI/t9kSw4v1a82ACnz2HytQdAh/b0", 
		"answer": "25KOSdHyxVno9pYpUV7i1/T8MHiQXiI2lV7DU7c0dnDgQKjQLu7x2oMxVByuqWs782KGrqTi/FYbz7hJ4I2aY2Bb2IEbCMtntstCVT9N0Gtp", 
		"explanation": "25KOSdHyxVno9pYpUV7i1/T8MHiQEGcDtXqQEqJnMGXrUefReuzs3Z5/IByZglJ15jqGsaDg5VYciqZP4ICYMDYLe8t5ydyc0qTwwX9EIcdQn4Qy5oNfefdPwjKgfdebJfB6x3qJIlawZTy7C2Jx1DDViXNDppey+yD7UtUlgAEzjoJrrckyOJeMzKqA4UmxgxXC03XRWK9rFUGaod3ozHW94IMs9cuMsibU5rT6levHsN8PaB1Bq5U/ZVSu16EH/CMqVMugKAZK6eHDIRzoOCumNxpd6t7hxX1tz4c6FCkg+19HkJFfdMUz14ykqDo1f8RkFjy3pgRFxoZyWhPWdqT41mnn9FotZjokY8p9riIxtAyIIVtw2ky4fGxQgMBm/8ISkBAjbX1Jn3PzwjaFg2maeJbwq5T9ne3j4LZtsrM1JkWVNkjLFsURbL3VNCdh3+uIBKJVNowuVzbpfccr+jX8I4LUyzEIkNY2KmXm+CbZn8znMmCu84T4gsFzVLAGdtDJ5Yuwv1PDcmPgL3nTdc7mTwHzSm+4wxxqsw0mzSVQ/2vMAIBxtTkFmz61SktqnSr5LtoLyxE7yRZlXILLG1ON0nk=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "GVA at basic prices = GVA at factor cost + GDP at market prices", 
		"option_b": "GVA at basic prices = GVA at factor cost – GDP at market prices", 
		"option_c": "GVA at factor cost = GVA at basic prices + GDP at market prices", 
		"option_d": "GVA at factor cost = GVA at basic prices – GDP at market prices", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020137", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRtH6QEo1bRDHuUanWZ+LwzJMxJk/JjBt4/XvWsaD48l0chr5eqY2QZicRf4xqiNOB1urwwTFIPYZtlIR75d0MPPpB2DSietXXYPdgzWGNIgXxZDqyEX5gnT/R1T7wgi7yyir04t2avjDBKb5F", 
		"answer": "25y2a53mwhDl+cUvVF77y/vwJ2bRF2serT+FQKx5MGXrUefDbe7x3JllNByGixt69WTPoLD840YdjqQb6oGQYCcRf59m3tWalfAOIcsbR/hv8hfAC8lxTAM=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH63xrm4pYpXRCyyvu/PGXWDHAcomuKXa00dmPsWefWZui+yJRyKEmHmUg7/XCGoqLi/lAag7xO+4+TMCEMcZtq2tGd3vLy1zFWMtUElI9mpJcacuBJwzOocJTaM75vjm2PKlXiYjG4CmN9gjSWiXNArZG68iL7V9I2zhI31E1KD6ZzlcaN1j5EzB7QRC4=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Incorporation of annual accounts of companies from the manufacturing sector", 
		"option_b": "Inclusion of information from the accounts of stock brokers and stock exchanges", 
		"option_c": "Comprehensive coverage of activities of local bodies and autonomous institutions", 
		"option_d": "Inclusion of information from the accounts of agricultural cooperatives", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020138", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV1711/LoIWOQEWMFpj+MVONdfnXqVeDRLsra+ddwMxyKglVo5nfIt+Xg5VoMirsb74GNMDYLe8tpwcOK1ui33XRAIYYWytEkqctIMLRB3329ccabNPZrjn6SKFP5Yzy5RHR1gDCJyMDbJkiJpj24+5kokijJLWc=", 
		"answer": "2+LuON+jgVyoYp0D6+K9I+KE+a+Gk85v4Q==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH0wxb9441gQB/mwL3wMyv3J1JRomvDUax6Y2XiWrOCfv/3ypJiZ1WazVh6/nXTr6Tk8ldPjbEb6oGSYCMRd4VoiMSB0qTQ4EEBPMAEjpd9pJkQcudFzyi5fcLeYOdrz3yTawXxYzOoF2RxkHHQhW4WoY29+SavXdU5gCE6n5Q46sEqOcTf2Oie51+9xgeB326DSalhUUSQttq9+Ubcr4R4ocWI8SDe9fi5nerc58oDIgdU/5J3Zhu5lKcH9ychHYi1e1JC5aTCZFniNi2wZxoV/Ivq22RoxZZpUm90/RFAjoJCa8996pbYshs+f9liEHO5oldFh5t6Hz6YcLS5nCjw6FB/Ul4bJY1/szohqU+OKUB72mqIDC9empN//94N1RRxdGxFjzbogyzLgmCKctPn7oPwjOb5rr4j+61nO0SDMFLMFpQZZKHTZ1N6z6mcH6lLJ5cnBSPyOJUn8nmrcMfCkmhakM4hPDfr+z2cgI3hMWS084bxi5RxBrAXItmF+8qjtRzIZ2O2dzjTb8W0C1ihGjGphU5RvxE2iCUV627RBow//D5Nn2qkW01mhzPlaDy1mf5dqoybcow0wbXj23IWmfdskInkmF01SQe3mHtKvIPfW1RKjV3bDswE0EkhCvQFEZve/GiCnGXRX3UCcY73D6zH1yRNmvD9gXZ5sIcAFYWAbA3Tj54hxBizAPE5UGTipon0JL5nNERAdzZK8osta3YqzQbR", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "760.00%", 
		"option_b": "710.00%", 
		"option_c": "1190.00%", 
		"option_d": "560.00%", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020139", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrl+pUvXBv80b3wMyvEC2dRrX6XW6x6cX2jXanBYeD7iZ5iZ1mamVJ282LDp+Xk+BMNiuhp+s7OIXNWLctjyduBl+fly2NEc8BLiMBm7J9fev1TzzyhNM3eIewunD7RcQihMGb/zRxL3Tu2LkXLdvFA0BWIFg==", 
		"answer": "25KOSdHyxVno9pYpUV7xyvPsIWreFyIBsXaAV7A2ImVTm6yNBCDF7ubhTrM+9A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHU5ziq/pZgRhb3henwIWrcQ3QQr2qGEqxyMHbsW6PRLuzwzddiIk6fhFh+4TbWsar04lAKi+hS586efmIGfYRhx92Qm6T6zX9UIIZQkoUy8psTafEAwzvtfdrPJexjy2qJJlH1JzCzFGVgh3HDmXlS6Iq1tTOzUdMlgAUgmYNt7tw1M9nf8LzT4V74h0aP2XqCXa9hUVuf9dqg7gOMso08oM6ZuCTS4O25lf6T8dBLZwtdsYlyemeyq6Y98C94dv6VKBNfsebRcl3uYDixLg0Y6ovqxTRqx44qSGU14BpCwoFPIsF30pHqu3IlL41+HTb6tUVM0pE8UBHWe6iswH3woFMtendrZIZh/Dk9pE+YIVJ4n3mZQjgRh4Vo6t8LhkRsey9UlHOghzyEjmqCZd+j+JX/jajxs/li9bEuKlSMIUnKU8FcaLLOMmFzyf2OH69SNNMnBCf0K9wt+Sq1YJOA3HkkxJkpPDfmtCeWgMi1Omq3o4D8htF4B7YWM5HI7MqkpU7CISznYXiQacX7VAHzD337xwdzvgw8iDUY6WyYHIF6tQoprjLwSFckmzOgaHOkhf5S5ZbOa4861rXl0yYf2PV7nJTi2gl8UwWjiGwDs4qbD09az0ffGsQC1zUgMLo1HJOR1Vu31XfEC34MbMf1QbiVyi9NyaP3gXM9q5gLFYqHPxrahp4/zRajQa8pBDGg+dG5NO9VD3c4879w3uil9960NfGhbFc5L0vmCLoKs5lQYwo7EhnSFyEDIKumWYoXT+cP0zXNhQhfU3cJF1vY/ugHW0T8/IGIYXzbcfEIBhuiRIUkU8j3XAfbPfTp0TXIFP/OxRbrEhVzDjWbYYIepVagLtWjZB+ymGAk+tPqIFRnSr8ZCC/2NGyrqrSXA0YofjggaIVBOlPdTlADoh+DJu0nj6YTeRttUbquGlUF1hhc3zLdGV1X8FgWXqvtVFsiaq5XL0wFxXenELQaHBPMxi4Cixa75hKgaftYcV0rfiS0q3ygj5Ntmuypi4CVBZTjLr4Ux4MXaKJaXJ/FX1oSnrP3+uPzGGgwA343BvffW/TUogO2FsDx4uTs5BxC2v4JdlI0NzzLiJza5ShsO6APYnVLrmYLqYrdZEav2odX2l1hUxXt9lXtV241r10zb4CrY8mcLpSg4xBRGTCHQ7hInbxx0zjrdd7SZxUqCXd1hQ+VZdeKwz2QKaPp1KQGCwue2aXFcYJorE9rwcumywxPrXthh3miLED7Iu7jqEwEcyo1GuPfDVxOxhstwj+jnkfgPIHqk64MzrdT16IH6UzlozVzz1eCDxieMianj6DS92TTqgco3ep0XXXjSGdkwgBkVP84+21nVihhfal9r/b8IrXNnWC7K4/42YQM8RZATqKKBrO/tNTyZabGIKvj1JnDOHPysYB9DfmjZdkXL2HEajpT5L/4YIHNeUmSKCuFkqiUHTyLN2BL73pr2G1taQ5ls09jqRyzHz6F7oA=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "GDP at constant prices", 
		"option_b": "GVA at basic constant prices", 
		"option_c": "PCI at constant prices", 
		"option_d": "GVA at factor cost", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020140", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV1711/LoIWOQEWMFpj+MVONdfnXqVeDRLv3729dyJkyAmVo7+3jFrKj1txs/rIESqY+LMCEMcJh7yd6dl/TlzXJEIIZClZIy8JIaPPJJ3z6seJTCJf98jjzQdhO9Nm7iRscLAqJO0nm7TXOUt1L75Jg=", 
		"answer": "2+DuON+jgVyoT5+YFJ6saxf8hqa1N8YUeA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH0wxb9441gQB/mwL3wMyv5DWYYojiQErNxYjHgVbfLeuy+wJlyKFGMzRNL0V+P46Tkt1AAgbtP6ICLMDIRd4hq25CP2Pa30HlEc8BNiYNz6NoGefVSjG/9JYKWcaku2W+TZxK1WzeBCkR8nSKWg28WqYC4+jW/XdQwgAE91pNw6IgsLtiJ0Lua50O5ikaHz2+YRbxwFEfZusjo6k2StYM09cOMpTvU+vX12vHd89EGZ0QS7dYuNRbtwOgb/SY9UNuxbFJJ6KTEaVGtEDqmNB1d0MXl2WZkx5YgUmd01gpUh4JDIvR709j0uSBwPMx6HCe7401OxJtxWlefev2q1WnooEE6Z3c4JcJsqG1n8V7NZQUs2nuORS9Uh8kr+N8L1RBreC9ZmXfywm3b0TPCLcSj4pO8gPvkqbRi5qYjaVWPdV3MQowVa/PBZ2t33OyXTalac8c1W3CwZJUv73n6L5uE3isI1Jk0ICCwuHLJwY3zNnf6p5r8zs1zFa1AZIGUvIbm5mDJXS3VKXjTYdn7Thz4D275xwsluB5l+AI5qGPMSIpw+z4Zn3CkCVR2myTlfzyohf5f646NaoIwx/DonTAJ2Pd3kov2xhQyQESvhXoDgqe2D1NJjUDBEY0Eywc9CbcUAJ/H9y2PkHfCWDBNfsr8FLuTxigI3OzjzmhzuZwPQYWBIlnvgtc1iBC4F/hqFWatpYnrOLwUCWc56LNlz62xvsmvYOGhbGosLw6/XK9L9pRdKAVpHhzJDWRGbvi6XpheUvRO3HHLhQMISHkJCVPa8qYPHQus6tDAayrOZr4MAhuuI7IWU8fsDlXKOP6/zSOJEreZ1U6zT0UmWnqSJ/AE6wH8e5j7Kx3xsogYCiCE4SKSOupC+sxm6Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "620.00%", 
		"option_b": "560.00%", 
		"option_c": "1040.00%", 
		"option_d": "740.00%", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020141", 
		"question": "25y2KIX71Fns+JctRxLzhcG9G2rECm0fonPDe613f3zmFKbWLsv/yoN+NRyqgkhvsiuGjYvAt1Ibz4Va+4WaZGIgcZh7iKPJ/urzzWNEMNIEroFq4YlfN7Rz2T++fdDSJe0i8izAME35ZDH9B395hD7Yj3JCu8O65yL7Vd4zxRFyl4l8rdspPsON2KuH7Un4gBSN0Tu/Zo0kEEDZmM+64EaI4KE3ptnS85zG4guUIldk8WCZs1WslHs=", 
		"answer": "25y2bJjh1Br+t7EhShvhhfzxMSvjFmACqnuKV7A2qUJIE9qaReJPzKffZrhmGw==", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJjh1Br+t5EhShvhhfztMCvDFmAFsX6ARqZwMHfxW6qCQMPOiZZlZ3GIn1B+5jblrLbkt1EKjKlO+ovfZCoGZ8tu2tXJ2evjhGFAOsIEmJky8JIaPPJBzymiZsebL/gu3nyPI1DzczCyCjBAnDTPyn1ErcOr9C6/FNgugBY9mJRt4M0uL5eQy+iR/V6xiAORz36CCKlrUUCRsI6v5FWZsow1sMOZjTzo4fbqk/za9c1LYxpX/4d7Z16417wGuAQWYYi1fFJm8PbbZECtAyewM04f/Mjiw2dshpYhWHB09Q1DwpNXa8Qz1IGkqDo1f8plAzaorUlFyYA8SxjWYLW9kG7l40EwZ2lraowtrD86pRqfPF1xlCuoRClI1IF5+5AQmxBmc2tFmDb0jX+ZhWGaf5aj/4j5xev/s60j/aVnOVOPMUnbQoQTa/PBKWMyz+eYArNOMphiVyflMtsh8TD6YJeXyzAb2c05bUt0C263tI9jq6v2XhDSrhI=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Indirect Taxes and Direct Taxes", 
		"option_b": "Subsidies and Direct Taxes", 
		"option_c": "Indirect Taxes and Subsidies", 
		"option_d": "Corporate Income Tax and Subsidies", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020142", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg7n1+3wJm6QDGRRsXqVW7B9fnajQK/HLu//2pIxPlmInxt09DbDoKr++F4GjOhS54qWcycQMstu25Cb0uf4yXxEPcJBnsBw/doLdPEA4jy5fdvVIfIu/XqBM0zjczC+BXw0tz7bh3VFu4q0+3j5x9g7FQCOG/ZpCHuwxuRCmw==", 
		"answer": "24G3KIP21xXv9JFgURbzy/r6JivZDSIFq3rDQbdmZXL3QbXHLuL4iYN5IhyMjlR1/Xvf4XHTREEsiu4QWILtZNUfkJ4=", 
		"explanation": "25a5eIXmwxyq5JEyRx3m0O/+OSvTC2MfpHqQEqp6MGXrUefHbeLwxppoZ32azU9z9zbDoKr++F4Wz6tT6ICYdTFPPp9nzZCK2Onny2JIJ89LlMB94toYc/tE332setCbM/t82GeDIlawdyuyAGV3kTWaymhercOp8Cu6QNMhxVU7m5d3/9w9MtSamaeVqEmxgACHzn6fXP13FFeNuty7pwOdroZ4ocWI8SLJ/ff8ibjc9p4MbQdWrMZ+bV/8hK0b7iM7VNv0axpK/+PVIVX+YD+mKwJdzcPmlnZo1YdpRGw15l9VioxDbsQz1J2krjcmNt5vEXOurARSwpJwWhSCNKmw1XvhoFY3dHQsYJkttSN1rh2YLUY+jmTcSSJCgZJuvsQRlBAjaWdF3H/uhjaIhXbPfYHmq4G8hOvztati5qZnJESBJknKU80TY/PFJGh8xeSSDuZdMItuASvyJOkgwDfQLYaG0C8IkM0oKjfm9ymMgMz2ICW1tdLthtE2HbEEP9LA+ouYplnVITfoLHjfJt/8XEjnSnX/2xp29w02zSVQ/G2YC4hz9jgBn2q1CVBsl2fpYniolbtPqo+PZs4z1vbj0DdQl+Fsm5rj0RlwBwi+jHtKvIPfW1MPxFrXHc4S1ggtBbESVKTU5GSFnHjXC2gFeo70ALuCgzVN2/Gxj21xsIcdFYqBPlnPgttm3xK4BvVtRif5p8b7OLwAGmAt7rd1hq22v8O4fbOnLWtqZhenS+BP9tVFYAc7EAjeEDZOY6HuWZteVehKknzEkw5LQmx1C2bC1qkDWES+osGIZ2TaarIZHV7vbKEAU833Q1fOJ/CrxDWJCamZhweqVkkgDg2VJL5N8Q/1Oo7zNxbzim1l64HsIRFJQZUeLyL3OCutrabDAgg+di8gO8pGaEKVWRVplz/PJOxrjLMFdFg4UqGpHhACnhQPkTvFTk9AuUsWS7btdFsuOelIIVAU3nehGaVfVRLOjzkPnRaRzTDpaflEPFkiaWWRg0mglIRjjb/9i4OERpTjPv0P2ogaaLdJQdrYEE9cm/Xi6uL0FGh5BHQ3LfDJUOXUow//DIjgqsaa0llCzrYcJR1aKleeLRfDz3vreTMLh65h", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "To update the tax rates for better accuracy", 
		"option_b": "To reflect changes in the structure of the economy", 
		"option_c": "To increase government revenue", 
		"option_d": "To adjust for inflation rates", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020143", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEhPzzPO/J2rECm0fonOGEqV7YjHiUKPLYOq+2oJzNFWNhF5osmLJ47H48hMBjrxS5oCefGIKcIhgxdXJ1vC3yXBTOMNQ2oN9945fdfoA5TOpfdWEYvCdX8kaE8KXzJYkNq72pbs=", 
		"answer": "24G3KJDl3hDut4EpQQr91+n2OmWQCmxRt3eGErV1fGTmFKjELv7ry4R4I1WTiF879XnJp7aw9l0Lz7te+5iWcycQPN7bvzOqGQiHlSnfGprp6V8=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+0BDkt5chRhf9y/zzMCvWDHBRonuHW61zMGL2VrTLauT72tdlKBydhV47/HfSqqr+9l9PhqZY5oOaMCMXPoZu2tuMw6T0y2JVc89K2ql84JMePP1TjCmiNMbeJvJrzXrAM031Jy2vEXU0gjDan3kWp4X78ii0UMl3wRs21pR9/941P9KMmbiB50mthQOGnHKfCKlsFBSctsGm5E6F4LEtt96EtTve57T4iP2T4N8Sbw1cq5U/blq4kugL4WosWc30bx1d9PbebFHjNGi3KE4N68Tnw3ds1JFpSWZ05hpCl4BTItR709jnsyEkf8JsVSOorEBVxIB1UBnWVqT40Wzg6Vs4NWk+Z5lkuCQwsk+IJxRqkm7cQi1FnY9l/9xZnApgcmJF0Db3h3+KkmDPeZXl7oPojP71rKAj5qIsIE+HdVXWQoJcZLDDKHJ83qmPBaMcNZ5kA2LyNdQ6vC3xJdaEzTYJxdolPWSn9Tic0t/wOmCzpZv3iZR3VLMPIdTXqduluV/CISXuMz2Hbs79S0j3QHP8wE5kuRxl2yQC/mvbDZoztToFl324CUlhkynzLGipl6oc/oqLP5gw3+DpnT0W2OBwmtvw2xI4VES6g3sDoYGNWVVMyEeWF95HyAY5CaZD5q6yTdU46Ye8TZE2Y4gdCg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "To avoid distortion in the value of subsidized goods and services", 
		"option_b": "To increase government revenue", 
		"option_c": "To encourage higher consumption", 
		"option_d": "To align with international accounting standards", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020144", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrv9JEvQFnhhfjsIWLdAnYUsD+MVONTYn7wR+f0b+HrzNdQI1iMiRsz1UDn6uXx5VZPn7pU/4ebdSZDf58vytGa3ue31GNIMMNX2oFx55UNeP1Oy325e5TPKPsu3GuWLlb1Y3mwAWR8mzXZhnNRsdz5XFnzMfzFWuXFE8ykdrY6VA==", 
		"answer": "25i5ZoT10Br+4pcpXBmy1vj8IWTCQZJlJ7hRtkBb+9ftOrDVNqs=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH2wg3j+oQ0Vw2yyvu/EnnfEHFRlX6PR6Y0UXXnUaOCJsrI6N4xJkjJj1po+3WGs7f59FYcz6lJ7M6PYi0Vd49qzJCP2Pa3xX1Nc9VBmZR99olfc/IA2DWoNNHYL/Bhw3fAJkbzaCu5DX5z1CXZymhercOp8DGyR98zgBg3go936ccwM9CGmZyb4V74jxXC3TuSQLxqFlHZs9yn5gOIqId4pd+IpzvU4ee5l/3H+NEPbQRduJ8zI0y0nqsBuCU2XdH0eABE5+3UZFCtBx6CZw8JucnixX1qhpI7VGox519AjZEWdsh2lpnjrjszKsF+ACG7rwRTwpdoUAXWQLW9kHrh9lwscH5raI95tCIxrgOTL00+k3jcRSIRmIll+5AOnBBrPWZOiHPyjD6fiWqBfZ+j+5L9hvz5o7wj860jaVGSOkrRUogPJbKAKmhgz6maDqVJIZ5zEmLrONQ96Sv8YJmSny0F1Zk2Lnvy8WqWlI36LHGqpoa5nsZ5EKoDM9WF4MX3pFTCISbiLnOca9K2ebwRowk7V51Oz5H9oMvF9Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Financial sector", 
		"option_b": "Manufacturing sector", 
		"option_c": "Agricultural sector", 
		"option_d": "Services sector", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020145", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg7gzPD+J3KQB2sXpXqRV613dTHhUbPVa+jwibBVFxyImRt4/XjVt6T+4xMCjrpQ7JrfYDAKfY58iNGH06TQ4EEBMtIEnIFx8JUNPPdP3ynyNuqo3r24G6RYWQ0J0HtGVMY=", 
		"answer": "25KcWNHyxVns9oY0XQyyxvLsISvUDGcC43GMRuN9fnLvQaPHLuTwzZ5jIl+dzU966nPV46T+8xMcmqpI4IqWdTFBhMOQSeHkCmMqFGP1TzZJyQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxDn9pc5Ehr7w/v6J27eAGdRoXqXRaZxfjHEcJeCb/m+yph/NEiIg087/3fUqKDkt0Mdhqte+s6efiZDWa9fiNGdl+L2x2VOIYZHlZNmpJMMPOBIzSntU/DrYP96jm2PKVbkZjepRH11hjrTnjxGuoq48DT7XdQ0zAA2k5Q45MY4NcWa2rzT/EyggxXOnGyZQbFhUXO9hY6p/wOaoYEsut/Nsj3I4LT9lf3AsNAEdkh7sYJ2cV6/g+gd+TI9Qoi1ehcL5eXIZEetNCCiM04c686j2nF/z4ctHWY6tBhJjYdFIsF90tj3uSAmNs5vBn/6sFFDz9R9TFeFdbG9wyjw4U1/dHQvJY91vyQmpE+YPUBn2l+USTURlZJuvt4WgURzfGZE3HT5wiuDhSWJfZD35JLvxef24Klx/acyKlWJOlKUFo8JcfPCPidmwuzbDqlSIIpqEjD1fdo8vDvsM5+a2ioe1cpgO3/m4GqJh9/2MWSpttLthtE2E7APMsKF6MWz8E/CczXoIniAJuzQaUjxWzz+0g1xuAplyy4D/CLRG8l+tSACjHvwSEdnhzXheHnhm7td+Zeces4+1bX41TdQkfp7kJbylBg9VQq+iT9Bq8SLR1kPy1XVCsIV10khCvQRBpnV526CnHneC34IfM/jEq3HyjgI3/vygnR5uoNOXIKKJQveicpm3BapBO47DSkn8iBKJ0t8zwoZ6zAAbA==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "GDP at constant market prices includes indirect taxes and subsidies", 
		"option_b": "GDP at factor cost includes direct taxes and subsidies", 
		"option_c": "GDP at factor cost does not include indirect taxes and subsidies", 
		"option_d": "GDP at constant market prices does not account for inflation", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020146", 
		"question": "25y2KIX71Fns+JctRxLzhfvwJyvTAm4StnOCRqp6dzHNVbPLYeP/xddYKV+GgF4782KGhaTz41wdz4tU+prTMDYLe8tmxtSAxeH00DFVMt5BicB84Z8bPOBPjD+oNOvkH8FR8VG/GHrPWAaCRHZmmzyWnnRT6K2VxWe6QJoawQc5k5M4zscvKJVdcRXrZEazQEF/TyzSDExY", 
		"answer": "27G9bITwxRzutazB9yhrPKkPmftK2//fDsI=", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71Fns+JctRxLzhfvwJyvTAm4StnOCRqp6dzHNVbPLYeP/xddYKV+GgF4782KGhaTz41wdz4tU+prTMDYLe8tmxtSAxeH00DFVMt5BicB84Z8bPOBPjD+oNMfOIup8z22UIkGwYSuyCTBgnDSWpFJm6IKvtQq6RtEy1FURmZRsrfw0NcTf0LvT6ki7hxOR2TuYRrltA1GaoY686luZs8I5p8jNvz3PtOT4k/yT8sdLdgBX/4B+YE+zhbtJ9yx4Qdq7bAdI5e3fbxitIj23ZwwEud/r0zRqyYw6SGQx5gwGjZEWYNVg35bhryE1LI1+HTKu41RV1Zd0XgSTNKmw1Sjj71o7Zjoqa44trygntwafLUc+uHLcXzlTgJJq/cQQmwMjdGFElWTlgSvLlGSXeYCj7ZLziKjkqLwj3I0XaUCUdXHZRIYZcfPjKHRmhqmMCOZdIZonEiTgONY69S/8LI/UyzgG2dcnb37p4CXZk872NnC0p9LthtE2Er4DIpHR4cqj8EjPZGPnIH6HadnnGQf2D2zq3ApwtAwsxy9Q6XDdSIdw4W0fm321QFJtnCCgeHSk1rhJ5o7OfoM+xvv4nT0W2OBwmtvnxhQ/QkS0iz9XuoHfSFNAyUeWH8MDhBorHqIIF5PCsnmekG+QW24Ce9v1BOqZBO/iszTV+DxnLBFmczF3", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "de,duc,ted", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020147", 
		"question": "24GwbdHh1A/j5IAkEhP30fXwMWTcDGUI43mMQON3cX3gQavDeuTwztdfJkiAglV6/jbnoKb/4l0bnOhS5862fiYKf8cvycPJx+HlhGVJNoZ3g5Nm4Zdfc/IA4jy5fdvVIfIu722DKFD+cyr9TENatXib2CwG8M/7/Cm4WM8zxQZyn4po/8cqOdPf2qeF7V+5gQPC033RSb5wGEKQocet+AOTpsIHivKyjg3ky8vGpcfsz54CbBtGtpJqd1KzmbtLHqjme7dXpwPLEcEL26sjGA==", 
		"answer": "27m3a5D/kRvl84wlQVxJfuZQC38CXHFjfZPgmspr", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHh1A/j5IAkEhP30fXwMWTcDGUI43mMQON3cX3gQavDeuTwztdfJkiAglV6/jbnoKb/4l0bnOhS5862fiYKf8cvycPJx+HlhGVJNoZ3g5Nm4Zdfc/IA4jy5fdvVIfIu722DKFD+cyr9TENatXib2CwG8M/7/Cm4WM8zxQZyn4po/8cqOdPf2qeF7V+5gQPC033RSb5wGEKQocet+AOTpsI+vMOMvzHS9fi5k/bA5NcfdxxbsIhsI2+0nrtJ8Tl4UIi3YBNF9uGQZ0biLWi3Lwtd6dnmwH1m05FpUGwg/BBCjY9ZZdk/lo/stTE4f8ljEXO0rFAAzpp/UwKScf2+2Wbl7lY2dHZrbIR+qCQhtBuVJ1pt2mKSDDhZkcBo/9wagAhiaWZPkjbvhH+FgXGGc53i58D9huv/tbd34eMTIUTAJ1nOX54ZYfPNInN6xe2UAalbKt9uBGLvM5Ui9Tf8YIGdyzFN2dc0KmXp9T6QncP0NSWqoZP6mt11Ef8BONWF+dm4plXDZDChID2eadnxGQnzTGnq0hpg9xUgyTIF+meYB48/4SUI3nuzRkprny7jLH2igrdK45aXP4c/k+Hk2HITl+F2i4nulj9kHVJqElDqlgbEd84KUmM=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "lo,ca,l b,odi,es", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020148", 
		"question": "24GwbdH0wxb9441gQB/mwL3wMyv5DWYYojiQEpNxYjHAVbfLeuy+4JlyKFGMzRNL0V+P46Tkt1AAgbtP6ICLMDIRd4hq25CP2Pa30HlEc8BNiYNz6NoGefVSjG/9JYKWcaku2W+TZ3rPWAaCO09Lqw7ptUNp6JO+5yS+Ws51gYnmxEHxt3290n56dOGn9Q==", 
		"answer": "24a9fpT9k4qZpsAH/7sGzaF6FvKHNPs=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH0wxb9441gQB/mwL3wMyv5DWYYojiQEpNxYjHAVbfLeuy+4JlyKFGMzRNL0V+P46Tkt1AAgbtP6ICLMDIRd4hq25CP2Pa30HlEc8BNiYNz6NoGefVSjG/9JYKWcaku2W+TZxK1Jw21DWM0nSKWi39Vp5G//Cm8FM44gAE6k8do/8cqNcSW1qaS5A29lRKL0XqFTa4kHlLZtMCm/kKQ4Iw5ocSCvzPXtP33mffe9ZJLMFgD6csuNBuukqQM+Tk9VYi2cVJf+eGQUUboMzvjDgAb9tnu12BgyYxpf3wm8R5TwrdeZ4Bj04qkvzMgNtlrVTq0oEtNwtR1UVeEcby0kHzh8lgsNTIqcco/7Hxk7F7OaERsk2iZX2URko95vsQRkER6eG5S3CSw02nG0TLPdYCj7pPojOXxtLxnsrcoaUCUIV3RWM0dJb/FMWJ+iuadTf4Of80xTmLnLpUt8zTpIYSR23kZ3453Yy+3p2qfnd+1LW2/84v8j8Y2Ru9RY5yUv4lUGFA8mcXeEizaxNJ0K8oN", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "sev,en,mo", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020149", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUFURH8yvD2NivzDG8BrHGGXLdnMGbqQK+CSujtyoV4N0iAglVosI/ADufceSlVR/3AjQz6cAI=", 
		"answer": "25KOSdHyxVno9pYpUV7i1/T8MHiQTiI8pn6QR7FxdDHhTeflSt2+yIMxJFOHnk96/GKGrqTi/FYbz7hJ4I2aY2ICcI8vzciK2/HzzX9Gc89Knolg4ZkLPOBB1Di+NNXVJL5922yTLkH5YirxRFdQpHHXnjxVp42o4Sa1QJo6wQc5k5M4/do1P9KMmeXTzEiqjxCH2DuXWrJpUXOvlI6p/wOeoZExto2dozvY8ee5mOGT48sJdhpTvJJ2bVz8h7oG/D87RcG7ZlJf8PzVchTsLizjNBsf6sLn33F6isIOa0h09QsGhIJVds9hlpvrryZwco1PBiezrkVUwpA8XQ7Wdbm82WbjoEYqd2kiYYNor20hrk+7HnU+m3/cTi1CnYMr7sIQlgFwMS9unWLpjTGKjCWmcpDs5oW8hPywhrhg5qw1aWKPJkiYG80obbaAIW58y+XbH6NPJpNzVy3gfdEr+Cz6NJ+a2HkE3t0pPXLk4GqNk9XwKiW7vZa5j9ByHbEHdsLQ69i+tFXCcmP1Lj29SPu0WBywYn3q2Atx9zsq2zVSRSUv0viPFB8qBSbv1ULpkQ==", 
		"explanation": "25KOSdHyxVno9pYpUV7i1/T8MHiQEWcBsXqQV61gYzH3XKKCeOzy3JIxKFrJgk5v4mPS46L1+VYdjrxe7c6IeTYLd4Uv3NiMl+H0y39OPt8I2oVq55YKeP1Oy329ZtvfNf16x2GOZ1HxfzyuRHF6kHHXjnhfpoT75jK5R9MzyRAh1rNw6Ig4OcScy6GD/ES3iEajnH2YXK4kBVyQpo6r5E6Mr4w9u9nNjTzn+tPdqrjS5J4IbQZBq4dxdxuxlroC/T54Qdq9axdYsenVYEf4Mi2wZxoV/Iv32WBoysI/XGUh8V9JhMNRbc93xdjlsjZwLMh4Azq5plcA14ZzWwKVcbn4x2Hw6FwxNW4jYMpovyI7rgKFZBR/nmGJXzhUkMBt8cJZnAplcW5UlXnuzn+KjmHPeYvg55X4jOb34LBt9qo1LEKUdUjZTogPJbLOIydh3+uIBKJVNownIyrjfdEr7zrrKYaA1jYDkPtgLnvu8ySK0tr8LW36p5rwnZR1G7IQOd/A59/3jFL7bwTXAD2ScovyWAvkQG640AF2o1g3zScV+nGYHIY/4SUI3mixRVFh0ijmLHO0gq5J/sKebYE1xvbp2XIdkfptjNvnxhI4UgevhHBN8pCeV1lcjVXYGo0GwA0nArNBB4PT4WSSnHPDC1gIbM3kCLiTyiNGmsCxg2BpvJgLRsyaJBDIytslxxm+DPR6FWTipZb2M/kbHlgixrwx5Oy1vsW1dP/kBWspYBeyGe5Ns7NQaxZ0A0v+CjdbILG9FpkbU+lZ13GKlR4IVGpLEUjN+LwBUwPqo8rMZ3jbYKVcGh/6ZqBFEsD8DkbLMfinz3DaE72PnEO3WldlWjXdD7UZpSnxboX9KhK/01h29sXwMUUbDK05DG6zdX/5iKKRAAMuPw8qO54HXkLGSAIthCrKKPcnqecJY1gsUruoGlkXghRL3ynbGlAFpEQXTOWuT143JadALk9TzV8Ofq1mJfMKGXO1jW8Djg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "GVA at basic prices - Measured by GDP at constant market prices and excluding indirect taxes and subsidies", 
		"option_b": "National Income at Factor Cost,The final result of deducting indirect taxes and adding subsidies to NNP at Market Cost", 
		"option_c": "GDP at constant market prices,Derived from GVA at basic prices by subtracting production taxes and subsidies", 
		"option_d": "GVA at factor cost,Estimated by adding subsidies to GVA at basic prices", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020150", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUDWh/8wvjsdWLeQ0wQt3aMXKJ4MFjtV6jPa63fypR+MlKdhFV8smHPt62w3l4fg6FY6JqWfywQPCSkIJ28q5KGqOmYc+pRl0o=", 
		"answer": "25e5e5Sz6Bzr5cUSVwj71vTwOyudQ1AUpXOGUbdnMHLrVanFa/6+wJkxM1SMzV54/XjJrry35BMcm7pO6pqKYidDf4VriNmH0ej20HhOPYoEuY9/9IgadPFO3zS7cZT4L+hr3G+HIgX/YXmbDX51mjLfi3AWm4a44SipFJd35Rs6l4l76Mx8ONaL2OiV+kK1xhWW03iaCL92Hl+cp93kq0aEo4o5u8qIon6b9fr92urW98sHYxxdrZ8/YVS4nq0atGoRX8u7egJE4+XEaFvjYCelZy8T997i2jRKyY85XGcttD5FgYxDbNRgltWklT8gLcJ8EDf6okdDyIFySx6Yc/2+33qk7loxOHcqa59rvS4htB2VJlM+m2iIRTpYgIlu7ZAWk0RgcmJQnXjphyzJBepdlu8jo7m/luuy5KEKvQ==", 
		"explanation": "25e5e5Sz6Bzr5cUSVwj71vTwOyvRBWQUoGuQEqt7ZzHmV6jMYeD3ytd1JkiIzVJosnfIoqnp7VYLz6dN7JzfZCsOe8tG3JCI2+j402IBNclW2oFx548NfeBFjD6iecTaMvd9wWDAJVywZj23EWNgnT/RynpZusO4/Sa1U98kgBw81o5268Q9KN6Q1+iS5kn4kg6HnH6SR7NrHE3epo67/1GJo5Ytp8jB8SbT4ee5m/zX4tsYcQFcuMZra178nqUZ9CM7UNy9ZxxYsenVb0DkLyamI04U94vBlkhn+owKUmQk5hpOh41Fa9Z2lrvrqjciPspvVTy842JJyZVyXB6XeP2L1Wvw70d/fHc7aYNor20hqQrcIVp9lXmMQz5QgIlk8JAWk0RnfHtB3HDyjTLLk3GAf5ij6ZLzju3is/Uj97skIUCOMlnLGs0da7eANWJ13+WaGalOKt9lGCbvOMZivC7xKZWcnzUI0d0zb2PotCeWgMi1OGa5poD4mtE2BroQJNTW7MWjsUjObi2hLnvTY8j7Vwf9Rn+40g1xvg4s3CgV+y6YCZo/5jkMinu0CU1q0gSgUHKdmJdS6Y2cb4Ej0uHl0jxQl/I4vpX5wRwwBye0gG9CvJ3fbl9MwkHYCt5HzQQ+HrsXEYWR826VmmPeX3UDeI7wDrrHzSNGl+7wgHR7vpMaQJ6HIh6bi90ywQG4FfR8Rifirsb6MvEFC2ol/6E9iu6gp96uZ/qqKyUrLxe4S+oZ+5pdYRFvGAidEy1Kd/ihUN0KSeVGwDXPlAhGSHJABhrP9KYcTw2ov9DBYWTNL/EdHV7rbbcMEM/sS0OPPP/p6XD1CIOStEO0SlcxQz+TNfAL6hWwSZnwNxq3mm13ucTrIURJQZBXKC/yYCutrabDHQc2ai0xIYVJOkjTCxcrmzrQZ/hpiecTdQo7SKuiChAfmBJDijrXHRhRuEkXTeWsQ0cyK6UFNlod2DL5UaEcXxPfiC4DgFHcxC3+aeleM1oqf22WnAzUk5t13/7li4mPGZT1JKkTkpkLLfZSSYraFlgdjvrr4aHtFGItD2J5K/yIV+yRlA1NA6SOcmWuBwiXf08Qt2m4", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Base Year Revision,Reflects changes in the economy's structure and inflation", 
		"option_b": "Comprehensive Coverage of Financial Sector,Enhanced data from stock brokers, exchanges, and regulatory bodies", 
		"option_c": "Incorporation of Annual Company Accounts,Improved accounting for non-manufacturing activities of companies", 
		"option_d": "Adjustment for Subsidies,Ensures accurate valuation of subsidized goods and services in the national income", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020151", 
		"question": "25u9fNHd0A3j+IshXl7by/7wOG6QCnFR6y7aC/Q9MlfcJLduN9b/lyTIc/qe72k=", 
		"answer": "25u9fNHd0A3j+IshXl7C1/L7IGjEQ2MF43mCUbd7YjHgW7TWLBfmmmGZogPV1NHVyjIhL9w=", 
		"explanation": "25u5fJj83xjmt6wuURH/wL32JivEC2dRrnCNV7o0ZnDvQaKCYeu+yJt9Z1qAg1p3snHJrKHjt1IBi+hI7JyJeSEGbct/2t+NwufywDFIPYZFlMB355URc/lZjDm4Zt3VJ75vjmiJKUT+ZDC8CDBtkTDEyl1C6Jez8Ge3UcwyzFU9kMd544g5P9iR1qWKpA2uhwqX2TueTv1iGFqYuY6v5EyYs8I5u8nNojfJ4v36n+uT+c1LZxlHvoo/d1T8g6AMuD43Rcm4KBtF8uvdZBTiJmiiKwJd/8rgwnt71cImWykk5hBCl4BCa899lo7tpnI8Ps9lACH240dB151oXhvaNLG53myk4Vs7NX8lcZhorD8wrwqJOkd2k3ve0s9/yxUSYVlx/PxKGfyMbw==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Net National Product at market price", 
		"option_b": "Net National Product at factor cost", 
		"option_c": "Net Domestic Product at market price", 
		"option_d": "Net Domestic Product at factor cost", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020152", 
		"question": "24GwbdH+3gr+t4QwQgz91e/2NH/VQ28UomyWQKY0f3ejUaTNYOLzwJQxIE6Gmk9zsn/V46zk5AlPx/oLudnWMnSOfbeUYdWDNvWOYa5S+4U=", 
		"answer": "24W9etHQ0Anj44RgYBvzyb3WO2jfDmdTGJu792WkbdUXpeI5URc4Lg==", 
		"explanation": "24W9etHw0Anj44RgQBvzyb32O2jfDmdRqmzDXKxgeHjtU+fAe/m+57lBZ12dzV168WLJseXz+EAbz4FPqYOacSwQPoVu3NmG2eX7hHhPMMlJn8B799oMafkA2DK5ddibL/guz2KMZ0PxZC2yFjB9mjLZh3lF6IK//zKoQN8zgBM9hMdx48suOdaM3Oia5g2olA+B2WjTCPl5miTT2VodcKPWp67x0w==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Gross Domestic Product of a country’s", 
		"option_b": "Net National Product", 
		"option_c": "Net Domestic Product", 
		"option_d": "Per Capita Real Income", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020153", 
		"question": "24GwbdHn1Avnt6shRhf9y/zzdULeAG0cpj+RV7NmdWLmWrPRNK22m8chdhXL5w3u2zMSJwra9Q0+nU2Tvw==", 
		"answer": "27KqZ4LgkRfr44wvXB/+he3tOm/FAHZRomvDX6Jme3T3FLfQZ+772td8LlKcnht/92bUpqb59kcGgKYb6ICbMCsNeoJ9zdOdl/D23HRSc9ZIj5My948db/1ExTi+NiLFyNYZTJTNNFXJqiEr9Wc=", 
		"explanation": "27KqZ4LgkRfr44wvXB/+he3tOm/FAHZRomvDX6Jme3T3FLfQZ+772td8LlKcnht/92bUpqb59kcGgKYb6ICbMCsNeoJ9zdOdl/D23HRSc9ZIj5My948db/1ExTi+NiLFyNYZTJTNNFXJqiEr9Wc=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "gross national product at market prices minus depreciation", 
		"option_b": "gross national product at market prices minus depreciation plus net factor income from abroad", 
		"option_c": "gross national product at market prices minus depreciation and indirect taxes plus subsidies", 
		"option_d": "gross national product at market prices minus net factor income from abroad", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020154", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbk8sUvVF7mzfi/M2TcD20GqnGEEqpnMGXrUefBYf/szJRlZ0+MnE5+/HXD46z+t0cHiuhf7I2NdSMQd4VoiN+b0+HlhH5Hc8VLlJRg7ZgKaP1Pwn2icpTfKfhoy3yFKVGwdDy+EH9mh3HChTxCoIb70jW0R8l35Bo/k5Rs5Mt8DMWQ3b2Q/A23gEar0n+YSeIkWQbJ5ZnhqaJa9mya3mhbxJ2euzkY+iM=", 
		"answer": "24a9eof60hz5t8hgexD20O7rJ3KQTiIwpG2KUbZ4ZGTxUeVjoflFWzJxSZJUcy5Ap4C9", 
		"explanation": "25a3ZoXh2Bv/44wvXF79w737PG3WBnAUrWvDQaZ3ZH7xR+fWYa3wyIN4KFKIgRty/HXJrqCwxFYdmaFY7J3fPWJWK9oqhJCg2eDi12VTKosEyNYmodZfXfNSxT64eMDOMvsugz/YcgCyHVEdRmFOh/dgJwBSoEn7QQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Services - Industry - Agriculture", 
		"option_b": "Services - Agriculture - Industry", 
		"option_c": "Industry - Services - Agriculture", 
		"option_d": "Industry - Agriculture - Services", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020155", 
		"question": "24KxfJmzwxzs8pclXB33henwTCv5DWYYonHDV6B7fn7uTeuCbeLw2p51Ik7JmVN+snDJr6n/4FoBiOhI/Y+LdS8GcJ98kuyHhqTDzHQBFNRLiZMywJUSeedUxT7tRMbUJOtt2i7IAGHALnm1BWM0nT/VmHlXu4a/tSWiFNw41Qdygo516Nt8NdnfzaCWqEG5lRLCjSvRUbhlA0elu5zo30uZ4JI9p86Ivyba8/G5ifDS4ttLbQ4Sr5N9b1K/17sM+z43Q4i9ZlJs1dSQaVX+YCymJAIU987nln1nhpYhWCk49QxSwtIGItl214r3gDwHN8RpHXO1pQRUz5E8TAOXYLi11WbwoFI2Y38lJYtvszsw4QaPZ1VsnyufQz5DkYN/oZBRx1QyLSYC9YIJo9Ajxk8nru1s3HSkuw==", 
		"answer": "2+f4R5//yFt67jgE+j2Q8dgQ6CQ8/0wB", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHj1Avp8os0Uxn3he73NHnVQ20X42+WUK99czHwUaTWYf++wJkxAHi5zVN64TbCpqb8/l0Ki+hS586LeCdDcop83JDYh6TuwXBTIIQT4OOhiUna8dxUMNGGrzQn", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 Only", 
		"option_b": "2 Only", 
		"option_c": "Both 1 and 2", 
		"option_d": "Neither 1 nor 2", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "020156", 
		"question": "24GwbdH90A3j+IshXl77y/7wOG6QDGRRoj+AXbZ6ZGP6FKHNfK3/iZB4MVmHzUt+4H/Jp+X55BMKnr1a5c6Lf2IXdo41iJjbh7WkiSAIccS2NZ6ekKLs5wz26o4/NHQ=", 
		"answer": "27i3ZpTqkQ/r+5AlEhH0hfv2O2rcQ2UerHuQEqJ6dDHwUbXUZ+772tdhNVONmFh+9jRChbmsHo0sMF+BPHX93oOO", 
		"explanation": "25a5eJjn0BWq1oYjXQv80b38OmbAEWsCpmzDXaU0Vn7xUa7FYK3yxpZ/NBDJq1Rp93/BreXU/kEKjLwbwICJdTEXc45h3JCI2eC39H5TJ8BLlol9pLMRavFT2DCoesCbA/9+x3qBKwXRZDqyEX5g1DjFymhercO18DP7Rt8k1Rkm1oh+rdgpPtuW2uiS5kn4lhSLynqFTf1tH0Ccp8Cp/0qTroM093HU3E7yEY939CPWBVRYuVk=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Introdution >> The Idea of National Income", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "total value of goods and services produced by the nationals", 
		"option_b": "sum of total consumption and investment expenditure", 
		"option_c": "sum of personal income of all individuals", 
		"option_d": "money value of final goods and services produced", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030101", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit4ElUR/2wL37PG+QEG0Sqn6PErB3eXTtQK7Rev6+y5J2LlLJjlN6/nrDraL5+VRPm6BeqY2QfiEGbp8vx9bJw+zyhDZEMMlKlY1759oSffoHjDyjcJTINOtq12eOIAX4cjS8CjB1lyXfhXJF6I605yL7V9Y40xA+j9g6wmAf/lv94ldFVMO9ZhOpTQ==", 
		"answer": "2+ThMMHgk14EidYF6o+cPf5+wHis6cA=", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71Fm7rt1wQVKy1vL8PGrcQ3ESqnqNRqpnZGKjVqLFb+O+yp9wK1CMg1xy/HGGt631t1AAgate+ZrffyRDaoNqiJeM1Ov5y3xIMIZJm441pI0XdfdIjDy+Z8HWJfouxnuNJkvjJzi+EDBmlSXfhXJXpI+itROzUcN30wEzhJN96YgvKMKbwKGd7w25hRKX3XfRQKhpEFrZt8ug6lWVr5B4tMOJ8T/U4P3vm+za/9AYIgVdrYM/YFezhK0F4Wo5RYigYBcL5e3dZBTZKC2xIggS686vlmBhw8J4BDFk519PkcNCasUz25f3qHIxPM5/BzKupgRByYdrWgXUT8u/3Z/hHNlHbHEsPN9QAQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "1960s", 
		"option_b": "1970s", 
		"option_c": "1990s", 
		"option_d": "2000s", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030102", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEgr31/C/cnvCDGUDpmyQFeN3f3zuW6nOd63r2pJ1Z16QzV5j4nPUt7aw41xPi61V5pqaL2Bj+b1hvAhd74cNjFugY9yA", 
		"answer": "25e9fIX2wxTv+ZFgXQyyzPDvJ2TGBm8UrWvDW600cX/6QK/LYOq8S/wbg5cNnxp9xr9f+m79qg==", 
		"explanation": "24WqZ5bh1Ar5t5clVBvg1r3rOivXBmwUsX6PEqFxZGXmRqrHYPm+xoUxLlGZn1Rt93vDrbGw/l1PjqZCqY2QfjYGZp8v4cTJ3ve3yn5Vc9VUn4N74pMcPOBPjDKjeM2bJf1hwGGNLkawYCuyE2R82HHCj39epoy3+iCiGJokzxY7l4s45NsvKdKMma2H6w2MjgOQ2X2eWrgoURObsNq87lGRpYws9cKf8TvW5Ob2jP3e9dAfIgFc/4dxek+0nqYOv2oxQoigYBcL/OvDdRTqJSamNQ8Rucrt0jRoxYE8T2gg8V9HjJBBZ9IxNzDtz/2ol4m2SWgVSiyzdA==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Economic growth", 
		"option_b": "Technological advancement", 
		"option_c": "Betterment or improvement in anything", 
		"option_d": "Social development", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030103", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MU0Whuy0fjtOCvsQWcSrHGMX6p3MHbxW7DWZtG8iZ5/Z1mKglV0/3/FsOXi8lUKnehP5tHdC6pw9Yt4FsGaXqjbdlVIcg==", 
		"answer": "25y2a4P20Arvt4wuEhvxyvPwOGLTQ3QQsXaCUK9xYzHsQqLQLuy+2ZJjLlONzVR9smLPrqCyC9glfC2FJG1l1XE0NsBizQ==", 
		"explanation": "25C7Z5/83BDpt4IyXQnmzb3sJW7TCmQYoH6PXro0YnTlUbXRLvnxiYN5IhyAg1hp93fVpuX/5RMInadM/YbfeSxDc4plx8LJ0uf4yn5MOsUEl4Vm9pMcb7RMxTaoNPP/ELIuwG+ULkr+ZjX9DX53mzzTxjxGuoy/4CSvXcw+1Ax+1op54906PdSLzLqa5kr4gxKBnHSHTa8kEBSdsMih5UaY4JI9p8SCtXLU8rTtk/XWsOoDZxpXuYltZhf80KEH+zg9UNuxKBtFseHTblriLSGgZxgc68Li1Hhs1cImS2wmtB4GkoZEa893lpfi/CY5MsgtVTqp41BIwtRxUASCNLy703324UE6NXsldp1orm9jsBe+0GDhaP0KYCkwYzeM", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Increase in economic variables over a period of time", 
		"option_b": "Expansion of physical infrastructure", 
		"option_c": "Decrease in employment", 
		"option_d": "Rise in inflation", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030104", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iPWK2Or4yXhCc8FWlZdm7NoWb7RBjCy4ddrPKfhnz2yMIgX9YjiuEWJx1D7QymhercOy+ySpUdskxVU7mMd97scyM9qW2uiF6V+xhwSO2WjRR6thAxSY9d247kCVpos79d2IozvU8LT2nLjH+dMOXgZusbR6YkizmehBymNiEe23ZxxE/O3TIVP/Lz+3L04N9cr6xTRohoE7SGo99RMGkIxaZ4B62NjqvSY5MMNrGXO7rUAAzppoWgWYdamx32bl7BU6dnUlaodkv200rw6QMUd7iSfcRSJXm5Jm994e1RRscWZDhTbkhzyCk2yAcoCj6o74xe75rrht8aomJQGQOV3WWIQSYvHV/Gt3zb5ycXURlNNE5P8Y", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBi5RonGHEpE0eWKjQK/HLu7x24V0JEjJiENr/nfIorH5+F1PgK4byMzsL+6VFW4bW6o228jH0bJh", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzwg3r44AtVxDm1r3+J26QF3AEpj/OEqZ3f3/sWa7BLursxoBlLxyYmFp15n/AqqDjt0cHiuhS542NdSMQe8tmxpCC0v23wXJOPclJk4My8psNdfVCwDi+NNvNJewu2meNIgXxaT39EHh9h3HRmHNBvIv78SavVZo+zhM9hIprrcExLNiNzamd/A2oiQqL32LRTLhnGEeQusC7q0KSpMI+vMOMvzHS9fi5ivTS/tACbA8SkoltZlSqkrpFuD4wVIimbRNY/uqQYlv/Mi2gMwIEuc77xnhoz4w6HX487V9DgYxYbc161djjrj0nK8UqHCD6rkFB1IFuWhPWOf2xxCjt8xUrejoscINpuW0wogCSJ1l3mSuMQyBYl4lu7ZAYmwAjbWNBknjpjDjLtG2Kbpbl5JL5yai3grZ3+uMGaUCOMRzqFowOYPPUNXJ3hqmpTaNEI5NmHiz1ffRpvDDqYIKc2nkA38o0b3bk9z+Lk9nweWqqp5v2gJY30u9Kh9H2BI5D2+VBVlWd", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true, and R is the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true, but R is NOT the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_c": "A is true, but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false, but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030105", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRqmzDU600dWniWbfOa63xz9d0JFOHglZy8TbBsarn41tQzR/gfvHknsbHK27R+nfiNsk=", 
		"answer": "25S2KJj90gvv9pYlEhf8hen3MCvAEW0VtnyXW6x6MH7lFKbXeuLzxpV4K1mazVlisieW5uX/4VYdz7xT7M6TcTEXPpJqycLLd0xTjTBScGgPfxUtp/4IHQ==", 
		"explanation": "25S2KJj90gvv9pYlEhf8hfzqIWTdDGAYr3rDQrF7dGTgQK7NYK36wIV0JEiFlBto+3HIqqP58kBPiqtU54GSeSFDeZlg38SBl/D/1n5UNM4En5hi5ZQMdftOjDKrNMDTJb5jz2CVIUTzcyyvDX5z1CLTiWhZusOW+jW+FNsi1Bo/mYVx4c0vfMeN1qyG60i8xgmU2WnRXLRpFBSdsMOn5VCIsoMssN7NozvI/fr+2ujB/9oeYRxbqY9rehu9maxJ9z8sQd2gKCZD9PbVZ1v/JWTjYC8TucLt1WZsx5EsHWA6tAtOh8NGcM93w5vwtT0+f8JsVTKvt0tNyJZ1UxKFNL+hkDm0pRUwY385JZ5luW05oByIaE17m3nbDCVC1JRj+5AUmhd3PW5Dn2PygyuOwGSBb4Tm+cJJa0QQlaD5+V73F0t0Mpbr", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "An increase in the production of automobiles by 10% over the last year", 
		"option_b": "A decrease in exports", 
		"option_c": "Stable unemployment rate", 
		"option_d": "A decrease in the number of new startups", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030106", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3v5YhgWw2y0O76MSvEDCIVpmyAQKp2dTH3XKKCauT4z5JjIlKKiBt592LRpqD+t0cYgOhL7JyWfyYQPohgxsaMxfDywDFIPdJL2pB39pkacuBByzjtctvJLaEsw9MSpYpR4Ilzc5fH0jwylQ==", 
		"answer": "25KqZ4bn2Vn49pElEAba2TT2SvmiLJ5Zwhg/uC4=", 
		"explanation": "25KqZ4bn2Vn49pElEhP3xO7qJ27DQ3YZpj+AWqJ6d3SjW7WCauT4z5JjIlKKiBt592LRpqD+t0cYgOhP4IOaMDIGbIJgzMPJ3uq31HRTMMNKjoF14doLeeZN332EYJTLMvF4x2qFNAX5aSq0A3hg1DjYnnMWoIystSquV9J3wVUkl5Vx7MowOZeX2LvT60W5iAGH2DueXrh2UVXZpt6t6EqaqYF4ocSAtHLd5vX0n7jn+NsZZw5drYMzIxybhace7CJ4Q8mgbVUL8uvCc1HuNCS6ZwgU9cfwlmBhw8IrUWg6/12jomPtmmzew28q7sBuUsl6", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Growth rate", 
		"option_b": "Inflation rate", 
		"option_c": "Interest rate", 
		"option_d": "Production rate", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030107", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxQD68sUvVF7i1/L4J27DECIYsD+TQKp5cWPqWL6Cb/7txpR4JkiMiRts+2LO46Dz+F0AgqFYqYmNfzUXdtQtpcg4IjdCezZurjBBgCdMHA==", 
		"answer": "24StaZ/n2A3r44w2V17i1/L4J27DECCm9S1VXS9vNYi7y3sn8kPi", 
		"explanation": "25C7Z5/83BDpt4IyXQnmzb35OmjFEGcC43CNErJhcX/3XbPDeuTozNdhNVOOn15o4TbKqq71t1sGiKBe+864VBJPPoJhzMWaw/b+xX0BI9RLnpVx8JMQcrgAwjy5fdvVIfIux2CDKEj1JzypBzBFgTDag2hXvIqt8Ge6R8oywwEh1otx5s18L9ic0KmfqEm9kAOO02ucTbNwXRScpNup50qIuc54pNiMvTvP7bT2nLjf+dgOIglAusZxbE/8nrwauC4xQ823fFJI/urTZEbjYByrIhwY/8Tx0zgpgbM8XGcg/QtHlopAZ4BjxJfjrjcjLIoqHCD6t0xFh5lzTAPWdb67xXrl9FB/dHQ4co9//s85yHtGzb0CvENGz1ImvD8=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Quantitative progress", 
		"option_b": "Qualitative progress", 
		"option_c": "Social development", 
		"option_d": "Environmental sustainability", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030108", 
		"question": "25y2KIX71Fnp+Is0VwbmhfL5dW7TDGwernaAQe80Z3niQOfLfa37yph/KFGAjht/92DDr6rg+lYBm+hL+4eScTAKcpIvy9+H1OHlynRFc9FNjogtpmbgZouyndcVbHt7ce/lIZk=", 
		"answer": "24StaZ36xQCq+INgXhf0wL/oS28ifRGXHXNolN1+HkKI", 
		"explanation": "25C7Z5/83BDpt4ElRBv+yu3yMGXEQ2sC42+RW651YnjvTefBYeP9zIV/IljJmlJv+jbPrrXi+EUGga8b65yQcSYGbMtn3d2I2aTgwX1HMtRB2oF84NoPeftQwDjqZ5TUNvt8z2KMZ1TlZjW0EGk0mzeWhnVQrcOy+2e6Rt8201U+n4x9rcA5PduL0auS+kj0xgOGyXiQXLRrHxjZptqp5UedsoZ4usvNvTvN/fr+2tHHsNcYIgZdq8Z1dkio16kL9z8sEcC9bxpO46TZb1fiLS2wZzoV/Nnm0Ht7w85pGlgh9RNPlpoWbcYz2pHiuXVwNt4qATu/40lP1IA8XBibZK+92G3q81wpcDoqa5l6uT93yQAty81W6wF6GYG8bsH5Pg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Quality of life", 
		"option_b": "Quantity of production", 
		"option_c": "Expansion of infrastructure", 
		"option_d": "Standard of living", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030109", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iPWK2Or4yXhCc8JBjIV+64oSefpUjDijd9vWMP993WuTZ0f/czH9FWV1miXfnn1CoZW+tSa1UJom1RQ+n5N5+cEqOZePy6eU+kirlUaL0juQRv1hEluXusOxpwOLqIcqsMye8TfY+/r2l/HQsNkZbR9Gt8ZvcVKxlroA9DN4Q82kehdY9OrEchT8NSmtMwcJ+N/qwHEp1pAmWnsx5wx6jL9YUMVyxZfq/HoCdpcqITu/40BJ1IB1URSCfbK2kGrh9EI6cHRrYIlisiI4qAzcL0ZxjX+UDC1fkMBu/d8Xmglqfi9EmWDljjCbjWCBaNPm5oXugu304Lhl5qY1aVWIMBzXVJ4Zd6XBM259xKmPBadIc4xoGiemONYh8jb0KZOHnzwVwNwyJnLp9y+d0sX8Pm36tID2mcB+VL0VIpHJ5tz3tFnRZC/uMXCWaN+4GQT1Tnjx3Qkloxdl3CkVqGTXGoR+4SQCkD6/TwRwmiKganWkmroc5YTOe4sn1vnjzT8VluA4mpj42hIxTgeozyDwz/t7e01IYxHwc24rmec=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz0Ar58pc0WxH8hbXefCvRDWZRsXqCQax6MDnRHefDfOi+3YVkIhDJjFV/smTDorb/+RNHveEb4J3fZCoGPohg2sKM1PC3wWlRP8dKm5R765Rfc/IAzS6+ccbPKfFgjiahbgdu0Vq1NgDqiVpBkCuegnh2", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHgxRj+8oglXArhhf7wJ3nVAHYduj+HW7BgeX/kQa7RZq37yph/KFGAjht/92DDr6rg+lYBm+ha54rfdSEMcIRiwdPJ0Pb402VJc+NHlY596ZMcPPBF2jihe8TWJfB6jmeOJEnlYzyuRHJ7gDmWm2lXppey4SavXcwygBg3gpVx7tt8PdmbmbmG6UGxkgeW1W2UCLx3AVGaod3o5EXcqJc1tMPNpjfX8vXrn7j289EFbQVbvMZ4cVSrg6BJ/iU7RNuxe1JF8PbCbkPhOWisKU4M7Mrtwn19x5YgS2x08h5FloxEcYB/35Ph/Ds+PMJnECD241RSyJBpXAOfe7P41XznoGE3cDo5YIt+syN1oAOPJxR9lXmOSS9FmJkr+8gJmQVqc3wAlHn3wiuDiXbPeJrw/4nyhvz5r7cj87EoOkTAeBzaT80TZ6DFNXF7xO7bBKhPJ55pFCf1fdoovD7rL4GA13ke0dczb3/y+SuX0snwL2C2vIL0i9piVIsIM8PA78SltRCHJgHuNXXTR4v1VwywfTz5wQslowowzW1Q2iLdEJlz9CQDjT6RDgRtgWf0ZHnhm7FP/sKPfI0kwfT42HIfiOBxkJW1eb+GrJUyNyz4FbxEcKOshQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion (A) and reason (R) are true, and reason (R) is the correct explanation of assertion (A)", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion (A) and reason (R) are true, but reason (R) is NOT the correct explanation of assertion (A)", 
		"option_c": "Assertion (A) is true, but reason (R) is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion (A) is false, but reason (R) is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030110", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDfOi+yIRhIl+dnht09DbDoKr++F4GjOhf7JiafC0Tc45h3IrJ6+qmijFtNtBBlsB94toRaeBSxSmke9qbHPA8gC6hMUT5azi/DXx9gCiWhXoWoIa6+TOzV9slxVU0l4Rx4cEoNdKMmZSduwP4qgOU2XfRR7skFFCMts+84kyS4rZr5tSfOwIUKaj4pQGZ5Mk=", 
		"answer": "25S0ZNH811n+/4BgUxz90/i9nRQLEAOvQrYd8yxhqAOnaw==", 
		"explanation": "25utfIP6xRDl+clgWhvzyen3NmrCBiIXonyKXqpgeXTwGOfDYOm+zJNkJF2dhFR1snrDtaD8t1Idiuha5YLfeycaPop82NWKw/e30HlAJ4ZHlY1i9pMMebRFzzKje9nSI75qy3iFK0rgajyzEDB1h3HCgnlP6I++9CP7QNV3wRtyn4po/8cqOdPfyL2S5ESsn0aN2judQbthUWCRsNyt7UyOpc548uyBvXLU8rTtkv2T8dwEdA0V/49sI0+0kugE9zksEcu7ZQJZ9OzVb0fkNi3jJgAZucrg1WF7x5YsHWg65whDkMGXZj1W6B6Hgd7ue80RczHQ", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Only 1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "Only 2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "Only 1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030111", 
		"question": "25C7Z5/83BDpt4ElRBv+yu3yMGXEQ3AUsmqKQKZnMHDwR7LQZ+P5iZYxJV2ahFg7/3/Iqqjl+hMDir5e5c6QdmIUdop7l5K13qNpaiwK3qaeY2E6lF2v", 
		"answer": "25y2a57+1FsS91M+zSK2qaAPhEtnHrve", 
		"explanation": "25T4apDg2Bqq+owuWxPnyL3zMH3VDyIepT+KXKB7fXSjWqLHav6+3ZgxJVnJik564HfIt6D18xMNiq5U+4vfeSwKaoJu3NmH0KT11n5AN8NW2oVx65QQcf1DjDmoYtHXL+5jy2CUawXxdHm0CnN7mTSWmm5Zvoq/8DT7UtUlgBAhhYJ2+cE9MJeXzKWS5g22gwOGzzudQbZhUVKWusrkq0uZoY4svc6Mozeb8eD62s/a5NYEdxwSq452cBf8hr0I9CMsSIi7blJH+OLVIVfsLiasM04U9Nvx2WJshrYhWHsx8hBUh88WJel91ZfpuXVwPMJ4Bza5t0hZh5J1UxuFNKmw1Sjm7FQxfjj87dS6y9cHzA1FS+3PkEaH", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Income", 
		"option_b": "Education", 
		"option_c": "Employment", 
		"option_d": "Infrastructure", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030112", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr+9pElXxv80b38OnnCBmEFr2bDVqZnc2PqVqLRLvn2zNdjIlCImVJ0/GXOqrWw9VYbmK1e586acy0NcYZmy5COxevg0HkBMshA2oVx65QQcf1DjDmoYtHXL+5jy2CUeAd0ea77xXMWWsqGNyHson6m", 
		"answer": "25C7Z5/83BDpt4ElRBv+yu3yMGXEQ2sfoHOWVqZnMHPsQK+Cf/j/x4N4M12dhE1+snfIp+Xh4lIDhrxa/YeJdWITbIRo2tWaxKi303lIP8MEn4N96pUSdfcAyy+iY8DTYO58x2OBNUz8fnm4CWB8lSLfkHlF6JKu9CmvXc421Bwkk8do/8c7LtKMyurL1DRbuCsuziTamSBqYPRE", 
		"explanation": "25C7Z5/83BDpt4ElRBv+yu3yMGXEQ2cfoHCOQqJnY3TwFKXNeuW+2IJwKUiAmVpv+2DD47Xi+FQdirtIqY+RdGISa4pjwcSIw+3hwTFIPtZWlZZ36Z8RaOcAxTPtdcbeIe0uwmeLIgX4YjixEHh3lSPTxjxTrJa49DOyW9R7gAY9lY59+dF8GdSQ16ee4U74gRSNy2+ZCLtrEkGKsN3o+1GVrYMqvMGU8T3VtOXsm/bH+coKdgFEusZyZk+unqsauCYxWs30YRxI/unVchitMDqsIxse7cLs2DRdzoc7WG875hoKwpdea9MzxYzlqDc9OsN+VTG/sFAAw5FvXAWfdrirkHzs5VwtNWguaYt5tSI7sgeVOBR/lG/cRT8RgIhuvt0WhhAjfGxDiWThljrLgWuca5bxqduuqWo18N4b2KZjJVEiv/w=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Economic development includes both quantitative and qualitative progress, while economic growth primarily emphasizes quantitative progress", 
		"option_b": "Economic growth and economic development are synonymous terms", 
		"option_c": "Economic growth leads to economic development without exceptions", 
		"option_d": "Economic development solely depends on technological advancements", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030113", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrl+ocpXB/mzPLxdXnVE3AUsHqNRrA0cX+jUaTNYOLz0Nd0P0yMn1J+/HXPraKw5FoIgaFd4I2efjZDe4hgxt+E3ue3w2NOJNJM2oF+65QYb/1EyX2+YdbINP9g2meBKwX5aimvC2ZxmTTYnm8WoY37/TK2VdR31xA+msp66MEyO4ij1/nTwES/jgOQnHyDR6pwGRSboNro50yLpZB4scibtD7U5Pn8lOzv/oxLTgdFupQ/ZEmzgLwBuCgtRYi8YRVD9PaQZVH7JSSsNwMY99/f2Ccp7osuVWwmtBhUjZRCaoBy2JyktDs3N8h4VTe/tUFMyIRxWhmCSLPskETr91AtNX05ap15tG00rwvcJFtpn3ncSClHkYxk7t0cmxAh/SZgTwLvlLFhjJDe80A0AA==", 
		"answer": "25q2ZIizgltCK8qb6cV1s+4AZnzwz1y0", 
		"explanation": "252xb5mz1Brl+YotWx2ywu/wIn/YQ2MdrHGEErR9ZHmjXK7FZq323JpwKRyNiE1+/nnWrqD+4xMdirhJ7J2afjYQPophiNWK2Or4yWgBJM9QksBw644XPOVVzTO5fcDaNPd4yy6FP1XxaSq0C340lT/SynVbuJG04yK2UdQj01U7mMdp+MkwNcOGmaeVqEGxgAPC6HOUWrhiHkac+Y7vxE2QucJr8o2auTvY/LTqjvnH9c1LJSBbuI56cRu7hace7CJ4UMawKBpC9uzVcxTpJT6mKwEN9M7twjMpz5FpSWExtBJJkZcWY8Nww4rlqDdwPsN5Ajao4UN0Fvar3dwHa/SWwWeqG+0=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Only 1", 
		"option_b": "Only 2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "Only 1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "Only 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030114", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg7gzPD+J3KQAGoQr3OGXKRxMHjtFKrHb/7r255/IByNiE1+/nnWrqD+4wxNORps3IurB9MwuulAflzIqA==", 
		"answer": "25G9fJTh3BDk/osnEgr6wL35NGjEDHAC42uLU7c0c37tR7PLevjqzNd1IkqMgVRr/3PIt+djI1VQGEs910EP/G+KC1Ma", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+0BDkt4EpVBj7xujzIXKQCmxRsmqCXLd9dmjqWqCCaujozJt+N1GMg087+2WGp6Dk8kEChqZS54nfcTITbIR/2tmIw+G3wnBCJ8lWicBz6p5fdfpExT6sYNvJM7Iuz33AI0DmYjWyFH1xmiWWiXNbuJGy5iKoFNg41B1yh5J549w1KNaL0L6WqEy2gkaTyXqdQallBV2PsI6p+FOZo5Yr9fmFtCDetP3q2vTS89VLbQ4SvIlxcF6yhL0auCU2EcC7f1Jf/qTdZFX+NTqmZx8I+MfqwnV9z5QsHW09+RpIkYpZbNMz4pDhrjc2MN9vWXP9h0FUwoZxVhmferr4xGDhoFM+dm4kd5ktqCU0tU+fJ1ptjmKIWThU1IRu6NUVmhRueGFU2zbpkX+fiGDPcZzw/8D/iuXgsrxr9600IFeFdV3WUs0dZrDVNWZmz6maA7VLNo0lBTLiiyIgY78eRJb2HCtRMQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Defining economic growth accurately", 
		"option_b": "Determining the factors that constitute development", 
		"option_c": "Identifying the leading economists for guidance", 
		"option_d": "Estimating the GDP of underdeveloped regions", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030115", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzImLeBCISrHuGQeN1fnWjVanReejsiZZyJFObiVJ19Xrf+Zn+1kAcirpP4IGROANKJMtbwNXJ2uX+yjFFOsBCk4Nn6I4GPP1OjCy4ddrPKfh3x2CHZ0H1cTyxC2B5kT/CynVF6Jez9DP7Xc53yRskmYtu6Nt8PtiL0eiC/Uy2kg+W3W+YXrgkEFqd9d+96k+VtIMsvNuI8TPI5PH6juvv/p43bDpXvpVwbROO3vJJyT85XcGgaQZC5+GQYEf9JSu3NE4O7MjrlnV6hoAsXHwg7V9HjIcWdsFgwp2kvzM+McJ+VTG/40lFxodpTRKSNKir2WbjoEY8dHYudsjCitGL2cjf+TMBEWL7x+pY", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt6QzQRvg0fTwOyuYIitRonGHErd8dTHRUabRYeO+gaU4Z12biBtv4GPD7+Xx+VdPm6BeqZyacTEMcMtm25Cd3+G3x35TIcNHjsB3/IoTffpB2DSiepTUJr56xmvANFHxczywAX5g1vNftWnKLhX7KnxWXC5aJ/U=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCy0fX+ISvUBnQUr3CTX6Z6ZDHrVbSCf/j/x4N4M12dhE1+snfIp+Xh4lIDhrxa/YeJdWICbZtqy8Sal+3khGVTJsMEroh3pIgafedPwn25fNXPYO97z2KJM0Tkbi+4RHZ1lyXZmG8WpIqw8Ge5Udsi1AxylYZ248cofNWama2S+0S0n0aP2XqCXa9hFRSQpo6p51CT4JYqoMjNsDzftPf2iOrW88oHe0hXp5ZzYlKyhOgd8C94UsembVJP+OLWaFf4LDy6ZwcTucbm12d81IsnWikw8QlDjoxGb8V9wtjQtDciOstlBzb240tQ051zUVe3NLSrkHzs5RUyemk/JYtuvzgnoBuZaFd2lWKfSW7dnjBpLp1zyuEgTmkRGFES", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both assertion (A) and reason (R) are true, and reason (R) is the correct explanation of assertion (A)", 
		"option_b": "Both assertion (A) and reason (R) are true, but reason (R) is NOT the correct explanation of assertion (A)", 
		"option_c": "Assertion (A) is true, but reason (R) is false", 
		"option_d": "Assertion (A) is false, but reason (R) is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030116", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MUIdjey1un+O2+QBW0D43aNErd8dTHgW6nWa/XqiZh3Z1GMjEhu4H/IpOX08kUKg6dL5IuRZH1BDm6NS4b/trixTGJ7ESpOsA==", 
		"answer": "252tZZD9kT3v4YAsXQ7/wPPrdULeB2cJ4QuGlRA2Qsmc2M560vwKZdw=", 
		"explanation": "252cQdHgxRjk85ZgVBHghdXqOGreQ0YUtXqPXbN5dX/3FI7Maujmib5lZ1WazVo78XnLs6rj/kcKz7tP6JqWYzYKfctgzpCF3uLyhHRZI8NHjoF854NTPPFE2T6sYN3ULrIuz2CEZ1X1dXm+BWB9gDCWg3JVp46+tS61UNM0wQE9hJQ0rd80NdSXmamB7Q2tlQOGnG+eCK9lH1/ZtsG95VeOqYcr9cSDpT2b8vvsiLjH+dsZcUhducZ3dla9megN/Tw9XcekZRdF5aTxIVfiNSa3NRdd6sjsxHF6hoogWmEx5l9upqoWdch22NjwtDdwM8RsECCqokoAzoc8Vx6RfLiqnCjw6FB/cH4+Zot5tSI74QOZPlFy2mKPDCRYk4hu7JxZlApnPXtImTbHpg/LkGCdPJDi+4nohKj5s/lr+6QvLFO8O2DWYoUZJZvkDidly/rbCaNKNpNoByfifdc3vC3xJdah0TAZ1d1gAXbz/SWXgY3RPHO/v53pg9F4AP8wJN7C+8q6vVmHKRbPBU3aJsL6GVmpFiy4+holvgtl3TIV7CLMB8ly8Cwei2y1CVBsl2fwfnOmhLtP+cKBec4y3ODiySAZnec4i5Tg1Q84VES6jndKt5KWQVsP2VzTXuAOyAUrAroIAZuR1miAkHrfW3EIcdq2JqeGzz8Iks7VqXI0/5EAUcyaJBybucs13Ba4D/x7WWKtjIPvOPAaGmkp9KYx7eKgu9n7PcCAC3ZjLb/X6yoGmIcVyL6cMd/4+Vs=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Humanitarian Development Index", 
		"option_b": "High Development Indicator", 
		"option_c": "Human Development Index", 
		"option_d": "Health and Education Index", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030117", 
		"question": "24GwbdHbxBTr+cUEVwj3yfLvOG7eFyIjpm+MQLc0OFnHZu6CY+j/2oJjIk/JiV5t93rJs6j1+UdPjbEb6oGScisNd4VoiMSBxeHyhHhPN89Hm5R99olFPNxFzTG5fJibBfp7zW+ULkr+K3m8CnQ0qw7ptUNpl8FPl3Ta7Jn3zteWaNOMfAk8", 
		"answer": "24asaZ/30Avut4omEjL70/TxMimt3zAOM3LxviaUUwQKdoAD", 
		"explanation": "2529aZ3n2Vnj5MUtVx/h0O/6MSvSGiIdqnmGEqZsYHTgQKbMbfS+yIMxJVWbmVM7xn7PsOX55BMOz6Ve6J2KYidDcY0v3NiMl+XhwWNANMMElJV/5p8NPPtGjCSodcbIYP8u3muSNEr+Jzq8CjBxjCHTiWgWvIz7+S6tUZo+xlUxg5Vq6MYofNqQy7yS5ESsn0aS3W+FTa9qAhSausC84k2Jpb42icOotSfY9eDwlfaT+c1Lbw1TrJNtZl/8lbFJ9S85X4itbRNZ4qTfZxT+IyCsKAIU98yj13pthocxTWw34BpCwppTY9Jglpfi/CEzN8JlGTq0pARtwpVyHw6Tda+rkGfioEY8fXUkaYNju208sk+IIFE+m32ZXi1WkcBl690bkBYjcmkAhXPhkCzLj2PPepzx5oHwxe30tbpi5qooJwGUPV3MFoxcdbbSNGh8iuGaHuZfPJJ3GyfyONFu2SHpJZWA2j1NydwhPWSn+yzZgc79Nmq2upz+zt1lVKsIM5HL/Ma1tU6HbiWhOHiSdNi0Vg6wXH/w3AFpvhYiiDUY6XaYCcl8/SQBmj6zSEoklz/waX+11qpTqoGBcp491uHpnTsW2PdtjYny2gl8QgqpgnNOt4qLD0xO2UDTDMMUhAohAqAIGoPUzmOqm0XESnIJftzyQaeBgyBBzOr/iSF0rNADUI2dOQvejp4k0Ve2E/JqRifjqZLwMvIUBiQl9LF+x+jh/+2VXLrkPGA4Lxm2SeZN8tV2Ris7AQ7PRSdOcLG6V90XUqBOknjPlhRdVXoJClyM76ANHQW8r9bJaW+ear8fARPnI7wDU8+4TUjaO+W70XfaRryVgU6kWko2DFlH4owwWbD9ZNDEQ35/HhY=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Wealth", 
		"option_b": "Happiness", 
		"option_c": "Standard of Living", 
		"option_d": "Economic Growth", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030118", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQAG0cs3CNV61gYzHsUufWZui+4bNYZ0uAmVM75n7Dqrew5VYcn61Y/YeJdWIOe4p83cKM2uH50GIbceDEH2+mZdxezRm8X4aRFiQ=", 
		"answer": "25C8fZLyxRDl+cUjXRPiyvP6O3+QTiI8pn6NErpxcWPwFKjELv79wZh+K1WHihc72nPHr7H4t1AAgrhU54uRZGJOPqdmztXJ0vznwXJVMshHg8Bz8NoddeZUxHHtR8DaLvpv3GrAKEOwSzCrDX5z1DLZh2xZpoa14Wf2FP0lzwYh1ql5+cEzMtaTmYGd60K1g0aS2WnRS7x0GECY+Y7ox0qKqYw/9c6CvCLU+vH3jriesPACbkojecHMPFmbja2AHrAc4pWr", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHb9TCt5MUlVgvxxOn2OmWQAG0cs3CNV61gMHzmVbTXfOjtiZp0JlLJlF564GWGrKOw5FAHgKdX4ICYPGILe4pj3NjJ1Ov61H5PNshQ2o135YkKbvFTjDGkctGbJeZ+y22UJkvzfnm8EDB2nSPCgjAWqY2/tTSvVdQzwQc21oh+rcQ1Kt6R3uie7UyrkxSHzzu2ZpQkAVGL9c2p+0qIocIMvciftDTU5vG12vfD5NcEbEhx/5F3ali016UI7CkwVNv0fBpO4uGQYlv/Mi2gMwIEucLwlmBhw8I7VG484F9HjJBBZ9Ix/w0P+kMIUEqLlPhCZEu5Bg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Education component,Mean years of schooling", 
		"option_b": "Health component,Life expectancy at birth", 
		"option_c": "Standard of Living component,Gross National Income per capita", 
		"option_d": "Living component,Nil", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030119", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YMzt2pJjM1WGgxNauyyGl631t3srpuhO+ouMMDYLe8tjx9eIxe3jzHwBPMAEk45x65caPOBPjC+octjeI+ou2maFZ0H5ajCzDWN8nT/RynVbuIyp4Sa1V993zxNyn4l74sU5fMCWzaDT4UO7lAODz3KfT/1DP33ZicCa7kKPr4xwh4TX8R7U8/Xrk+zb/dcIIhtRvop6cBu9m6QG72o+Xtr0bRNY+OHCIVfiLTiiNQcO9sWj2XIpz4wqUmQxtBNDlIZacYBy1YrrryFwPMJ/GyeoqkFTh4N1Sx/WcLS+1m326Vs4NV0FTMp7vSEgpBzevUhglcmYHbkASUi5yr6JrQ==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmzxRHvt4QzQRvg0fTwOyvRDWZRt3eGErFxcWLsWufDfOi+3YVkIhDJj05vsmLOpuXi8lIcgKYb4J3ffi0XPp9nzZCK2PblwXJVc8Ncioxz6psLdftOjDKrNMDTJb5v3X2FNVH5aDf/urUQPfrwRmyfGAvgBuwGug==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCy0fX+ISv4J0tRtmyGQeN4f3biRq7WZuD3ytd4KV+GgF47+2WGt7fl8hMngL9e/4uNPGIXdo4v2tWIxOv5hGNENMdWnol849oafedJyS/td9vWMP98x32PKQX0aDyuCjdg1DXfmHlVvI+itSKjRNY2yRtygo9x/ogpL9LTmaCW5k69xgKN2WifD6kkFEyJuc+h5QOIqId4tN6etCDP/fv32szb9cwOZAdAuso/bEuonqcHuAh4WNv0fBpOsenfckCtISugMhwc7c6j1Xxmz4EsHyJM39MRiAYNrFczXrgIu3k=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the assertion and the reason are true, and the reason is the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_b": "Both the assertion and the reason are true, but the reason is not the correct explanation of the assertion", 
		"option_c": "The assertion is true, but the reason is false", 
		"option_d": "The assertion is false, but the reason is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030120", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3FKbMaq39xplyK0mahFR1qErIkLHx41YCiqZPs86reCdDS6VL+JCK2+Xk13hHOsNX2oN98ZQLbv1F332kesDUYOpm3GuFZ0bxczy6C2J9kSKWiH1FrYf7+in7QNIyyQdyl4Rw5M0qOdqa17yAqEK2xhKK2Tu5bJQkLVq6usCr51aPqY02742hviWb3OH0m/aT1NsdZwRdr4t6bU/8tKcc9j4qWM2nKBpK5+GQYFqtCAyKZxwc98zmlntvhtJ5DTlHpEsf28NGbcl9woumU/9AThEA+ey3ud0xA8NlcQ==", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHgxRj+8oglXAqyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHgW6nBYvjtwJh/Z1WazV16/mXD4UVnoeylI0gtU16ESJhEeRs=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHgxRj+8oglXAqy0fX+ISvlLUYh43yCRqZzf2PqTqLRLu7x3JllNVWMnht56zbuh4yw9lAHhq1N7IOafjYQPoJ8iMSbwuG37H5WNtBBiMwy8JIaPPdPwj6hYcfSL/Auz2yPMlGwczG4RFhQvXHEi3JRrcO9+jX7WNUggB0nm4Z2rcw5KtKT1rie7UOsxgWNyXWFWrRhAhSQpo6h5UKfo5cqtNmI8QbT8eb8nPfB9ZJLbRhGtolxI3n8nrtJ7CI9EcW7ewYL8OfTdEbsNC3jJgAO7s7xlH8q0TKdHkrCthfsAmDnUqc=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the statement and the conclusion are true", 
		"option_b": "The statement is true, but the conclusion is false", 
		"option_c": "The statement is false, but the conclusion is true", 
		"option_d": "Both the statement and the conclusion are false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030121", 
		"question": "24GwbdHb9TCq9IotUBf8wO6/IWPCBmdRqnGHW6B1ZH7xR+fWYa3zzJZiMk6MzV9+5HPKrLX98l0bz59T4I2XMC0FPp9nzZCP2Oj7y2ZIPcEEk5MyyrUrPPtOyX2icpTPKPF9yy6JKUH5ZDipC2Jny3N36ypfz1tz2ALV5OxeD6fh", 
		"answer": "2525eIH63xz55MfrW+VCzCGsaywkZUrSGxdP", 
		"explanation": "252cQdHw3hTo/oslQV76wPzzIWOcQ2cVtnyCRqp7fj2jVanGLv7qyJl1Jk6NzVR9snrPtaz+8BMbgOhW7I+MZTAGPoN6xdGHl+Dy0nRNPNZJn45mpLIebORJwji+Z5TSM75gwXrAMlb1Y3m8FzB1mnHfhHhfq4Kv+jX7YNIy0hA0mZV9oYh7FNaPyaGd7V6rwUaLzzuFQLgkBFqYuMyh7FaTtZE0rI2OviDJ8fft2vnd48kOcErn13F1QX/tASE4yGAJPyhN", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Health", 
		"option_b": "Education", 
		"option_c": "Happiness", 
		"option_d": "Standard of Living", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030122", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwRj49oglRhvg1r3oMHnVQ2ccs3eCQapudXWjVr6CY+jzy5JjZ1+GmFVv4H/DsOXn/1oDiuhO+oeRd2IXdo4v4MWE1uq34HRXNspLio136o5fTvFQwy+5NJzzBMwnjnqPZ1TlZjepDXZt1DXTnHlap5O28CmvVdZ3xRM0mZVs/pd+YKHTEFT9ECav8swDyZ3lKg==", 
		"answer": "25y2a57+1FWq8oE1UR/mzPLxeSvRDWZRr3aFV+NxaGHmV7PDYO7ni5e0ei32YOz4Hfy1fbnbJ3c=", 
		"explanation": "25mxbpSz1AH68oY0UxDx3L3+ISvSCnAFqyXDZqt9YzHqR+fDLuD7yIRkNVnJgl075n7D46Tm8kEOiK0b55uScicRPoRpiMmM1vbkhHABI8NWiY98pJkecrRF1C2od8CbNPEuwmeWIgX5YXm+EWJmkT/CynFZupe6+S6vTZonwQEmk5V2/og/M9mL0KaG7Q2RkkaLzzuQCLprHlDZvMCs4kCdtI0q9cKL8SbT8bT2jP3B8dIHIgBXvopraxuzkegIuDo3Qd24aQZC/ursb3noISbjPgsc69ij2XIp1YEhUmY4/RFB2MNiaslglpH3/CY4Oo1rAzaookNFh5ppUhWTZv231ij95VQtZjokY8prsz84oAPcLVBrmWqIRSNf1JRj/8RZlERzeH1Tk3igij6YwGaAcYPv7pT5gajZtPlq4eMmaUaPOliYX4MYbLDBM2hgiuadTbJUNt9iEzflPMEn8zf4LNaVyy0M2dctKnnztCWf0sy1KWqqpp74mt15GoMOEf/sqduyohzEYDPoNXzJJv/8UBuwRm+40k5oshk23TMVqG3eSJ138G0MiHuiSENh0i7ub3Osk/5T7MKPP40+xvv4zytXi7R7lo/+zhgyVESSmT9KocSeD1tAwlCWF8MDzQovGLsTVJnXsnmekDbDX30De8/kBeiIxWxE0/X4gGY9sJZOVMyeIwnOht8ywRi/PfNeUGnprZS5NPIQG3Et9rtl07fhg8KyZrOtPyUrLxeyWPxM4ZARZwQ7BQPYRSBGZr6rRJgQQuVcknfPgxBNQnEJCF/Cu6kGWUS9pcnNYCrXbfEICwzvcPMKFY75TUTKJuLp3D+JA7uJlkaqVksrAnqVJLEB8Q+weY3gIV/zkmZguc7xOlRJBJESLyjmZmi8tuOqH0YzbGwkaI1IdUOVQh4gnT3CM/Z1zagGMAwlROirHEYTmlFAmX7VC1ZBtV5eWrS4QV8uPrAFKVVRzHe2HrURSA7TujQ6gUCZ0Db1c7p/OUAwO22Az02glpdnjOr7h86ODJT2Jbhb3JgOKrNJBJXQX0sZlePo6qHsGHowCGo3LP3EUfWRsQ/1B9rgo8rUhVVFyrEFMx8vLSuOmpfW/D4tBrEPZmMKvDMeo8XWIg+k3YFa1ERnQhXj8wHwSWJhuhRla5+rZducOpSz9UJLD2TOWflC2P93yCLwJ8btaj8xEWonngmdc9zexjjDLrno1KwACxmg3pXCUZM3rHxxx8/yyl8Aqnt4in3xHmTfIujrqApcJzx5Sb2TE0lExhgklTvx3Vz9M5u4nuYdgfBM3bAHoRj/p2F4iluIXArBZTPjyuXep2PJrkskib1qSG6sTmctzQMpVOIk/3B9SSMmCbV8ufb0LrjIl3W2bpO+jYoY8UNGQ+fNKrO+r9ToLKzLPOX41sCOKnf1sYdhAfy9ZdESLjbDYTgbt/7ddsTNfkmSfGyL3b/YGyWKLCNa+nZ82m2IFAxkKCC/Tt9YEnZdlsJzLa8YtsHqvU9raGvMWqJ9yrUIklVYDllVQ+j42HhDWPkiOoGJfEt/5hR+lcZsvrNtPvMQZYJli7Sn", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Cultural promotion", 
		"option_b": "Income, education, and life expectancy", 
		"option_c": "Material resources and technological advancements", 
		"option_d": "Good governance and economic growth", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030123", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iOSB0qTC6lVxfsJBiYl16p8bPNxk/nq+NNLUI+t9jmGOZ0z+ZDawATw0kTXDiX1CoYy1uWe6Wt53zBw0k8d99dg5P8Oe16uKqF+9gAqH32+CCLwkEluXpsum+FaP4I029dmFtHLf8eD8iPXa/t8FdhsSsIA/Z16qkqQG6Cc9X9z0VBx59OXDblqtaBrqfU4w+N/mxH1oysIoTnkx9wtVwoJEZ4Bn3p2kszw8Jo14ED+/tUVO09R6XhSCe6+rkG7r8hUycHs4cJhksip1pQqKLVhximaZQjgTuyh+ocZ9Fd/EAUL8TXXrqA==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBi5RoWqXEpE0eWKjWqjWLvn2zNdyKE6biFhvsnPes6nx+VIbhqdVqYGZMANBVpDr8DG+r/xFqySp39Hq+g==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCy0fX+ISvEC2dRi1uxFbA0YHDxVarHeujs2tdjIkybiEh+/GKGouXz+F0ciqZI/J3feTFDapl6zZCh2PPy0nRTf4ZQkoUy9p8eb/tOjCmldcCbL/Bi1y6NJlH1dTC8CDBylTLChW5F6I664TO+Rpo+01U0l4tr6IhxfMOX3Oi7zH/4ggmHz3XWXP1hH1eWuN6p+FDcoY409cmEvDfV5/32lOuT/9hLZg1Euopwc1a5mbxJzCI9Q82yZwBOvaTfcUDkLybjBU4U6ov33nEpy406SSk19xxTkIJCZ4Bw3pftvzdyNCKS7BOoc1yb0wvKqg7tIg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true, and R is the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true, but R is not the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_c": "A is true, but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false, but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030124", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3FKbMaq39xplyK0mahFR1qErIkLHx41YCiqZPs86reCdDUoRhzN+Hl9f0zH5OP4ZLnMBX55URc/lJzy7qNNfJKepn33uFZ0r2Jy21ATBcsBiWi3VbrYf74Sj7RNU+zgFymZJsrcEoL5eW16uc5V20gxKH0n6CW/1YH3eWu82k/lCVr4xi9fmFtHLz0N25lvnQ+81LYwZL/5V2ZFW1kaEK+SQsEcG5eBNI5aTfbxT9LySqJBcQ+MDq2HMry2qVavLVW9OxDQYKvEcGog==", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHgxRj+8oglXAqyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHgW6nBYvjtwJh/Z1WazV16/mXD4UVnoeylI0gtU16ESJhEeRs=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHgxRj+8oglXAqyxP/wIH+QF2oU41OMXKd7fjHQV6/NYeG+yoV4M1WYmF4783/Lqqv3t0cAz6BS7oaTeSULastH7PnOxKT7zXxIJ8dQk49899oWb7RU3iioNPbONL56xmvAJEr+ZDWoF3l7mnHCgn1C6Kuf3Ge3Vdk801UimYtx7tF8NdqP2KuHqESrxgCD0GiUCLxqFRSXutro4k6MrIs9sY25uTfJ8fL2iP2fsNEbdgFdscZdI0y0nqsBuDksUNyxe1Jf+eGQckDsNC2uIgAJucLwlmB704dpX3wgtAtOh8NVbc5w2o33tT0+f8R5VTW7r1dFh51vHwOecf2133vwoFQ8dm85ZJ5o/Cw7shiZOhZl2jBMVoSiifib45YzD5mo", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the statement and conclusion are true", 
		"option_b": "Both the statement and conclusion are false", 
		"option_c": "The statement is true, but the conclusion is false", 
		"option_d": "The statement is false, but the conclusion is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030125", 
		"question": "24GwbdHf3hfu+ItgYR36yvLzdWTWQ0cSrHGMX6p3YzajV7XLeuTv3JIxJlWEiF875nmGq6z3/18GiKBPqZqXdWI8QbRQ9++26KT4wjFVO8MEsqRbpo/ml+UQ09pniXkX09/qny8=", 
		"answer": "27mxZZjn0A3j+IszEFvbctAQqTT7NQOpuYTNKlI=", 
		"explanation": "24a3ZZSz3h+q440lEhL7yPTrNH/ZDGwC43CFErd8dTHLcI6CZ+P9xYJ1Iga1g2d122KGp6r15BMBgLwb/Y+UdWIKcJ9giNGK1OviymUBOshBi5Vz6JMLZbRXxSmlfdqbI/F7wHqSLkDjWzeUEDBwmzTFynJZvMOv9Cy+FNM51Bpyl4R74t0yKJeQzaCW+g2xixaNzm+QRqkkEEeJsM28+AOTpsI8sNuIvT3L+fH3jrST48sIakhTrMZ6bU21hacH9S82Rcm4KAFe4vDRaFrsIiGvLhoEucrt0jR6yYEgXGV0/gpVlopVZ/x94pDh/CU1NspiASD6pE1Wwpo8SxjWYLW9kGzt5lM6Z38lccpksik8og6IJ0Zt2mqOSWxQhoJi6sIYhx1fc1tImTbIphbLiXbPcpz3q4G8iO3xs6xx9+MoLwGINEzIX4MZdqCAKHUy3eyXAeteNpZpEGBN/HLN3zHXSvYrSWSfBwVR", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "li,mi,ta,ti,ons", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030126", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3FKbMaq39xplyK0mahFR1qErIkLHx41YCiqZPs86reCdDS6VL+J2N0vf+w39EN4ZsvrI199oPfeZBwTi5ccbIYPFojmeOJEr9YnX9AXRhlzDCg3NY5MO6+yP7WNMxxVU3jpd97tw9MtSGmamB7Q2xixaNzm+QRqkkEEeJsM28+AOTpsI8sNuIvT3L+fH3jrjv/v0EbAteqpV2bFXm15wB/WoQdfrze1Jb8PbRbFH5JTqwZwsT+sTuxnV61cIoUWV08BZLh41Fa899xdjrunI0OttvGTyqrkFO09Zo/a011+V7RrPhbH/0rqL2", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHgxRj+8oglXAqyzO6/IXnFBi5RoWqXErd8dTHgW6nBYvjtwJh/Z1WazV16/mXD4UVnoeylI0gtU16ESJhEeRs=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHgxRj+8oglXAqyxP/wIH+QK0Yj42+CQKJ5dWXmRrSCbOj3x5AxLlGZgklv83jS46H14VYDgLhW7ICLMCMQbo5s3MPJ3ve30GNUNoZslZd38p8NMLRUxDjtd9vVI/J73WePKQXkbzipRFhQpnHThH9ZpZO65jS+R5o2zBlyko516MYvNdiRyuic7g28gxCH0HSBRbhqBRSQpo6u6k+PpcIMvciftDTU5vG12vfD5NcEbEhw/49sI0+0kugE9zksEcm3awdZ8PDVIVflLyGgIkzvDoMHyM0ChIiH1eF4xg+D", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both the statement and conclusion are true", 
		"option_b": "Both the statement and conclusion are false", 
		"option_c": "The statement is true, but the conclusion is false", 
		"option_d": "The statement is false, but the conclusion is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030127", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MUHfDay1un+O2+QBW0D/D3KTaYWOOYRs2w6OAXOeuZt", 
		"answer": "25KqZ4LgkTfr44wvXB/+hdX+JXvZDWcCsD0eQTCNfsylOraSKfc1iXND", 
		"explanation": "25KWQNHgxRjk85ZgVBHghdrtOnjDQ0wQt3aMXKJ4MFniRLfLYOjt2tdYMxyAnht6snvDorbl5VZPgK4b/YaaMDUGcociytWA2eO3y3cBMoZHlZV88IgGO+cAzzS5fc7eLu0u53rAMETjJz24EnV4myHTjjxfpsOZ/TKvVdR3yRtygo99rZlla4eMmamAqEy2xgeOyH6DRrxwGEKc9dqnq2SOr5Er9emCvDfI4P362sjB/9oeYRwS96FbUxLw178B8SkwEcGnKBML/OHRckH/JWisIU4cucjsw3p91JtuTikx9xBIjY5fYYB8w4z0qSYMMfFkMh2S401Th5Z9TBKSNLK2kHzs5RU9cHYiYIwtqCU0tU+UKURuk2WZXz8RnZMr898LkERqcH9PjmLhjCvLlG2OctPu6pT5l+HxrPl096IrPUnAHEiYX4MfaabEInQyxOCVCOZYPJJmHiz1fdoovC78LJrZ3TwE3t56E3nX/DOKm870NSWytpP1mtxKGpIFOMXE5Yu/tV3LdSvdL0maa860TBv1c3Ld1xtmtgwsxy8s5kfVGIVw7CAIkGqMR2drnyr1YnW1j/5K45aPc4clysni/iccjOFqnpe30BQqQhaohGta8oWRSxxdyEffEsQCygorMLotHYDY/GrWhmLRRXgMbcrlPaagzCNMmuT+mGRvsZEAVomyIjzYhdIpzx6yAPE5UW77rZTqNOgMSmUi/vJjz/6ou8O+e/Chbqaob+hc/zo7lMRggAvfUFs=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Good National Hygiene", 
		"option_b": "Gross National Health", 
		"option_c": "Great National Happiness", 
		"option_d": "Gross National Happiness", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030128", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQzk/pQ1V17z1u36Nn+QB2sV412LR7d1fjHqWqTOe+n7iZ5/Z0iBiFJpslHoi+X5+VcKl/cZ0b/c/4Is9FhGFkbVdL0yJw==", 
		"answer": "24WqZ5z8xRDk8MUjRxLm0O/+OSvRDWZRpmuLW6B1fDH1VavXa/68toyIFsWCXrrzz6QMS/maiw==", 
		"explanation": "25ewfYXy3175t6IyXQ3hhdP+IWLfDWMd41eCQrN9fnTwR+eKScPWgNd4KViMlRty/HXKtqH15BMOz71V4J+KdWICbZtqy8TJ2OK3x35MPtNKk5RrpIwWaPVMxSm0NODTKe0uymGNJkz+JziuF3VnhzTFymhercOo4TW+Wt0jyFUzmIM4/80vNduW3KaQ7Q23gEaB03acXbNtBV2cpoLo6lDct4c0uY2MonLP/PG5if3d49tLbQ4SvYNzbFW7nqYOuCs2VYinZxFC8OiQckH9MCexM04J8cr3lmRsyZIlWCky8RpKvo1qbON825XxsjskJo18HCe7r01U3tR1TFefea23wnzl7kF/d38oZJ9+uW08tU+fKVo+km6QXGxFm8B77N8UmhBmPWdBjGbpjDqYkyWOcpej/IXwiaXypbBt9eMuJwGBdVLNW48Zd/PPISdly/CITYBTId9iDyPrLdkrsHnqNISb0T5N09YtImLp/T6Ql961OmS084LrgcJ/ELpAJtTK+cey8EvOdSuhID2AY8XnXEj/STzx1wtroxEx0WER5maYCoxz+iMKl3C3BQRzmi7jZDyil7Ac4oeCb84l3LXuyDQWneY4npz23RMvU0SomW1GoZffTlJLjVXSCMgV1wA6FfQ1HJPIsm6XmzbRR28CP97kDr6OxykIyub+nm14/4cHQYTOPxbYg98qiASkEe12R3Oh6JHxNP8dSmct9PJ5z+Gx9960NfqpPHcleR/3Tedc+ocRZQd1BQrRRSVBZPi+XoQNSONO3jXCkgZEU3cL4dVkMRdqkIpQw9yj5XNvHg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Higher income", 
		"option_b": "Environmental sustainability", 
		"option_c": "Good governance", 
		"option_d": "Promoting cultural and ethical values", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030129", 
		"question": "25i5fJTh2Bjmt5UyXRngwO7sdWrcDGwU43yCXK17ZDHkQabQb+PqzJIxMFSImQQ5Haa/O9HAFppLMo/oZFmj2w==", 
		"answer": "24GqfZSz2Rj654wuVw3hhwQpaK8L9E+rdX+LEMRvAC4=", 
		"explanation": "25i5fJTh2Bjmt5UyXRngwO7sdWrcDGwU43yCXK17ZDHkQabQb+PqzJIxL12ZnVJ192XV7+X24l8JhqRX5IuRZG5DcZkv39WF26n1wXhPNPpKpo5f5Y4abv1BwH29ZtvcMvt93S6SIkP1dSr9EH80gDnTynVYq5G+9DS+FNM5gAE6k8d5+8k1MNad0KSa/FT4iQDC23SeTK4kEFqd9d2t+VWVo4cr9eSZ8TvItPv/jv3dsNMOYxtHrYN7I1ml16EH/CM7UNy7egEL4vHTaRTsM2iEAz5RucLt1Xtkw8I5WHt09x5Wi5dXLoBy2Jykvz0+LNhnBSezrEoAy5FqWhuFSLOE3l/s6Vk6NXcqcY9/tSw54R+OJ1Nsn3iPDC9QmsBi88ALmhJmPX9Fk2bsh3iYwGmGapbwq4nyxeXxrqAj5aI+Og3APEiYVYwSa7zUZ2Bny/uaA7JZNt9vFjL2NNsr7yq1YJCB0z8E3NUtKnnzuGqWgI3iPGm2/pD8h9pxVIsIP8KF4Nj3slnEYDbyJD2bZ9vkUAb1XG+0kwhwux4sxC0d7WzMRMl++ylNiXu8RQlmly7uazyghLsc646dcM443fPgyDcem/F835nulBIoTwGpzXlCsZCQXU8DjUfDHcVHxRpuHrENFYLY/WOFnX/AWDBNd8v3DbyPj2xJ1OexnmRvrJ8AVIDOOhjXn9s1ijtWjKXsoFou3eWqWbbCPmY=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Economic growth", 
		"option_b": "High HDI rank", 
		"option_c": "Poverty reduction", 
		"option_d": "True happiness", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030130", 
		"question": "24GwbdHU/zGq9oE2XR3z0fjsdXvCDG8et3aNVeNLT07ca5j9UdK+35Z9MlmazU51/n/NpuXk/1ZPp4xyq98xcQuGfYstVcm1+QtKXp8=", 
		"answer": "27CsYJjw0BWq9oskEg3izO/2IX7RDyDjWhCpZcCeWAB7MCdEO83b", 
		"explanation": "25KWQNHy1Q/l9IQ0Vw2y1e/wOGTECmwW43qXWqp3cX2jVanGLv7uwIV4M0mIgRtt83rTpraw4l0DhqNeqaa7WWUQPphgxNXJ0ev00WIBPMgEl4Fm4YgWffgAyDi7cdjUMPNrwHrAE031dTy7C2Jx2HGRj2heoYC6+We6Wt530wU7hI5s+Mkwe5ec1rqB7U6sih/C2nKdRK4kBVyc9cyk6k2X4sBEFfqw/eGOtO+jDdsmaXU=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "eth,ica,l a,nd s,pi,ri,tu,al", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030131", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRqmzDU+NicX3qUOfBfOTqwJR4NFHJgl07wWLHraHx5VdPi61N7IKQYC8GcJ8vxd+N0uiohrlOhvUnSb476IlKGHb5bm4=", 
		"answer": "25qubYO+1BT6/4QzWwT7y/q/OGrEBnAYonPDU7BkdXL3R+UfEVyMW8+zvNgc2UWa2bbm", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHA9TSq/pZgUB/hwPm/OmWQAiImpmyXV7F6MGfqUbCCYeu+zZJnIlCGnVZ+/GL6rZH48hM8q4Ub4J3fdi0Aa5hqzJCG2aTyx35PPMtNmcB19pUIaPx8wgmlcZToBNMux33AM0rgKj2yE35ImgXejzxljK77/DT7WtUjgAYnhZN55MY9Ptua5aan4Ej4tSKvnHKCCLNrBRScpNuh/0KerId6X9DblHjth0QY7ADcEbYWVg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ignoring sustainability", 
		"option_b": "Increasing inequality", 
		"option_c": "Limiting economic growth", 
		"option_d": "Over-emphasizing material aspects", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030132", 
		"question": "25S+fJThkUClptRsEhf80fjtMHjEQ2UDpmjDW600cWLwUbTRZ+P5k9WOlB4Z3HHA7/hPLi5Qe2MD", 
		"answer": "24W3e4L60xDm/pEpVw2yw/LtdWbFD3YYoGqPRrZmcX2jV6jHduTt3ZJ/JFnLChIsP4pvLiGFFeOUNlH5Pw==", 
		"explanation": "25S+fJThkUClptRsEhf80fjtMHjEQ2UDpmjDW600cWLwUbTRZ+P5iZ53Z1iAi11+4HPIt+Xz4l8bmrpe+s6cfzcPestsx9WR3vfjhHZNPMRFloxrpNdfdPFOzzjte8TPKfFg3S6BJUrlc3mwEXxgnTLDhmhDuoK3/DS2FNMkgBg9hZM47Ms/KcWeza3Rfm+t4GbUbx7IV88axtnbDA==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Global terrorism levels", 
		"option_b": "Redefining development", 
		"option_c": "Humanitarian aid needs", 
		"option_d": "Possibilities for multicultural coexistence", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030133", 
		"question": "25CgeJThxQqq5JAnVRvh0b3rPW6QCmYUoj+MVONwdWfmWKjSY+jw3ddiL1OcgV87+3jFr7D08hMYh6FY4c6QdmIXdo4vzt+F2+vgzX9Gc9BFlpV398VdVfD9SUoqHimBUSnDpDtECw==", 
		"answer": "24aoYYP6xQzr+8U2UxLnwO694m8FOKSPLjMdb9TYFHqbZQ==", 
		"explanation": "25CgeJThxQqq5JAnVRvh0b32O2jfEXIesX6XW61zMGLzXbXLevj/xddnJlCciEg75X7Pr6Cw81YJhqZS54nfdCcVe4dg2N2M2fC3xnRYPMhA2opn945fcfVUyS+kddibMOxhyXyFNFawUzG4FnVymyPTxjxCoIqotS6oFM4/xVU/mZRsrck/P8KN2LyWqEy2lRGHzkefdLNQGVHZkuCAq0KYto07tNmIonLL5vv0leza/tlLbAdc8ot+d16unqkFuDw5Xd2xe1Je/+jZalGtNCCmZyY50Pft4nxshqUHdSk9519Hwo5ZcMUz3pfotSEkNs4qGDa7sFFSwtRzWVeScau93Gf07VAxYTo/bYtj/Dk9pE+0DH0+s3/cWC1akZMr994NmkRifmxPiXj0wj7Ll2yLeYGj+YHygu2wr78j9KIkPU6SJhzMXowIJbDPKXNgw+uOGaMcJ5AnACfqMZgs+TD3J6qa6zEIkP4OBzfu52qKhsT5NSW784D8gtViHakFOsiF586g8F/IbyDkMWnfJsr6XUj5WzzxwE52oxEpxGES7WvWD8l78DsIknGgTEAkuij3aWqkhPIc45bOd48ik+Hk2HIAl+B9kY/+1RF8Uwv7j3oDs8SSQE5KjVnTH8MOyg4oGbhBGZPQ4XiEkDbfTTwJetjzDaeXzilGzqPlhmBz/4QGUMymCDCZY2u+wyvAGhjsSh9BFFcDSQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Political freedoms", 
		"option_b": "Cultural promotion", 
		"option_c": "Income equality", 
		"option_d": "Spiritual values", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030134", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRb48IQuWwTz0fTwOyvCBm4UomyGVuNgeHSjY6jQYum+4ZZhN1WHiEhoskTDs6ri4wxNKHlwBGfCXxOahBuaAikfbA==", 
		"answer": "24ate4Xy2Bfr9YklEjr30/jzOnvdBmwF40yMXrZgeX7tR+fsa/npxoV6ZRU9zLvur4AFhnsOaG7gnIg=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHE3gvm88UIUw7izPP6JniQMWcBrG2XEqpnMHCjRLLAYuT9yIN4KFLJgl075n7D45bl5EcOhqZa64KaMAYGaI5jx8CE0urjhEJOP9NQk49899oxeeBXwy+mNJzoBM1AhyLAJgX3aza/BXw0mjTCnXNEo8O082e+TMoy0gEh1pB3/8M1MtDfzafT6U6wjwOU2TuFQLgkIkGKoc+h5UKerId4kcibtD7U5Pn8lOyT19EKbhsS97VbREj115wB/WoLdfuaKBtYseWQYlvhLCmhKBwc7cLs2DRrw5Y+WGw6tAtOh8NjbMln05ykkjMkNsJkBnO7rUAA05x5HzWTZqm93Hvp4VsxNVwkcIRpvTk8rgGgJmhwrmOZDCpYhpN/vucWhwhnPUdBjGbpjDqYkyW9eYPs+ZS8kunj4Ktm/qYmOkSEdVXWFt9MNOGAE293ivueHalOJ99uBGL2KNci9SrxJZLU3jcDxdgsI26n9SSd0t/0N26p85H2m9piBrYFJZHE6si4oljObyShNXLTcsPxUBqwR33owwdrsgs2iC0V/mfUG8lL/ShNjHugRlZw0i7zLH6ghbtYqo2AP49xwOD+yzcJ2Pt+34vy2w0wQkSygz9Hu4KZSk5Kw0CWHcISyh08BbESVJfT/XiC1WLYTnUfP8LzF62L0GxH3KP5j3Fttp4LRp+yIiXVvtYjiEXhU645Ymj/pIK5Ff0FGm0i/6Fiit+kp8WpYbOzLXZqfR+7XO5K9pERZww7PArPBiwPMeDiFs9OE7MP9HzEmwZGQz9eBEmM6akGVgGu6tDAayrWYqEMBxvxd/MGHNv2WlXWdfiniCTBA/+LmlWyWwhlSDWRLb8a4AOweJWyABa9nml28o2lG1JeSIIZOGuzR3ywsbmGGQo7cShpaItJfgfBQxVkujvXL/x1gaYOdAttdaCiWWUYnwVKm37hGllRtV9eSKS+AEEmJKJAJBtAmyO9XeAIVBXGg3ojgFKVw2L7KOkLI0gtcGGXzx2zzYZu3a84oFrNfrBkbKVpyYFPcLA=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "United Nations", 
		"option_b": "World Health Organization", 
		"option_c": "World Bank", 
		"option_d": "Sustainable Development Solutions Network", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030135", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17Fyu/zMSv4AnIBqnGGQbA0QnTzW7XWNNHw9ZlCM12diFZ+/GKG8v+ww1sKz59U+4KbMAoCbptmxtWaxKTFwWFOIdIEiIF874lff/tVwim/fdHIYO1hwmuMPgXyZiq4ADB7mnHCgnlfusOc0Rf7RN8lgBYzho5s7PQyD8Oeza2e7UOsxlTYnE+ZTf1THkaVsY6A6lOMqYw9pt7NgzfL++bt2vnA49sYcQ1B/5F6b1fxla0A9i14U9H0ax1F4u3UZEbkLi/jIQ8e7cTxxTR604EhHWgntBZIgYxbZ4wzxZfntTM8f95/BSO1sVAMh5VyW1eafbu9kG388FA8YXslZpNRsh4hoBuZJVFwjivPFmxlnIUryd8LmQAjVW5QjH/uhyyYwFeKbJzx/8D1lqjgtbtv+7AvLEXANFLWQ4wQaaqAJX4yy6mYAqpQMp1oBSPyNNogvDb/YKOa1i0I1JkOLmPu+ySK0sDwNGe/odLqmtViEaxCQBV0j7+ZoozTUHVlvubmWw==", 
		"answer": "25q2ZIiz4g3r44AtVxDm1r2udWreByJC436RV+N3f2PxUaTWLGmc3wOR2HL2k2c/Iwvx3pc=", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhdv+OXjVQ1YZpj+0XbF4dDHLVbfSZ+P72oQxFVmZgklvsnLJpraw+Vwbz7pa54Xfcy0WcJ99wdWal/f4yHRNKoZGm5N34NoQcrRUxDikZpT8BM4u3muSZ0bxdzCpBTBdgHHVhXJFoYe+5zT7VZohwQc7k5Nhrcc6fNGe2ryc+l70xg+M33eETLRqFhSQu82n5kbQ4JE3tsSMvXLI4eTplerHvJ4Haw5X/4Nnc16/g6kH+zN0Ec6mbRdP/umQdVutLSmoIk4R8M3mlndhyYsqWHp4tBhDjIZEbdN6woGo/DM+O41rFyC/rUdFh5t6HxSZZq+twHzt71sDe0YlVp5sqCg4pAGIaAY+k3jceD5EkcBf9tVZogtxcWsAtHfwkjaFhXacPKHm+4/ukajxs6pm4bAiOgGXMFDUG48ZbL3HZ2VriuqUA7VVN5p1HizhfdMv/y32MoXUzCwO2JkhPDfu+imWn8i5eXa1sJv4gpRlAa8QOcPRpYu2vliHbSrnJD2WftvxWhzxQX/hkydx9xkp2y5Q623WG4B78D8e3nGkQUF20iHhb2iuhK0QqpGbfIZx0uas2yAVnfB3ktvj210xRg++zXNKtIHfTFRAxFfTDYFHwwwgCaYOB5/F6yHWlHjUC30PbMv4Aq3HzCoI2ezjnHRtq5kBW7CAEBfont8yzRq0D+k5Bifku8bNL+kQSlAk//JGxf+ts4qTdOO0JWsvfAn3a+pJ/IdFKAtoURvIByhGc7CrUt0fT+5a03nGjkdKXj9IRVnD96QJXwu4q9DBYWSebLdcOxDrd7YBU+D5Wk7AO+LpxTXEBLqO1VSqXlAgXXqpKbVN1iPDVMCyJVO0n2dm+M2lPFRPU4wFN2f8ciu8vbOGGRIpPzsqOoFOdECVXx9klT3LLvxxiOcUeB1tcr20DVEfmBBNkzuSKl1TtUART6ioTkdnDaZELEhRhQSRNrNWEFzDlXoYi0WMzSz/IPhHNAkldHbTn1nil5t1l/bnhc6VAtGiP7gL3Z8XasRVhW8o7NkZ4xfk/shclT8=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Only Statement 1 is correct", 
		"option_b": "Only Statements 1 and 3 are correct", 
		"option_c": "Only Statements 2 and 3 are correct", 
		"option_d": "Only Statement 2 is correct", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030136", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQnr5YQtVwr31732Jiv+LFZRtmyGVuNgfzHxVanJLu7x3JllNVWMnhty/DbxrLf88xMnjrhL4ICaYzFDTI5/x8KdiKbDP/Hcs5IjKfzFfBG86W0v", 
		"answer": "25C1eJ38yBTv+ZFgQB/mwL/ONmD1gKMYZEo/cNLQRbjW", 
		"explanation": "25C1eJ38yBTv+ZFgQB/mwL32JiveDHZRtmyGVuNgfzHxVanJLu7x3JllNVWMnhty/Dbxi5ew4FsGjKAb74GcZTEGbctgxpCIxPTyx2VSc8pNkYUyw74vMLRTwz6kddibM+t+3mGSMwmwYSu4AXR7mXHfhG9CrYK/tROzUcgyxhogk8s4+cA1L5eWyuiH4Ej4iwmRyDuQS75xA1WNsI6p5VCLpZB6KXVWbM3By1yF66mYUUP8iQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "GDP per capita", 
		"option_b": "Social support", 
		"option_c": "Freedom", 
		"option_d": "Employment rate", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030137", 
		"question": "24qHV67MkRjk88UBRwr9y/LyLCvREWdRsHaEXKpyeXLiWrOCav/335JjNByGixtz82bWqqv15EBPjrwb/oGNezIPf4hq25JVa/+juwe4W9lCdhrblbEb", 
		"answer": "24K3epr/2B/vt4chXh/8xvi944s3JHPFPDHTJFo7L437Hw==", 
		"explanation": "24K3epq+3RDs8sUiUxLzy/76dWreByIQtmuMXKx5aTHiRqKCZejniZNjLkqMn0g7/XCGtKri/EMDjqteqYaeYDIKcI5825CIxKTnwWMBPdNJn5J98Ylfb+BVyDSoZ5TvKPt8y2iPNUC8Jy21DWM0lz7EmHlVvI+itSq6QNk/xQZygo99rdguM8GW3a2XqF25lAeP2W+UWq4mtUPmb+Aaf6rRsjE9NcDQcg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Wo,rk,li,fe b,al,an,ce", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030138", 
		"question": "24GwbdHE3gvm88UIUw77y/jsJiviBnIesWvDU6dif3LiQKLRLu/rwJt1LlKOzWREzUn5nJqw9l0Lz4Be6IKLeDtDUoJ5zcPJ2evjhHZUPdUElZIy85sTcOcCrlvxAX0ofcrD8kqSp4D90Q==", 
		"answer": "24a3a5jy3Vn+5ZAzRlztNPk/5RdcytCnd7UG/AA4", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHE+Suq9oE2XR3z0fjsdWnFCm4VqnGEErB7c3jiWOfWfPjt3ddwKVjJhV56/mLOuuX8/kUKnOQb54GLMCQCfZ9g2sPJ2+38wTFGJshX2o9gpI0ecPhTjAmlccbeJvF8yyLAM031JzuxBX5/h3HXmHkWqYC44DW6QN872VU0n4t06Mx+5rkSZVqzpO3phqPILIJwkg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "So,ci,al t,ru,st", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030139", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+zxxDv4IAkEh/hhfzxdW7dDHYYrHHPEqt1YGHqWqLRfa3szJF0NU/JmVQ79HPDr6z+8EBPirBL7JyWdSwAe481ilf8v+V5Z8nHNjS/XS3d6+Y=", 
		"answer": "25y2KIX71Fn65YAzVxDmhfDwOG7eFyDW/vefMDr3vaKFcodwLyLN", 
		"explanation": "24OxbYb63x6q/4QwQhf8wO7sdWrDQ2Mf43qOXbd9f3+jRqLEa//tiYN+Z0ybiEh+/GKGpaD1+1oBiLsXqYCQZGIFa5962tXFl+vhwWNAP8oI2o9gpJYQcvMA2Di/eZTvKPt8y2iPNUC8J36UCjBgnDSWmm5Tu4a14We2W9cyzgF11o5rrdw0OZeS1ruHqEy7hROQ3W+UCLxqAkOcp4zSG1Oc54Nx2wN857kTGTXa", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "For the future", 
		"option_b": "Overall in life", 
		"option_c": "Long term", 
		"option_d": "In the present moment", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030140", 
		"question": "24OxbYb63x6q/4QwQhf8wO7sdWrDQ24YpXrDV7V1fGTiQK7NYK3szJtwM1mazU90smHOqqb4t1wJz7xT7M6Zfy4PcZxmxtfWlePBQsD8E2EjwAGFaGf0qDI=", 
		"answer": "25qubYPy3RWq5IQ0Ww30xP7rPGTeQ3UYt3fDXa1xN2KjWK7Ea68++T9ZzOL+Y0EmC5NwrExg", 
		"explanation": "2525eIH63xz55MUhQV730/zzIGrECm0f422GXqJgdWKjQKiCYfv725Z9KxyFhF1+smXHt6zj8VIMm6FU586NcTYLe5kv3NiI2aT90WJVc8JFk4xrpJAQZbRP3n29e8fSNPd4yy6FKkrkbjazFzBAnDTEj3pZuob3tTOzXcl3yQZygo99rcUzL8Pf2KuQ/V+5kgPC33OeQb5hU7Drz9jLeT8IzjT+mJM/bgA=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Daily joy", 
		"option_b": "Having purpose", 
		"option_c": "Meeting goals", 
		"option_d": "Overall satisfaction with one's life", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030141", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z0Arh8oFgUxz90Om/PWrAE2sfpmyQHuNDeHD3FKPNLv37xod9IhyNhF1992TDrbH59kcKz6pe/ZmadSxcPORBM0TqYRnrbrv4KzwT+lk=", 
		"answer": "24awZ4PnkQ3v5YhgVxP90fTwO3iQAmwV43OMXKQ0ZHTxWefRb/n32pFwJEiAglU5FEU1VpgsV6iOoKIbZLv0pw==", 
		"explanation": "24awZ4PnnA3v5YhgWh/i1fTxMHjDQ3QC43OMXKQ5ZHTxWefKb/3uwJl0NE/TzWh0/3OGs6D/518Kz6VS7oaLMCQMfZ58iN+Hl/f/y2NVftJBiI0y7JsPbP1OyS6+OJTINf1mjm+TZ0P1YjW0Cnc0kz7ZjjxfpsOv/SL7WdU6xRsm1qhs5c0uL5eS0K+b/A2+iQWXzzueRv1oHlqe+Nqt+U7cqIMopcSDtCHIuLTqj/vbsN8YIglRt496dVKykOgd8C8xQ4izZxNH4qTfcxTgISOqKQld+Ivn33Jvw5AsU2oxtBZIwpdeZ4Bk2YrouHDuvpnddVbEQri2RUq06OP2", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Personal and community happiness", 
		"option_b": "Present and future", 
		"option_c": "Daily joy and life fulfillment", 
		"option_d": "Short term emotions and long term satisfaction", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030142", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRTv9pY1QBvhhfnwMHiQF2oU40iMQK9wMFniRLfLYOjt2tdDIkyGn087+3jFrLfg+EEOm60Eq7WRm1FsSt4FQZtb7LBgIiA=", 
		"answer": "24atapv20g3j4YBgRRv+ybD9MGLeBCIQrXvDXqpydTHmQqbOe+zqwJh/NB53z/vYeP1NyGGRT6+t+JSs", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHE3gvm88UIUw7izPP6JniQMWcBrG2XEqp6c37xRKjQb/n72tdiLkTJgF564WPUpraw41xPi61P7JySeSwGPoNu2MCA2eHk1yt9PfpKvaRCpIoabrRDzS2kYNWBYMpmx33AKkDxdCyvAWM0gDnTyn1ArZG68iL7XdQ0zxg31oh+rcl8P9iK17yB8QqrxgWLyHKLTbN3LVqqus2h6k/cs5copcKfpWibwPzwibje9d8YdxpXrMZra178hLwb/SQ/RcD0ZxQL4uvTaFXhYCamMxkS68DwlnVnwsI6SHkk+w1SwpBPcdR224uktTxwPo1pGia0t1ZZ+5pQVhGTNLigwG3n9FQxdmNxJb5ltT51rAqdO0Fsn3jcWCRU1IF9+8IYkgEjc3pNnnPywjCNwHyKfYHwq4G8le3is7ZtsqAmJwGFLUzdVZlccbyAK25kz6mSA+Zdc5xoAizyL8wS8h/rJZOQ0DRNxNZgInbs8WqVm8vweWayvJv6i8csVIsIP8KF5M62o0nVZDChNXWWJs/xXhr1Sjzs3E5yvxEmwGEA7W3IBIw//CNNnz6zRlFqhjX5LHSggLsc/oqLP4gj1vDo0j9QjPs4kpr80V0/TwuyjnpQ8oWdQElbjUDeG8QVhAUnGrESKJj292OTh3nDQmgUJY7CCaGUgyFN2/DknGRu/4QGUMyCKQ/ehp4pzle2COtwW2CtqYj9feoaBnEi7rd02OSvsIqye7OlbGYlehSjS/Zl/bRTewd1Eg6dCiIPY7e8RIgOVelA3C+Kow9BVD9EAFvf7roNTkS+osGIYm/IZr1cARiiYLwXAdvoWk7AO7GgxnDIRryTgEmqTV1ncUWcFon94L7SeuSrPcONRg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Governance and income", 
		"option_b": "Emotions and purpose", 
		"option_c": "Relationships and leisure", 
		"option_d": "Subjective well-being and life evaluations", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030143", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sU0Sw731r3wMyvYAnIBqnGGQbA0ZH6jQK/HZ/++zZJiJE6AnU9y/XjV+ecVLKDZqgXFZWDv9COGt9E3", 
		"answer": "25S+bpTwxRD88sVtEjv/yun2OmXDTyI0tX6PR6JgeWfmFOqCQuT4zNdiJkiAnl168WLPrKu8t3sKi6dV4I3feCMTboJhzcOal6m313xIP8MI2qVn4JsWcftOxT7tfNXLMPdgy32TZwjWYjyxRmoh4JccvzHZCKW554YS5hA=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHnyAnv5MVtEh/0w/j8IWLGBiIQrXvDV7V1fGTiQK7Ua6G+xJZlJFTJjlRp4HPFt6npt0cAz7xT7M6bdTEAbIJ/3NmG2fe3iTFEPslQk49899oecvAAwDSrcZTIIepn3WiBJFH5aDf9FnVnhDTVnnVArY+itROzUcgyxhogk8s4+cA1L5eN3LiB7V69iBKRnG+ZTf12GFORoY6l6lefqMBe568dJKu6VkMsiX5tB5di", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Affective,Emotions", 
		"option_b": "Evaluative,Life satisfaction", 
		"option_c": "Hedonic happiness,smile", 
		"option_d": "Eudaimonic happiness,Feel", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030144", 
		"question": "2525eIH63xz55MUoUw2ywfTsIWLeAHZRpnKMRqp7fnDvFKbMaq3735Z9Ml2dhE1+snfVs6Dz40BPja1Y6JuMdWITe4R/xNXJ1OX5hHVINcBBiIV88JMeaPEAzji5Y9HeLr56xmuJNRqyi9lsVzykXamftfggpFEg+Q==", 
		"answer": "27y1ZZT32Bj+8sUlXxHmzPLxJieQDHQUsX6PXuN4eXfmFLTDeuTtz5ZyM1WGgxnkAuZe1oanPnZwIhiGn42K", 
		"explanation": "2525eIH63xz55MUoUw2ywfTsIWLeAHZRpnKMRqp7fnDvFKbMaq3735Z9Ml2dhE1+snfVs6Dz40BPja1Y6JuMdWITe4R/xNXJ1OX5hHVINcBBiIV88JMeaPEAzji5Y9HeLr56xmuJNQXzciuvAX5g1DfTj3BfpoSotSa1UJojyBA7hMd3+80uPduTmaSa7kj4lQeW1WiXSb5wGFuXicCU5WaRr5YxusOMvXLT9eTpk/bW481LcA1UupRsI0+z17wB/WoxXMWxbBtK5eGQZ1HoLCGtIE4S/4vr12R5z4wsTnp0+w0GiIxPIulnlpH3/D02K8hkVTKpsEtDzpVoWhPWY7Ss2Cj070Y2YXM9YMposSIhqACSOxg+iX6fRGxQh8B78tUYhhFxeCMAn3nuljqFlGiKcoevq4Hygaj3srh3+7cyLUS8O3nOV4EJZKfJMWIywuiLHa9SNox0VzDjO9A873ntL9aA1zxN388lPXbr+GqYgd7wKna3tpztzttwVLAOM5bWqce+tlmHSDehKG7Tac3gXAawTm/r3A1stgwgzGEH4XbQSIV28yhNjX+kQFdikyT0ZXOv2v5f5YyaeoAl3vDiyX5Qmfp834zy2BFxRQGyg3gB3Vjh0CG8wehU7EXoh0Xbow==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "present feelings, future aspirations", 
		"option_b": "daily joy, life fulfillment", 
		"option_c": "short-term happiness, long-term bliss", 
		"option_d": "immediate emotions, overall life satisfaction", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030145", 
		"question": "25y2KMOjgEimt5IoUwqywfT7dWqQNkxRsXqQXa9hZHjsWufHYO7x3IVwIFnJjlRu/GLUqqDjt0cAz6Ve6J2KYidcPMdd5iZ6Ozu/FlTUG91t0qs=", 
		"answer": "25u5fJj83xjmt40hQg77y/jsJivcBnQUr2zBalN7NPCrC6tU5poeajyPhA==", 
		"explanation": "25y2KMOjgEimt5EoV17Hy/TrMG+QLWMFqnCNQeNTdX/mRqbOLszt2pJ8JVCQzUt64WXDp+XC8kAAg71P4IGRMHRWMdg/kZzJwOz+x3kBNshHlZVg5Z0aeLRDwyijYMbSJe0u2mHAKkDxdCyvATBgnDSWgn1GuIq18DSoFNs5xFUlk4t0oMo5NdmYmaeVqFmwgw+QnHiYXLR+FFqK9fqg7gOOpZE3udiZuD3VtOb8mffU/tcRZwwSq45+dxubs5hJ8Tl4X8egKBML4eHCZ1HuNGiuIg8O7NnmlntvhpUsUWV59hpPjIQWY853lozsvSZwMNliECH6pUVD05tuTFvWZ6i72Cjl8xUsenkiZIYtrzglsQCOPBg+km6dQDhZ2MBq8NRZkxZmeGtPkTqggy2OwGSDb5yj4o3sivrkobd3zq0bJ3WIMBzKU54TaabULmh8iuqaAapZN99oGWLlMsAg6CvwJYXUyzZN1Nw2Knvo5GqXk9n8Nmu7v9LwgNB/F74UOcPWqcSx8FTGcTPoL3iAdYv1VwywWHn030NnshErz2ER5maYHIY/4D4I3mq4TFdh0i7uaHWil6pT+JHOa4Fx2vvq0iAd2OBwmpLllA0zSw24hHpQ8q2LD11D3luWHcwLyAwqTLsPVILZ9y2juzbERDwdbcH7DryCgzhA36P8i2BuqoILWImAOFnUjJ4uyQehCPN8RnStqYj9fesQBmhh+Ld4xOrhtsS/NeerbHYibgiyGe1c4IEReBB6Eh/UBiFcXLaSWKkWRKBd12bFmxJcTnBHRU3N6OgJHRejrcrBaGPdYr8ITg32ZqNFFcHqWUbdMbGgxnDdDrrckEG4UFYxDi6SYb0I5BTlaImyLBKjg2Fq/NL2clBVQMMAOSv/OWm8rK2ESy8uPyQkO8pFf0LbCxYrmDLMMPxjzaUZMBltT72qG1UE1h5J3zfcB0xMsVgXSaC+DBMuJKpJNV8YwzD1BagaHCvFlDYOzn6d0jLlJ/9YIgkRfnScnVis24VulvzhwoeSSsT3L7ESwYUGLPZaSpTDHlcQg7Pm9qH0GWl5NXhkOvnBUOPTvEq2Js3ip8/V1VFOx6pIBVA3MC2ChpHKsBRoO7JAfXsI9ro9jUh8GdM7yL+ww0nL9Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Sustainable development goals", 
		"option_b": "Poverty rates", 
		"option_c": "Human rights protection", 
		"option_d": "National happiness levels", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030146", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut5EoV17Hy/TrMG+QLWMFqnCNQeNyeWPwQOfSe+/ywIR5Z0iBiBtM/WTKp+XY9kMfhqZe+p3fQicTcZl7l5LER8UyZu3KKE9SQkvX3DA6", 
		"answer": "25y2KMOjgEuoN3ND6oQ0hrwcpQy72p2qaw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHG3xD+8oFgfB/mzPLxJivWCnACtz+TR6F4eWLrUaOCeuX7iaB+NVCNzXN64mbPraDj5BM9irhU+5rfeSxDLNs+mpCgw6TgxWIBI9NGlolh7J8bPPZZjCmlcZToNe16z2eOJkf8YnmZAWZxmD7Gh3lYvMOI+iuuQNM4zgZyuIJs+scuN5fX6oygxgT0xgfC23eeSrxoUVqcodmn+Ujcr4R4sNWdtCDP57TulerY+dAMIhxd/4d8a1K5ga1J7CI9EfuhewZK+OrRY1joYAymMQsR9tvu03p9hqUmXGUntFd1pqRFK/x96pbQtDdwLch6GiGu401Th5Z9TBKSNLK2kGmk80AtY38yJYVr/D0wrh+QLRR3lCuYRSpXkZJu8MRZlgt2c3tSlXPzwj6Jj3CbPIfr7onuxeT1trxv4eMoLwGINEzIX4MZdqCAE293ivqOH7BZKt9mBCn1fcQ7+SrtKZmazHkM0tY1Ozf38SWJnsiyKiW2upT8zsd3ALYTMNDG/cK4vhCHdSvkKG/Tdc76Sg2wQHq4wxt3pxc2zWEZ5iLUAY96uW0MkHrwXUxhmzWgaWSxk6xV74yNep1x3POszT0DkeBxiZ631RM4Bwq+in5Xu5KaD1lCwkDfEcMU+AcSAoAJEdbD932Zh2KQSnAecI7/D6uL1ihNyaP1j3V8/58AFY3OOhjJg9sy0Ve+B71/VGT5p5TqfegdC3Bs+6B0ivmpuN+8fefkOGpqbBW5Tf1Q8YBFbUJvHkvVBDRfabarRY5SAfNa0X2KlhQIYFt5RUrJ6egLXBSjvsWELnnRYLgdAl7xdqMVHNzsAgfDPPesiDXRFrqfgUawXF1pDjuTJfAL9wL1foP/ZAe802Vl8sSlPlhdQcMUNCj6d26qma2/BTIyemwSJ5hLfgf9SgA0nTDGNOonv6IQfwo5AaG0WVEY1hhCjzHAGllLpAwKUKqhAFUoOOlQLl8U3yShEK4bVRLNxjILnkaVzCf/OrpKP01jbGGfgwHinptomL/Als6CC9qiL7hbx54GLPZPS9rCDVofkbP0/e7nA2kqFS1jIe/JTObC8Fv+B4jHhuTJiRxcwbcLPh8yKzqHnJvcsDstKKpOYzBFuzMcotnHcA+k3shN3VF8EFTg+QH0RGgxuhQzZpL9b53dapOk4EBGViXJU/lFjfB+1CDoPNHWJBY2AWZ3bPMpmc0tDL7d5xKVnkcVPA==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "In 2015", 
		"option_b": "In 2010", 
		"option_c": "In 2000", 
		"option_d": "In 2012", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030147", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut6c1Vhr6xL3rMGrTCyIcomuGQKp1fDHzW7TRa/7twJh/NByIgVR19zbFoqv++EdPn7pU/4ebdX1BFWZ9WaUiH5W9rxDZRk+jIw==", 
		"answer": "25y2ZpThkRrl+ZElXAr/wPPrd8+7LozHJFGtFzGa9unvdJ8=", 
		"explanation": "25etbJX70Fn+9pAnWgqy0fX+ISvdAnYUsXaCXuNkf2LwUbTRZ+Lw2tdwK1OHiBt//TbIrLGw+1YOi+hP5s6WfiwGbMtsx96d0urjyXRPJ4ZFlIQy4o8Tev1MwDCoesCbFPZr3GuGKFf1K3mpDHln1DjFymhercO2+jSvFNs0wwAgl5N9rcs0M96c3Oq3LMmCOOU1+mQo0k3hAzF9", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Wealth", 
		"option_b": "Desire fulfillment", 
		"option_c": "Social status", 
		"option_d": "Inner contentment", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030148", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YNHw+oNwM1mEiFVvsl+c44H15EMGm60b7I2Qfi0Od4gvz8KGwPD/iDFJMtZUk45394lfdfoA2DWoNOHoYPZv3S6SIkjxbje4ADBngDDRhH1YvL+1xjO6QN86xRsm1q5Rt4gUPceP0KaW+174jwjCyHOUCIhXUVyYpo6h5UCOpYMrsMnNtTfI5P3tn7jW89EFbQVbvMZ4cVSrg6A19hY2ZsC9axoL/uKQdVzoYC6sKwIS7sLt0TRg1cIqUnsm8RxSwopYItJ2xYjhvyZwMMsqATu/40VCyIJ5HwSCdam93W3q9EZgN9YjEq3PfF6Th7ro4ztihhU=", 
		"answer": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhf7wJ3nVAHZTxUAyXK44fetuC/ebju3aMQ==", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48UJEhfhhentIG6QImESrG2HW61zMGXsFLPKa63JxoV9IxyhjEtr+3jDsLawxVYfgLpPpc6LeCdDdop/2NmH0vfkhGJCPNRB2o90pI4XebR1wjS5cdCbE+pv2muTZ03xdHmvAX11nT/TjjxFvIK8+ya1QJokyRsxk8cqvZhkcJeb3LuD4Vm9xhWL23WYTrRnEFqN9cur5E2TrYs79cqfviXP/LTQlLiBoI5TLkhGt4M/VlW1g60NuBksUNyxe1Jc8PeQc1XjKy2nZ19J7cOj33op0oosHX475hNCwopYItR2xJX3/D02f8VrBSOzrUFT1NRVUVfEJO/rnCjw6FB/QHQicY9p/B4hoBuZOxRpm3jcXi1fn4VvvoFPgQxfc1NOr2LhljqGhWubPLrKq4nvxe7xrKpmspcvLFOFdVXLFoMTJbbWLmN3xOqeTbJTc4xyECXjLsFu6DH4NNac3ikd2dclPGSn/STZhsXweVC0uob8ipRFAL4UM8KF4cqk8FXJYjHkIG6WYovwXBvgRmj9kwtmuBYqxSgTqGXKB55r/W0kkD62SEdw3mf0ZHnhk6hV7oeAfItxwODr2jcDjOc4i5PylBIsVwuohGtG8GF5EaJIMp7DHvkLDygqNsU=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Statement 1 is correct", 
		"option_b": "Both Statement are Correct", 
		"option_c": "Neither 1 or 2", 
		"option_d": "Statement 2 is Correct", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030149", 
		"question": "24GqfZSzwgz544QpXB/wzPH2IXKQCnFRrHmXV600fnTgUbTRb//niZF+NQPLz6Li3/WWGF3zJKxeW+ivnA==", 
		"answer": "24WqZ4X20g3j+YJgXB/m0O/6dXzYCm4U422CW7B9fnajXLLPb+O+3pJ9KxGLiFJ19TQnn3FUG+VYO2Knl3eDasYg", 
		"explanation": "24GqfZSzwgz544QpXB/wzPH2IXKQEWcAtnaRV7A0YGPsQKLBeuTwztdlL1nJg1pv52THr+X1+UUGnadV5IuRZGIUdoJjzZCI2/f4hGNAOtVNlIcy7I8SffoA2ziheJnZJfdgyS7NZ0zkJzq8Cn57gHHQhX9Du8O0+2exQckjgBo8k8d/4skwfOOX3LqW7kKqg0rCyHOYW/1tAhSNvcvo5kyPtMI5ts6YozPP8bT4lOvE9cxJ6UHUytwk7eIa5h/Oy+cGAw==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Prioritizing either environment or human needs", 
		"option_b": "Pursuing green economic growth to help the poor", 
		"option_c": "Reducing consumption and resource use", 
		"option_d": "Protecting nature while raising human well-being", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030150", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1xjp44oyEh39y+ntPGnFF2cV42uMEoV9fn3iWqOFfa37zYJyJkiAglV6/jbVtqbz8kAc0OqKpK+OUyLQzSBxGXFgDcNr", 
		"answer": "25T4e4Xh3hftt5YlXA33hfL5dWjfDm8ErXaXS+N9fjHwV6/NYeHtiyirbNikYOhjeMwwG2rtv0M=", 
		"explanation": "2//4SdHgxQvl+YJgVBHx0O6/OmWQBmMDr2bDUat9fHXrW6jGLuj63JRwM1WGg2d1uDbn46358FsDluhe74iaczYKaI4v3NWI1Ozy1jFVIcdNlIl849oMZedUyTCRep6bAb5owW2VNAX/aXm4FWV1mDjCkzxXpof7/Cm4WM8kyRo8qokyrel8P9iS1KGH5Ui2kkaW0zudQbthHVuXso6k7kKOros2svGD+3L6tPfsluzG4ttLbQ4Sq5RqcE/8lqYNuCk3XtixehNf+OveIVboND+mIgBd7c7i1Xxs1JFlHXk15hpIlpAaIsF90tj3qCc0OsN+BnGLvp5Uu2h1rh2wzlBJj2g0", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "High funding for education", 
		"option_b": "Rigorous academic standards", 
		"option_c": "Excellent teachers", 
		"option_d": "A strong sense of community in schools", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030151", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz3BDu84klEg7z0fW/MWLUQ0AEp3uLU+N1fnWjdbXLffnx3Zt0Z06MjlR2/3PIp/qy8Z0b6Kqwr1IGIoI2juX2ug==", 
		"answer": "25e9fIb21Beq9pAzRhvgzOnmdWreByIcomuGQKp1fDHmTKTHff68DpAQ7NlEklJEnlYS7GUiFg==", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmz8wzu840hEh/8wb3eJ2LDF20Fr3rDQKZ3f3zuUanGa+m+yNd8LliNgV474nfSq+Xy8kcYiq1VqYuHZDAGc458iOSB0v23xnRNOsNSn4Qy8JIeaLRJ2H26dcebKfN+wXyUJkvkJy2yRHFimzjSymhercO+7TOpUdcy01U9kMdx48wpMNCa16uWqEy2gkaDz3iUXLRnGEeU9eem+FeZoYZ09dmFtCub9fDvlfvS5NsPIg5drcZ+I1m9m6kH+y88EcmkeABE8OfYIUDiYCSqIQtd7cPiwjR+yZclWSk48R5CwpdZIshyxojtsjcjLI1rGzf6tEFMy9l+Wh6Yc/+pRod3uRAW4wZPOlbC5Ghv", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Between poverty and luxury", 
		"option_b": "Between moderation and extremism", 
		"option_c": "Between deprivation and indulgence", 
		"option_d": "Between austerity and material excess", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030152", 
		"question": "25y2KIX71Fnp+Is0VwbmhfL5dX/YBiIUoHCNXa5tPDH0XK7Oa63zxpN0K0/JjEho53vD47fx41oAgalX4JqGPGIGfYRhx92A1KTy3GFEIdJX2pJ34p8NPOBPjCqlfdfTYP9qymeULkr+ZjX9AnF3gD7EmSMUlbdDVOsAWgPTi2C2lxp7fQ==", 
		"answer": "27C1Z4X63hfr+8lgQRHxzPzzd6Gk4/cEzAI4MfcBCLpoymc=", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kRzp+IsvXxfxhfDwMW7cECIQsGyWX6Y0eGTuVamCfOzqwJh/JlCAmUI3snTDq6Tm/lwdjqQb7JaPdTAXbctswcSMl+H6y2VIPMhFlsBz6p5fb/tDxTyhNNLaI+ph3H3AM03xc3m8CGN71DjYjHBDrY248Ge5UdI21hw9hMdM5c0uOdGQy63fqFmwg0aA0HqfQ64kEEac9c+r6FaOoZY9udTNtzvX+PH92Iq9N5Smxr2o2DdFZQSizEw=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "altruistic, ethical", 
		"option_b": "impulsive, biased", 
		"option_c": "cohesive, consistent", 
		"option_d": "emotional, social", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030153", 
		"question": "24e5fJn2w1n+/4QuEhf8xvLyMCeQE20dqnyKV7A0Y3nsQavGLv3sxpp+M1nTz5KWJ+lkvgZMogri0lsgLow=", 
		"answer": "252tZZD9kRHr55UpXBvh1r3+O2+QFGcdrzKBV6p6dzNDuUtq+dhxFK79EUFPoHmS", 
		"explanation": "24K9ZJ2+0xzj+YJgYhH+zP72MHiQEGoetnOHErNmf3zsQKKCfuLywJR4Ik/JmVN65jbPrrXi+EUKz7he5p6TdWUQPpxqxNzE1eH+ynYNc9VRmYgy5YlfffdDyS6+NMDUYPtq222BM0z/aXX9DHV1mCXeiX1Erc/79Cm/FNI41QY7mIBE4/QyGcaK2KSa/FT4tgmO1XiYTa4kAlyWoMKsq1OOr483ocjNtCPO9fjwjuGfsM0EIhxavpI/Zk25hbEG9i94WcmnKBNFseHBdFXhYCezNwEP7d7t32BwhpYmHXoh9xxDh4dqbPx95Y33qDM5McxoHD+zt10A95twVhSfca74w2Dr9Vk7NWo5aodiqCh1shqPPFV3lGqeRSBYgJknvsMW1RBrfHsAmmP0ly2OwGKKcpbx6pT1iubj4Lpi/OMiJ0uPLBzMXohcdrLNIid+z/+eAeZTNd9wEi7qcNcr9Tf+Ygz/vwbtweB0SMRcTxgLw9E=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Equality", 
		"option_b": "Meeting basic needs", 
		"option_c": "Economic growth", 
		"option_d": "Human happiness and well-being", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030154", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1xjp44oyQV7z1/i/OWLeCGcV42uMEqt9d3mjWK7Ea63tyIN4NFqIjk9y/XiZ4TMAfprcfe5tlZZwCzev/j4=", 
		"answer": "24a3a5jy3Vn+5ZAzRl7zy/m/NmTdDncfqmuaEDIho43kWlf4jiQE4tTZBzE=", 
		"explanation": "2//4W4Xh3hftt5YvURfzyb3tMGfRF2serWyLW7NnTH+pFIDNYem+wZJwK0iBsVUxsleGsKD+5FZPgK4b+ZuNYC0Qe8tmxpCF3uLy+H8Lc+BNlIF855MecLRTyT64Zt3POcJghC6mNUD1YzawRGR71DzXgXkWq4u0/CS+R+Y5ilUT1pRt/dgzLsOWz63T7UOujxSN0naURqkmYjjwsljniLUNDCBPM4CKxA==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Low stress lifestyles", 
		"option_b": "High social status", 
		"option_c": "Career success", 
		"option_d": "Social trust and community", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030155", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut6coRwrzy73vPGTeBmcD43KGU7BhYnjtU/iAJ7RMfHm8G7J8ER176CXxDw==", 
		"answer": "25KqZ4LgkTfr44wvXB/+hdX+JXvZDWcCsD0eQTCNfsylOraSKfc1iXND", 
		"explanation": "25ewfYXy31n6/oouVxvgwPm/IWPVQ2wetXqPEqB7fnLmRLOCYeu+xJJwNEmbhFV8sn7Jr6zj41oMz49J5p2MMAwCaoJgxtGFl8z21GFIPcNXicBm69oYaf1EyX29e9jSI/dr3S60L0DiYj+yFnU41CXeg28WoZD74S++FM85wRgwn4Bt4t0vMM7f2qeB+ki7kkaD0miGTa8mhLaEPoo7xSk3N7GoMki9Bg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Human Development Index", 
		"option_b": "GDP", 
		"option_c": "Sustainable Development Goals", 
		"option_d": "Gross National Happiness", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030156", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Raq/4wnWl76xO3vPGXVEHFRoHCWXLdmeXTwFKvLZei+7ZJ/Kl2bhhtv93jC47H/t1sOma0EqyUSzU0dUtusbpYez4TpdTI=", 
		"answer": "25CpfZD/2A3zt4QuVl71yvL7dWzfFWcDrX6NUaY2ZH1T0QFzuxuulLVhro/Fjw==", 
		"explanation": "252xb5mz2Rj654wuVw3hhf7wIGXEEWsUsD+PW6hxMFXmWqrDfOa+wZZnIhydiFV/93KGt6qw8l4fh6lI4JSaMCcSa4pjwcSQm6Tky3JIMsoEjYV+4psNebgAzTOpNNPUL/ouymuNKEbiZi20BzBzmyfTmHJXpoC+tSitUch3ygAhgsdx48szMdKMmZyb7V+9gAmQ2TfRXLVtAhSQpo6840bcrY0roY2MsjHO5vXtn7jQ+NECYQ1usbpxKRuPg7oG9i14Qse3YRNHsffRZ1H5OWitIhoOxcWpllUpzosuVSk48QlDjsNZZIBnxI33qA4+dY1LVSCusUtOwNRvWhmFcf231ijn71gyYHQicZNRsmd1gE+aJ1driSuTQmxGm5Jgs9wQkwEjf25MnXjjhwOFyiWuPJvm6ozojfGwt7Zx+eMiJ1eJJ1PWW4gScfGY5vRxJ54ToN6b19dCR22A", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "High average incomes", 
		"option_b": "Low unemployment", 
		"option_c": "High-tech industries", 
		"option_d": "Equality and good governance", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030157", 
		"question": "24KwcdH33lnv75UlQArhhe7qMmzVEHZRrnqCQbZmeX/kFKnDeuTxx5Z9Z1SInUty/HPVsPqy8NHQRfKf+mUMn/Ooe5ESrw==", 
		"answer": "24G3KJj31Bf+/oM5Eg39xvT+OSvZEHEEpmzDXKZxdHjtU+fBZuzwzpIzMF9WORO77udsitBuDPc2bQ==", 
		"explanation": "25CgeJThxQqq5JAnVRvh0b3yMGrDFnAYrXjDXKJgeX7tVauCZuzu2Z5/Ik+azVl+8XfTsKCw/kdPjKlVqYaafDJDboRjwdOQ2uX8wWNSc9JL2o1z759fePFDxS6ke9rIYOpmz3rAMEz8a3m0CWBmmyfTymhercOs8Cu3GdgyyRs11oh+rdw0Od6Nmaua/ESigwiRnFmICLBhEEeMp8em7AOUoZIovMOIoiGXtOT2lvHQ6dMKaQ1ArMZ8YlX8hK0MuD0wUNz0YQEL5uvCal3jJ2iiKQpd7sPiwjRg1cInUn14tB5IhsNCasVqlpvlsnI9PsZvVTK+qVFT05l5UQOFNKm3kHzs5VwtNWokaYNutSgm4Q6fK1tsnmKSSyBI1uoZYfgmhALtV5+VegY9k58=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "To benchmark against GDP", 
		"option_b": "To assess depression rates", 
		"option_c": "To guide public policy", 
		"option_d": "To identify social issues needing change", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030158", 
		"question": "2523f9H33hz5t6IyXQ3hhdP+IWLfDWMd41eCQrN9fnTwR+fHdv3/x5MxKFLJqn9LrTQqVV+OuRtnR1kuPxdF973R", 
		"answer": "25ehKJj90hb454oyUwr7y/q/O2TeTm8Qt3qRW6J4MGbmWKuPbOj3x5AzfWUrA7lOT1kEsE5Y+Iub2A==", 
		"explanation": "25KWQNH2yQnr+YEzEhH8hdrbBSvSGiIYrXyMQLN7YnD3XanFLuPxx9p8JkiMn1J6/jbHsLX19Eccz6ddqZmafC5OfI5mxtfJ2+38wTFCPMtJj4578INTPPdVwCm4ZtGXYPtg2GeSKEv9YjepRFdQpHHQhX9Du4aotS2uR853zxtym4Zs6No1Pdvf0KaQ50C9lUaD0n/RWK9rFUGaocen5QOoqIcqsMuCozeXtODxk+uT+c1LdgBX/4twcE/8lqsK7Tg5Rc30axpE+OfVIwVeUYLxuFLIDFrOgTW6XDc=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "By including sustainability", 
		"option_b": "By adding income equality", 
		"option_c": "By factoring in leisure time", 
		"option_d": "By incorporating non-material well-being", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030159", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Raq440lEh/n0fXwJ3iQAG0foHOWVqY0fnD3XajMfa3twZhkK1jJjFJ2smLJ47fx/kAKz7xT+4GKdypDboRjwdOA0veohngvW2UCZmJwqy/SfEkZ7Es=", 
		"answer": "24Wtap360ln98okmUwz3hfzxMSvYAnIBqnGGQbA2dC829Yj+cHKc/seDy2LONA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHyxA3i+JczEh39y/7zIG/VQ2wQt3aMXLA0Y3nsQavGLu7syJFlZ0ycj1dy8TbWrKn59FoKnOhd5o2KYycHPoRhiMOcxPD2zX9AMcpd2pJz7YkWcvMAxCigddqbN/tiyG+SIgXxaT39DHFkhDjYj29F5MO1+jP7Xs8k1FUhnohq+YUoOcWSma2Q50O3iw+BnHyDR6pwGRStvcu67kWTsod09dmFuCGb/ee5jvDWsNMEcRwSvIlyc0m5n60H6yMuVIi1ZgFc9PaSXIZFennfeGshwgCRjqX1jw==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "GDP growth", 
		"option_b": "Income equality", 
		"option_c": "Healthcare access", 
		"option_d": "Public welfare and happiness", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030160", 
		"question": "25S8bJj91lnj+ZYpVRbm1r35J2TdQ10unEC8EqB1fjHqWbfQYfv7iYd+K1WKlBt+9HDDoLH54VYBirtIq+atAkU8JY2M2ZBYQNG7Gik=", 
		"answer": "27e9YJDl2Bb49olgVx39y/LyPGjDQZZ4YK/d2rcenDS5q68fZdc=", 
		"explanation": "25y2e5j02Q35t4MyXROyx/j3NH3ZDHAQrz+GUax6f3zqV7SOLu/niYRlMliQhFV8snfFt7Dx+xMHmqVa586ddSoCaIJg2pzJ1OX5hHhMI9RLjIUy8JIaPPFGyjiuYN3NJfBr3X3AJkv0JzCwFHF3gHHZjDxGvYG3/CT7RNU7yRY7k5Q42cA5LtKZ1rqWpA2sjgPC3neQRrZ3UVWLsI6p6ECJsoMssMGU8TTS+Pj8nrq3aBMjofq8LMrAH5jlta8A", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "be,hav,io,ra,l e,co,no,mi,cs", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030161", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTDk84whXF7hxPP2IWrECm0f42+RXaRmcXyjV6jPbOTwzJMxJVmBjE1y/WSGqqvj/lQHm7sb/oeLeGIQaophzNGb06Tk0XNSOsJNn5My5ZQbPP1OyjK/edXPKfFgkSzxKfNOhsAbWkzJkMf3Ab+j", 
		"answer": "25a3ZZzm3xD+7sgMVxqy8fLrNGeQMGMfqmuCRqp7fjMsIWkIXEGfex92KHJI1bvl", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa3x3j9otgcTLG9r3vJ2TXEWMc43yMX6F9fnTnFK7MfeT5wYNiZ1qbglY78HPOorP5+EEOg+hI6oeafiEGPpxm3NjJxPD2ynVAIcIEiZVw95MbdfFTjDyjcJTSLvhhjnqPZ031ayn9FnVwgTLTynNGrY378SK9Udk21Bw9mMdM5c0uOdGQy63fqEKokg+N0juwCLR3UUCRsI6l5FCI4IM7ttifsCbetPX3ie/W4pz7tx4SNzFvr+juZwixKrY6", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Total Sanitation Campaign", 
		"option_b": "Clean India Mission", 
		"option_c": "Central Rural Sanitation Program", 
		"option_d": "Community-Led Total Sanitation", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030162", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRkGuCRqZ5dX/3FKbMaq3dxplyK0mahFR1qErIkLHx41YCiqZPs86yfzAGPo19zcGc0urjhHxIMNRLnIl85ZQcebRNyTi5fdrcM758y2qVJED0Jz24AnFhmCXFykBYi4y19iuuR9M4zk9yoYJ95sQlfNqa3Lya5kqrxgKH32mUSa5hFRSdsMip/k+Is8IusN+epCGb+fv3jvDf6ZymqhQObx69a/DDiYHK0cgD", 
		"answer": "24asaYX23Bzk48UpQV7m1+j6eSvzDGwSr2qQW6x6MHjwFLPQe+i8w5fMRLuVjJ48ILkUn+pACQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHgxRj+8oglXAqy0fX+ISvdDHAU43mRV7JhdX/3FKrLbf/xz55/JlKKiBt84HnTs+X98lYbhqZc+s6XdS4Te48v2tWNwufyhH1OMsgEnoV05Y8TaOcAxS7tYMbOJb5PwGrAM031JzqyCnN4gSLfhXIWvIu64WesUd88zAxym4J9+cEyO8TfyriW60S+jwWD0HeICLlhEkactN2t7wOYpYQ5oMGZonLY+/npm+rW9J4fbUhfsIhra1el16UM/T4xX8+nKBtYseXcclutNDq2Ik4p8c7x03Jm1IdlHWYk4BZJjMNyItd735vs/CEkPtlvBnO4rFBIh4R9TQOFNLyq1Sjw8kA6NXM4JZ5luW04rhyIaFV9mX6OTThU1INj8dkakEZ1IQUmpAEN5BjGXv9V8Oow", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Statement is false, Conclusion is false", 
		"option_b": "Statement is true, Conclusion is false", 
		"option_c": "Statement is false, Conclusion is true", 
		"option_d": "Statement is true, Conclusion is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030163", 
		"question": "24a3a5jy3Vnj84AuRhfmzPjsdWjRDSIZommGEqI0fnTkVbPLeOi+wJphJl+dzVR1skn5nJqw8EEAmrgb+YuNdi0Rc4phy9XLMxlnffF/SFez9NQCq+wp1g==", 
		"answer": "27i5epb63xjm/p8lVlx+Z06pX63/dOFPB9bnSqk5", 
		"explanation": "25CgfJT9whD88sUyVw33xO/8PSvYAnFRsHeMRa00Y37gXabOLuT6zJllLkiAiEg3snrPqKCw5VIMiuhU+86ccTEXe8cvy9GHl+ryw3BVOtBBlpky7ZcPffdUjC2oZtLUMvNvwG2FZ0r2JzS8Fnd9mjDag2ZTrMO85yiuRMl3wgxygpVx6s85Lt6R3uif4UCxkg+M2zuCXLh2FFuNrN6t+AOVrsIsvciEo3LW/fr9ibjn+NsZZw5drYMzI0+0kugL9Cs2Wtv0aQBOseXTYkH/ITymKxdd/8Lv2nFthBpI74WgMx6xJ8u7z+li6q8=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "mar,gi,na,li,zed", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030164", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kR/r9JEvQF77yO3+Nn/DQ2YUtXqPXbN5dX/3FKXHd+Lwzdd3Lk+KjFc74nnKqqb58kBQz5RVyM6sfyEKf4cvxt+b2ve3xX9Fc8VRlpRn9p9fXrRtwzOoYNXJOb5+wWKJJFyyQ5eGF4JLsQ22sIXf5qlWKA==", 
		"answer": "25T4W57w2Bjmt4svQBPhhfzxMSvTFm4Ftm2GEIpmLFFOO3rCJH6RVjSKhVI=", 
		"explanation": "25e9cZ791Vns/pYjUxKyxPP7dWbfDWcFom2aErN7fHjgXaLRIq3txpR4JlDJg1Rp/2WGoqv0t1Aag7xO+4vfeCMVe8tuxMOGl+bywX8BIM5LjY4y8JVfdfpGwCioetfeYP8uzWGVKVHifn6uRHV3mz/Zh3VV6Ie+4yK3W8o6xRsm1oZ26Yg7LtiIzaDT3EW9lAOE02mUBP1rAUCQusDoygOVs8IsvcjNvD3I4LT4mfvG4t8fZ0hTrJV6cU+1mKZLovnt1koRgco9KJQGxlZFmw==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "B Monetary policy", 
		"option_b": "Both A and B", 
		"option_c": "Neither A nor B", 
		"option_d": "A Social norms and culture", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030165", 
		"question": "24a3a5j2xRDv5MU3Wwr6he7rJ2TeBCIunEC8EqJ6dDH3RrLReq3qzJl1Z0iGzUt+4HDJsaiw9VYbm61JqYucfywMc4JsydyFzqaQp9dLCpK3HvHbkg3PES2D", 
		"answer": "2723ZpTgxQCoCS3wE1zL6wJJcWKGSsVSkw==", 
		"explanation": "25a3fZ/nwxDv5MUhXBqy1vL8PG7ECmcC42iKRqs0Y2XxW6nFLuXxx5JiM0XFzU9p52XS7+Xx+VdPnKdY4I+TMCEMdo58wd+Hl+z20nQBO89Xjo9g7ZkecPhZjCmoetDeJL56wS6QIlf2aCuwRHJxgCXTmDxTq4y1+iqyV9s7zAxyl5Q4+cA5L9LfzbqS4VmrxgOM3XmdTf1nHluJsNyp/0qTrsI5u8nNoSDU8+b8ieuTxNYOcA1UsJR6Lxuon61J+iY5X8OnKBNZ9KTRYlf4Mim3IgIEuc3q2nhswsA3w/yamQJKlbFCZc8VDUpj", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "ho,ne,sty", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030166", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kRr4/oglEgz3wej8IWLfDSIFq3qMQKpxYzH3W+fWZuj329d1Ik+Kn1Jr5n/JrbaqtVNpA4E5Awxa1ndC36nusIQ=", 
		"answer": "25eqZ5r231nd/oskXQnhhbC/A2LDCmAdpj+QW6R6YzHsUufGZ/7x25N0NRyFiFp/smLJ46z+9EEKjrte7c6cYisOe8cv+8Sb1u35hEVJNslWg8A/pLkNdflFjC+oZ8HXNO0uyHyPKgXyaza+D3Vw1D7GmnNEvJa1/DOyUcl3xhog1pRt7ss5L8TTmZuc60S5ikam1WieWrplH12DtNqh5E3clIo9ut+U8X+b1+bwl/2T+c1LbwdAusZzalC5m7FJ8SR4Qse3YRNH/f2QdFr+NCmhKwtd987q0XxryZAhUmYw51MGsIxDdsl909jlvyY5KcR+DHOuq0FP1Y08Elebe6mxxmnw5VF/enwtYIRpuT8m4UncO0F3jmqeQCkRgIF5+dUNhkRic2sAiH7lwj6Jk2CBf5aj5Ia8hungobtv9+MgPECSMVXZWJ5eXLX+7ylshKPCJL0hwJ58Wg==", 
		"explanation": "25eqZ5r231n9/oskXQnhhen3MGTCGjhRl3eKQeNgeHTsRr6Cffn/3ZJiZ0iBjE875H/Vqqf88hMchq9V+s6QdmIAbIJizZzJ1urjzTxSPMVNm4wy5p8XfeJJwy/hNNXVJL5tx3iJKwX0biqyFnRxhnHVmHlXvIb79Cn7Vc46zwYinoJq6IgoNNaLma2d60KtlAeF2WjRTqh2BVycp46r+UqRpcI5u8nNtTvI++b9n+qTxNYCcUhRvog/b169k+gd92o5Ecyxax5C/+GQaFqtIyeuKhsT8N/6lnlm1IMlWCk1+hsGg8NFZ85g09jrunI8PtpmECCprUFT1Ng8SB+fd7X402nqoFg+fn9rbJ4tsSInpE+YIVJ4k2iJQDgRgI8r/d8XgRZscS9Djn/thwOFvGu8c5Dq6oy8geHjr6tk860uM0CUPFPWFpkUYLzSPj0y/uGSHuZIO5poBTumLsEv6DzqYIKc3i1N08spInKn/TnZn8LnPCW2upn8gs02ALBAOdLG/Nn3uVKHYizsLGidb9/9XBuwW3T5x05kpR1lyykR+mPbHIxt/DcImj6yUAR3nSTpbXDhkrdP5ZCJfoA4yfT41D0e2MBwloi31xwyBw21jnNWtoHfSV1M2VvEDY0U0QomTLUSVIbe5GiEgW+cC2kDesPmDaeezilGzq+xj295/5YPWIWCNVnfg8003QelCPJ3FVPlrZX8ffoUCXAj6KExyeyv98e6fvbkJXFqaxOxX+Za5plFKAR0A0veCilCdbanQpQbUqBb3TXJmAlcVXBFRVne8qUNHQWkroTYfGXIarUZThHyc7wXB9v2R1PGMOLpzj/bRqaTgEm5H1QgQSqRJIwD2QnCdZnmLR2202ln7cjzO0VCBJcfOSjhbTH5kauKGEYudykqOpMHaVPUXxU31CrLJu0njrUJfR1tSLvnFF8Ek1FDljXXAkEFpENeUKauVUFnPaFALhsFxTKnFOAWT1zLxjkFgECZ0CXpJ/lOcUYlO3CbnUnl25RnnOvmkJ3bStntObQN05kGLPZUQpzTEV8ZiOCor/L1GHg4BGFybuzJTOXUpFy6Qsn6poPOzVkLyLwbM1E4IHmEj9/a8SpsLalKL3dfvGEdpcvccUae0YFKlV1tUVv/tVXsQHNhtQN6Y5arY86cJ5S39RBTHy/CW6ADjPM40i/nIM2RcxI6CSMhmQKCc5LL1THDLan00KEMRQ+q2NnKV48t+0F1wtW8xAxUpHt2gHHvAmKaYfXk5RtHbjxsSqaYH0lOxgMq1C7x30HtfY6+k7QIjaRIzrBT9QO3oTN/gleCTkbdLzPr0PLeuWmGsUkkiatxU3OtXzN5wUw0VvU993d6ADkpTOF3rr/4KfHCjG6ibpS53ZwI619aQZvEE7OYr9zxIOPVPaD63I6XJn3vsYdhFvq6ItZFJXjbbS8QqrPxbJDFYUmXOXiN1bXYWgi+EQV/pyMurmqHR1h4JWW8WdAdDSJThIdlY60Zpdqks1hscW+AGbBmmaMM20tLCUZcROjknDFPAbhmPJ2VdVFk8VFcHecQKn2/cFl/ZN1Km2a6VS695CexhrR6RN7l1RU5PwqDhzCAeGGc5ep/Lz/lVtaFz5iLB0WmqfImSFJF+bwSlAufRn8Df2htrRfIn6F7VxmPYR0hN+pSxM4cRtzk9jEGn9JnBQwUKXDWHjasH52EQ90CBJCxk7QuoJ9exj5RE5ACdIWMQFbelm2aCGdGZQJOb0OWhAO6rZZwlczBBxKB6G2mj8ftHVrQtXdA0pzmFMpS0VIpYYKW387yQ+Y1jPHkHmQMSdJc9XQbj2RaYmeZUkVoxLfgKSrZIACq6lo/94iehqNwmuqcxnOtPjEnSPUZR9FxhedQypD36bZXM98nMzhERRYX7SFDNspCyrXdRAg4bOGet2yuS9JwWSw2X1Ewjwe09bzx9o95RyD9va8SKnWAh5774a0nO0t6Fx6s+fgRubc8zOrWF2aQfjwL/rMWunGTdxvodAviuvCylQqNxnq6oZke2kNP05pBmrCfD1JM/mON2p4bzGm9Elos2N2gS+HbklGc0Yrstc2stvVYGff7X+qsxgOiTIEk57d2HzJxAuUH6MiJXDBzH5hUeiNdecPUe6NWy9z1O2LHwcT9fj+3bS3SJB9rBt04tmjIvOAHUCdKGfmBibciXJByV+erX0iE20Q2VlMrK4pLgBm5NtiIyAanUvDc6Q2hwawyutA90hsA5+k/fB1zMQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Broken Windows,Visible signs of disorder lead to increased crime", 
		"option_b": "Strain Theory,Crime results from blocked opportunities for success", 
		"option_c": "Social Disorganization Theory,Crime is more likely in socially unstable neighborhoods", 
		"option_d": "Routine activity theory , motivated offenders & suitable targets and the absence of capable guardians", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030167", 
		"question": "24K9ZJ2+3Bjj+ZEhWxD3wb3sJWrTBnFRpnGAXbZmcXbmFJj9UdK+y5J5JkqAgkk5Dxx5hC9lf/jAGwu24XFg6Q==", 
		"answer": "27CsYJjw0BWokiMSAcyfyjoU0WK/Khiixg==", 
		"explanation": "24K9ZJ2+1Rz5/oIuVxqyxPP7dWbRCmwFonaNV6c0cmTqWLOCa+PowIV+KVGMg09osn7HtaCw9VYKgehI4YGIfmIXcctqxtOGwvb2w3QBPslWn8B38JIWf/VMjDyjcJTLMvF9wW2JJkmwZTy1BWZ9myOWg3IWuIa05Su+FO4/xQc3kIhq6IR8KN+amaqf6UOzxg+RnHqSS6h2EECcudfo7UqQrIc895hrAHmfeGRe20e6aZs5YK8=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "eth,ic,al", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030168", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRkGuCRqZ5dX/3FKbMaq3dxplyK0mahFR1qErIkLHx41YCiqZPs867dS4Ld8tizcSb2KTlzXVEIdUEnoV/65QMaOZB2DjtcdrNKexhwGOFKVG3dHm0CnZ4gTTYiXkWp4379ii1UM801FUOmKR348swKcSW1qbJqGS1lhSNyn6VCLhqB12LusCl7k2Is8IxuN2Msiab9vHxm+7a/8xJdJDfb6uQEr3/bS6Fosl5PQ==", 
		"answer": "24asaYX23Bzk48UpQV7m1+j6eSvzDGwSr2qQW6x6MHjwFLPQe+i8w5fMRLuVjJ48ILkUn+pACQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHgxRj+8oglXAqy0fX+ISvEC2dRrG2HV7F4aTHgW6nGe+7qiZh3Z3iMgVNysnvDt7f/t0EGi61J+s6bdS8McJh72tGd0ve30HlEc8NKjIlg65QSefpUiy7tfdrdLOtrwG2FZ0r+Jzu4DHFinT7EynVF6Jep4CL7ddQzgAE6k8d74sY/MMKM0KedqFmwhxLC1XaBWrJyFFDZsMC+4lGTro89u9me8SHT9eT82ujc49cfax5X/4VwbV+plLxJ8Tl4UMSnZ1Jd8OjZZRTZKC2xIggS686vlnt50osmUykQtAhOi4BeItNn14zhr3IyMNliVSO7sVBTh5VuWleCZqi9kGH3oEE3cDomapl5/Cw2ohqOKUB72miUQyVSkcI/5kNoN0we82aoYvZ8gKNw", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Statement is false, Conclusion is false", 
		"option_b": "Statement is true, Conclusion is false", 
		"option_c": "Statement is false, Conclusion is true", 
		"option_d": "Statement is true, Conclusion is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030169", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0Avvt5UyXVPhyv72NGeQAWcZommKXbZmMHDtUOfPYf//xZ5lPhyInkh08X/Ht6D0t0QGm6AEq1saLAni7VGKAagPRX02FNU=", 
		"answer": "25y2ZpDn1Fn++MUoRxPzy73xNH/FEWdT6SxLguIDSRLJHxwfGYcZ1g==", 
		"explanation": "24WqZ9zg3hrj9olgUBv6xOv2OnmQAmwV43aNXKJgdTHuW7XDYuTq0NdwNVnJjlR14X/Cprf18xMNluhe8Z6aYjYQPp9giNKMl+35zHRTNshQ2pR9pJIKcfVOjDOsYMHJJb58z3qIIlewczG8CjB4kTDEhHlS6IG+/SatXdUl01U9hMdr4ss1Pdvf2qed+1mqkwWWzzuQRLJqFBStvcu67kWTsod09dmFtHLZ+PX3kbja454KYQtHrYdrZlel164A9CY9VYqIfbaVIDTL0Uv/oBR5W5O6", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Learned behaviors", 
		"option_b": "Social constructs", 
		"option_c": "Against human nature", 
		"option_d": "Innate to human nature", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030170", 
		"question": "25SrKIH2w1n+/4BgVwbiwO/rJieQFGoYoHfDXaU0ZHnmFKHNYuHx3p5/IByZhV51/XvDrar+t1EGgaxIqZ2QcysGapIwihUFG3M/Tdm1xJK1miZGiDc=", 
		"answer": "2523ZpTgxQCq9oskEgrg0O7reSv5DXYUpG2KRro24Pq7Ii7K8LZV3lyR2eMXKg==", 
		"explanation": "25S7a57h1RDk8MU0XV7gwO76NHnTCy5RpX6ARqxmYzHvXazHLuXxx5JiM0XFzVJ15nPBsazk7hMOgawb4ICLdTATe5l8x96I26Tj1mRSJ4ZUloFrpJtfav1UzTHtZtvXJb5nwC6CLkv0bje6RGN7lzjTnmUWqpr78Cm6VtY+zhJylYh3/c0uPcOW1qbT3EW9lAOE02mUBP1mHkCR9d6p+VeP4I0+9dmFtHLa5+f8iOza/9BLYxpX/4VwcUm5lLxLQWRCq7edS6YqOGEdg/O82g==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Regulations, Shared interests", 
		"option_b": "Social hierarchy, Laws", 
		"option_c": "Vision, Goals", 
		"option_d": "Honesty and trust, Integrity", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030171", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MU3Vx/5hf7wO3/CAmEF42yaQbdxfTHrVbXPfbK8Y/79IFbDMFegb8JEvxugAg==", 
		"answer": "25i5epr2xVnu8pMlXhHiyPjxISkNxZZY15nAVZLFeYo+gVKO", 
		"explanation": "24K9aZqz0hbk45chUQqy1uTsIW7dECIQrXvDQqx7YjHxQavHLuL4iZtwMBycg19+4HvPraCw+lIdhK1PqYqaZicPcZtizd6dl+buhHVIIMVLj5Jz45MRe7RJwiuoZ8DWJfB6jm+OIwXkdTizF3F3gDjZhG8Wqoav4iK+Wpon0hwkl5N9rdg9LsOW3LvT3EW9lAOE02mUBP1wGVHZt8Kp5UjcqZF4tM6OpCDa4PH1g7jV+dIHZwwQJ279E97jbkRAaGWDx650aQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Investment", 
		"option_b": "Economic stability", 
		"option_c": "Productivity", 
		"option_d": "Market development", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030172", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yKQQ0sJCLwOeariVtFQb90Ozk=", 
		"answer": "25mxfJTh0Brzt8hgcBvm0fjtdXvfD2sSqnqQHuNGdXLsU6nLdOTwztdnJlCciEg7+3vWoqbktx5PrKlP6IKGaidDboR8wcSAweG3x3lAPcFB1sBC65YWaP1DzTHtZNXJNPdtx36BM0z/aXnwREB1hiXfiXVGqZe+tS61FN041hAgmIZ27s1wfP+eybia5kirlUbPnFy/YP+MRdn/1/EF6P+E5FsYlJrB", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHw3gv48oY0EhPz0f73dXjYDHUC43CTRqp7fjHKGOfOZ/n725ZyPhyBiFdr+3jB46b541oViqZIqYqafSMNesttzcSd0va3wHRXNspLio136o4ecLRQwzGkd93eM75o3GGNZ0L/cTyvCn1xmiWWq3JS6Iyr4S60Wpoe6VlyhIJ74s8yNc2W16/T/ky0kwORmzuYRa1lEkDZts+86k+Fuos2so2dviHS4P3vn7jA/90CYwQSvI5+bVy516oQuCkwUMazYRxMsebVbV3oJjvjEwYY687l2WZsisI9VWAntBBWlopZbIB+14zntDcjf8BlBif6okdD0oZ9SxKabf8yFzIZCRPH4+oYCvXqSRMa", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Literacy,Better policies", 
		"option_b": "Recognizing values' impact,Catalyze positive change", 
		"option_c": "Political participation,Participate in governance", 
		"option_d": "Happiness,GNH", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030173", 
		"question": "2523f9Hw0Beq54AvQhL3hf7+IWrcGngU42+MQapgeWfmFLTNbeT/xddyL12Hil4ksKHGh6Z1If9JvvNzl25mOaY=", 
		"answer": "25ehKIP20hbt+Yw6WxD1hev+OX7VECVRqnKTU6BgMH7tFKPHeOjyxod8IlKdz/HHj7sFdrVIlQllEZtO5VQ=", 
		"explanation": "24e9a5703xDw/osnEhbnyPzxdX3RD3cUsDjDW655dX/wUefLY/3/yoMxKFLJjBt4/WPIt7fpsEBPi61N7IKQYC8GcJ8v3MKI3eH00H5TKoZHm44y55sLffhZ1jjtZNvIKepn2GvANErzbjixRHN8lT/RjzxUscO4/Sa1U9M5x1UhmYRx6Nw9MJed3KSa7UurxgeM2DufR69pAhStvcu67kWTsod09dmFuCGb/ee5jvDWsNMEcRwSvoV8dkm9g61J+SQrRs2mKqbGnxK7B5HiKncmYd5qRRw=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Through political participation", 
		"option_b": "Via entrepreneurship", 
		"option_c": "By developing new technologies", 
		"option_d": "By recognizing values' impact on development", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030174", 
		"question": "2523f9Hw0Beq+4w0VwzzxuS/PW7cEyIYrm+RXbVxMGHsWK7BZ+jtltXElDLCGHBSc6y4s29e2L89", 
		"answer": "25ehKJT90Bvm/osnEg73yu3zMCvEDCIVpnKCXKc0cnT3QKLQLuLwzIQzGRd0XZCJw+BOywUshNqJgw==", 
		"explanation": "25mxfJTh0Brzt4YhXF73yO3wIm7CQ3IUrG+PV+NgfzHgRq7WZ+7/xZtoZ1mfjFdu82LD46L/4VYdgaVe55rfYC0Pd4hmzcPJ1urzhHVEPsdKnsB/64gaPPFR2TS5ddbXJbIuy2iGIkbkbi+4RH96kSKWjHNE6Ie+4yK3W8o6xRsm1rNw6No5OtiN3OTT/EWxlUaLzzuFQLgkHFuKoY6r5E6MsocwsMOeuCTetPX3ie/W4p4IagdbvIM9TUEB7TX2nypzLUdOuONcwQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "By increasing fiscal discipline", 
		"option_b": "By promoting financial inclusion", 
		"option_c": "By accelerating economic growth", 
		"option_d": "By enabling people to demand better ones", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030175", 
		"question": "24GwbdHG/z3auoElQRf1y/j7dUP0MSIGomzDR7d9fHj5UaOCbPS+3Z90Z2uGn1d/slTHra6w41xPjqRX5o2eZCdDQbRQ9++26Nu3wmRPN9UEjo8y6Z8SfvFSjD6iYdrPMvdr3Swg0QH/sGZPyRLuMIboSrUZ", 
		"answer": "27KqaZ/nk1S+yyM3OV9QvX916LrP5yc=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHE3gvm88UCUxD5hfTsdWreQ2sft3qRXKJgeX7tVauCaOTwyJlyLl2FzVJ14WLPt7Dk/lwBz7xT6JrfYDAMaIJrzcPJ2+v2ymIBMshA2odg5ZQLb7RUw32pccLeLPF+x2CHZ0b/cjepFnlxh3HignkWn4yp+SP7dts5y1UnhYJrrcl8KtaN0K2H8Q23gEaBznKFTa9tEBSNuo6s7leZso8xu8jNpjrS9/y5mffG/soZaw1B/4dtZhu5m6EO8Sg0VIiyZwAL9/HeZV3jJ2TjLgAe9d7n33puhpYhWCk3+wpIlpFPJdMz/rzNgDwMMfliEHOSh20Azoc8XleVe7Co33vt9FB/fHQvYJItqCU0tU+RLVVtj3mZX2xQ1INk694Nhx0kbi9MmWDljn+EhiWHaZ7i5cD4gP71rLZz/6YpPQGpIRzRRc0fZL/DMmtz3uyfTbNPOpFgVzbuL9ArvDD3JJ+X3i0Cwsp6b3vu8i/Zl9XlPGauspz6l5g2EbsVNdDR4MS5/BzGbyehKHOQacbxGSv/WnLswQdgpFgywTUYqGOYAIB4/Sgf3laUYARlgCKgb3OvhbdY75CLe84l3LXu2HIdl+Z935/ywhgwSBS+iUNNjoqrR1kP+lvEEslH5gggB/QUB5PCsnmekDb4b1VNa8G2CKyCzThB3PqxjW5osYQcXImdbA3Ti8pmyQW0QfR3FWnorYK5MvpVDmE6/75+2uCkud77dOC3JXY+bhS0XK9t+5ARSgN1GkvfAChGZa6rRd0KSeFbknbFgglcVXZMFhrb8rwAHQXqpsvfLkL6SvEdHBuibrwXFo70R0zKOejp3D+JA6eMkFW3WkomS3qNLqYI9xPpNsz6MR20lnooucDrNhFfTZASPTT2SGWFq5eLDkYNcD4pLMple0neCwA2myjKI/x0zaAScRY5UuizFhAVmQRBiyzbC0sFpENeV6ChUBMzIqxIYFIc3SW6B6VfSBTPjyhKhkORwyysLf9dNEUsa2mWgVigr5pjjPqphZyABMDxbb4a3M0BLfZOV5/SX08T2vXx4eWgAX42DGh0OuuIV+yRtUvjAcngq8zUiRxDzL8EIld3ZTCFj43Y4y5/OqZbemJP8TMYos6SbRKi3JoZ1EJtUUauXByhZwwPgGRMm0b9Mf4kRw==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "", 
		"option_a": "gra,nt,et,ri", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "030176", 
		"question": "24GwbdHw3hfp8pU0EhH0hdrtOnjDQ0wQt3aMXKJ4MFniRLfLYOjt2tc5AHKhxBty/HXKtqH15BMwsJdk1rGgT2IFf4h7x8Kal+X7y39Gc9FNjogy6ZsLeeZJzTHte9reM7zlBkn/EheJaYfS7ye9IAHO", 
		"answer": "27uxZpSxggWpYHNl+g431KazwaSELQ==", 
		"explanation": "25KqZ4LgkTfr44wvXB/+hdX+JXvZDWcCsD+KQeN1MHzmVbTXfOi+xpExM1SMzUx+/nqLoaD5+VRPgK4b6M6cfzcNapl2j8PJ1O3jzWtEPdUEs5Qy85sMPPBF2jihe8TeJL5nwC6iL1DkZjf9DX40gDnTyi0P/9OotSaoFNs5gBQ+goJq48koNcGambycqGqqiRWRnF+eRbh3BV2a9f665EeJo5Z4/eqpgXuXtOPxk/vbsNcYIgkSsoN+cE6ukugG/mo5Ecu7fRxf4/2XchToIyetKAMU+ovsw2B505YVU1U60zFuwopFIsJyxZ3g/D0+f9liEHO4pkhJwpI8Sx+XYP2w0Xj06Vs6ZmlrbJktsSInpE+VJURxiH+dQjgRgIhq8JAUlBBmb2ZBkDb3hz6HlG3PVYej4o7/if30paoj/KopLAGEOlHZX4MPJbzGZ3B3xuXWD6NVPZg9KyzWNcw99Tr4LNac2jgBxNEcIVri+j6Yno39PGS2p5rFgOB/GbpAI8LA1cWStEnEYDfoLnOvaO75SQT/VnH93RpZuTsqxSwF5mvMEclp/DkMknekUHhqsTLseGmzl7Ic7ouYepwi2uH1nTMenLRqmoj+2BQ5SQe+sXFvu5KWQVsP3kDXEMkG1g09MLomG5nVsmqZg3PCRX0DfMvKD42EzCBH3eryj209u5kYUJ6dJQ3Cyt8ozFejBO5wWW7opoX8fwJP2M8rDEi/aKlJhDYJ3lM=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics  >> Growth, Development & Happiness  >> Intro to Value of Economics", 
		"difficulty_level": "", 
		"option_a": "ni,ne,ei,ght", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040101", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17by/n2NGWQJmEerXCOS+N3eHDxVaTWa//305J1Z16QzVpvsmLOpuXk/l4Kz6ddqaeLNzFDd4VrzcCM2eDyynJEbIRmmSh1EnRSvAVTtPk3fNnI", 
		"answer": "24aseoTwxQz49olgVhfh0fLtIWLfDXFRqnHDU6RmeXL2WLPXfOi+yJl1Z1WHiU5o5mTf4YLU46GhyibdQf6YK9cKZy4=", 
		"explanation": "25SsKIX71Fn+/oglEhH0hfTxMW7ABmwVpnGAV+N9fjGyDfOVIq3Xx5N4JhuazV54/XjJrryw4FIcz6tT6JyeczYGbIJ1zdTJ1f23yXBLPNQEiZRg8ZkLaeZBwH2pfcfPL+x6x2GONAX5aXm/C2R81DDRmHVVvY+v4DW+FNs5xFU7mINt/twuJZeM3KuH51+rxi+MnHqWWrRnBFiNoNytpwOQoYw89dmIvyfJ8bTqg+vH9dMYIh9XrYM/ZkOsm6cA7CssWN6xKBNF9aTCZEf4LDymI04U94vq2GBs1I8sWWA15hZDkcNFd8N7lpn3/CgxMsRkETKosARByZA8UhiYcaT43G3q5FAtZjoufZ5/vS4hqAGbaFlrmWPcQyoRgIhuvsMMhxRvaHwAtXjklyyfknzPa5Lwq4TziOH+oa1m9uMlMAGGOk7dX4oSJbrOM2Jgz/qPHuZdPZsnGiPvM9k3vCr8MoCR23kO39UvIX7m+GqWkMfwOnGzpZfqzsZ3ALcFJJHR4cq58FLSczf0M3jTYsT5XBvkRn+41gBxpR012iQe7XfKG4F25W0CjD69TEFw0ivvb32t1rBZ74adP7o51rXp3j0el/lh35f21xY5Q0S/hGlGoJeWW0UPzFrSXt4CyA9jHrENHZff8WjWoX7VWXkLcNzzTeiTyykI2+3imWRv/5kdFb+aPgzYnss0yRvxBfRqQWj/vI/2M+9VA2ps+7Vjw+60u96uZ/bkLWsuLxO5XfpK54dIKvKz0xh6yUHwZhBoUpm0XRo=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Robust growth", 
		"option_b": "Low inequality", 
		"option_c": "Advanced infrastructure", 
		"option_d": "Structural distortions in agriculture and industry", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040102", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t4RgXx/4yu+/PGbAAmEF43CFEoFmeWXqR6+CbeLyxpl4JlDJn0539zbJreXZ+VcGju9IqYucfywMc5IwigVGJ9BnPmbHQxoRaswzybk=", 
		"answer": "24C2YZ3yxRz49olgRgzzy+75MHmQDGRRtHqCXrd8MGXsFIXQZ/n/wJkzX9Brq/mn1hQ1nRDyXlQ/8w==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH20hbk+IgpUV77yO3+Nn+QDGRRs22MXqx6d3TnFIXQZ/n32p8xJFOFglVy83qGsbD88hMYjrsb5Y+NdycPZ8tq0MCF2O3jxWVIJcMEk44y6psLaeZFjA2ieN3YKft9jnmFNUCwYzyuDXd6kTWWnnMWu4ap4yL7XdcnxQc7l4s45MYoOcWayryAqF+5kg6HzjuFQLxqUUSLusOn/0bcpIcusMGCoT/e+uC5k/aT2dAPawkSi456cV78gKkauDkxVsa9bhtI8OrEIUHjKSSiMwsP+MejwmZoyJEvWHt0+xkGlYZXbtR7lp72sz9wFsNuHDL6t0sA5YZ1Sxafev2x3ijw6FB/c3U5aMpium0npBmZJkF7iSfcXi1G1I1q6tULnAVvbiMAjGTvhDafkyWKaJCjwo74jO/1rrZ24eMuJ0WVJkjKT80OYLDFLnF3zqmXBLJIP5onBDbnKdBu7yzpMJmGy3kM3t1gInjj8TiX0srnNnKuu9Luj8c2GLYNP8XA7YuUv1DIbyrgLT2Bc8fxGQn8XHO43wth9wwqiDUY7SLNBot++SwDnXe+TgRrlGf0ZHnhgqxd7ouadoE/0vms2DEflvt1htvD3BguQgK0n3oP8pCXShxCzF7ZDI0OyRkvD6BBA5fCsliYnHrRX3kffsK2FbqGzT9O3/GxgWc9qJUPWZiGbA3Uyvw0wQOwCPM7lLaV39MHGXy4wxMuhZHLnA==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "High GDP growth", 
		"option_b": "Industrialization", 
		"option_c": "Agricultural modernization", 
		"option_d": "Unilateral transfer of wealth to Britain", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040103", 
		"question": "25Gtepj91lnp+IkvXBfzyb3tIGfVTyIzsXaXU6p6MGHxVaTWZ+77zdd0JFOHglZy8TbWrKn59FoKnOhS5862fiYKf8t7wNGd6NvI+05+ceM8kLPEgZYVWnAuamvgv64=", 
		"answer": "25y1eJT31B2q84A2VxL91fD6O3+SsfQIiEMhJMOn3lwEbi047g==", 
		"explanation": "24C2bJThkRrl+4ouWx/+he/qOW6cQ0ADqmuKQas0dXLsWqjPZ+6+2Zh9Ll+AiEg75XPUpuX08kAGiKZe7c6Lf2IOf5NmxdmT0qT+yWFEIc9FlsB76o4abvFT2C7tZtXPKPt8jnqIJkuwdyuyCX9gkXHfhHhfr4a1+jKoFN4y1hA+mZd16MYofN6RmYGd7ES5xiWN0HSfQbxoUUSWucer4kaP4IQ3ttietDab+/q5n+DH4t8IdgFcuMZWbV+1lu8auD09UMSgYFJZ8PDYZEatNCCiKU4U993mxWBgyIVpVGd0/QtVwoZVbc5824Gklzcpf95vFie1sVcAy513WlebdbOt1mnn9EAtfHQsJYtjuG08rwmOKUdqiH6fWDlDkcB5+9McnBJmeS9MlXvpljqPwHabfYfmq5Pplfj/sq0j860jaUeBNlncFokVdrDSLmp7xOiPArRFc49oGyvlNNA9vBbvJYSV0zVBkNovI3jp/SuV0t36NWy5upfqzt14HLYCP8XA7Yu2vliHZSryNXKBcs7wGQ3zQHL33gdm9xwg3iQc53LVDYdrtSQD3le+TU1l0hPoaW6kkLFO787OfIE93Pvl3D5QiuF0mtve2Q05QwG/zXtGpIGTQExCyFrCXGYsQERqb0uGtySqHr7zc7w=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Im,pem,de,d d,ev,el,op,me,nt", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040104", 
		"question": "24KwcdH32B2q3oskWx+yzfzpMCvcDHVRr3aXV7F1c2ijVanGLuH3z5IxIkSZiFhv83jFuuXx4xMGgaxe+YuRdCcNfY4wiu7gZdj0IdwpLR3EAIt43lE=", 
		"answer": "25u9b5320g2q+INgQRHxzPzzdXjVAHYesT+WXKdxYjHBRq7WZ/72iYVkK1nLOTeoQY1IB6dnPqAFmel+GA==", 
		"explanation": "25SsKJj91Rz68oskVxDxwL32OyuBWjZG7z+qXKd9cTHrVaOCauTtxJZ9Z0+GjlJ6/jbPraH59FIbgLpIqYKWeydDcoJ7zcKI1P23xX9Fc8pNnIUy4YIPefdUzTOubZTvKPd9jnmBNAXxJz20FnV3gHHEj29DpJf7+iH7RMg4zBo8kYJ8rcY5O9ua2rzT50v4jwiU2WiFRbhqBRSQu46g/k6drsI8sNuIvT3L+fH3jrjG/toOcEhwrY9raki016sG9CU2WMm4KABe/eGQVVzoYCusKwET8MrvlnNm0Ic7U2Qx+gsGkZNTbNQzwJ32pXI8Ntl+GTb6rEoAwpBpXBaCfbK2nCjs5VQzYXIoZJho8G0moAGVPFVqk2SSDC1fkMBk6tgch0Ribn9Fn2LzwiuDgXHPdZ7z6oPoxeDlrbhtsqciP0SMOkzVU4MIJYfIIidhxeqSDKocIJpkAy30fcIv73n4YJqbyHkdwtAvPX7z7WqQnI32Nmm1vZv4gpRzF7AOOdzM6ounv1DOYjqhFXWWdM7yVhr1Azzs2wslpR0k2y4eqGTXGslz+jpNknekTFZlkT6gbXKl1rJV7IfOepYh1vb43DwTgbRvnoi3+hg7SwG4mT9MtMSMQF9GzFiWDcgE0AY8TKEPEJPDsk+EnGLZWHRNbdv6BOo9UGuT4MeV8TKte0VJidrm", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "High poverty", 
		"option_b": "Lack of schools and hospitals", 
		"option_c": "Social inequalities", 
		"option_d": "Neglect of social sector under British rule", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040105", 
		"question": "25y2bJTj1Bfu8os0Ejf8wfT+dWTAF2cV43mMQON9fnX2R7PQd63syIN5Ik7JmVN6/DbHpLf59EYDm71J7M6eY2IKapgv2MKA2uG3yX5XOshD2oZ99pkaPPBF3y2kYNGBYpe1PLAHoxjVTKpudoJiuDA=", 
		"answer": "25m5a5r63x6q55clQBvj0PTsPH/VECIdqnSGEqp6dmPiR7PQe+7q3IV0ZcI17HKCrBDj80Cx9zlkOCk=", 
		"explanation": "25S+fJThkRDk84AwVxD2wPP8MCeQKmwVqn7DVKxmfXDvWL6CYf3qzJMxIVObzVJ19mPVt7f59l8GlalP4IGRMC4Gestt0ZCIl/fj1n5PNIZUj4J+7Zlfb/FD2DK/NNXIYOpmyy6QNUz9YnmwC2Z9mjaWjHNEq4b7+iH7Udk4zho/n4Q46tozK8OXleiX7V6ojxKHnHeQS7ZtH1PZuMG7/wOTpsIsvcjNoSDe5vHoj/HA+coOcUhnsYp2aF78tKAA9it0EeG6bBtKseDZZRTjLzzjLw8L/Ivww3Jvz4EgWGcgtB5BkIpVd8xnw4rlsHIjKt96GSap40tSh51yWQWXZ6mqxWvw9Uc6NW4kJYNjqigmtU+VJhR3lG+JXzhDnYFn98oYgQ1scy9iiWKgkjCHiWaWcZLo7pLvxfvxt/lq/KcyOlWSLBzZRc0IbbaAN2Zmwv6aFOZIPN9qGCbjL9sn5jjtKZmanxAD1NAhb3vm9yGclo38N2OosoHtnMF1AKoSM5HV+86ltU3SaDDoNXiAJtLxTUjzR3Pr1k5suRww2zUC8SLXHoxttSwKjHezXEhwhzXlLEipk6xZ7I2cesJxx/3pnTMei+N9jdv+x10QRgewhHFE8pSNSk5K3EHfDcQTwRpuAL0KEdbY/GuElGXEWWkOa9vkBOqTb08+mNrQCxZOSgb9xMzQ", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Sufficient foreign reserves", 
		"option_b": "Adequate technology", 
		"option_c": "Favorable policies", 
		"option_d": "Lacking prerequisites like infrastructure", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040106", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kR/r9JEvQF70xOvwJ27UQ0sfp3aCEqJwf2H3XanFLuz5255yMlCdmEl+snfV47H48hMfnaFW7M6SfzQKcIwvzt+b1OGohtLkU1h+7Lm9saIZDKKGFQk=", 
		"answer": "24WqbYL23xrvt4omEhj31+n2OW6QAHcdt3aVU6F4dTHvVanGLLwIVmeiP+6q3A3oVhmWrXE=", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJjykRj+t4wuVhviwPP7MGXTBiIGomzDV61wf2bmUOfVZ/n2iZJpM1mHnlJt9zbAprfk/l8Kz6Ra54rfcSwHPoNuzJCIl+j21nZEc8dDiIlx8ZYLaeZBwH29e8TOLP96x2GOZ1L5czH9AnFmmTjYjTxTsJO+5y6+WtkyjFU/l4xx4898PdCN0KuG5FmtlAPC3TuHQbxmHVHZpdyh5kbcrY0uvMOK8TTU5vf82s/a5NZLcR1Cr4ltd1KqkugZ9yYxUsGxe14L8OPCaFf4LDy2NQtd+sT22nApwYcnWHs14BoGkZZEcsxmxZ33/DQ/LY14EDq0tUFT05l5UQPWfbP42Wbg9UYrZ2NrZIRp/CQ7px2dO0Bsj2iIWT5U1KllvtMWmxBxfHxU0DbJjDuCgSWDfZDo7oS8lfr1srxy56o0IFWFJhzUX4YZJbDBN25my+XXTbVXOpNrBGLnM9Fu6Dz6KJib0zYKyZkmIGWn5iuJm8m1MGu+poHtnN13GLYaN8XM5sX3uVHKZCfoIGmWatK0bQD1XXn+3Bxg+1gxwCRQ+HDdG4xx9ihNkXjwT0F2hi7saTyig7JI45SPfYI0k/nt0zZQvvVukIny0F09QBayjmpPppGNShxO3hTCFshH1BsnAbFBGZnH+2OR1XDfWX8IPcHr+Doa0Uew4IagGl1ZslU=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Strong industrial base", 
		"option_b": "Advanced infrastructure", 
		"option_c": "Skilled manpower", 
		"option_d": "Presence of fertile cultivable land", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040107", 
		"question": "25S+fJThkRDk84AwVxD2wPP8MCeQAmUDqnyWXrdhYnSjQ6bRLv77zJkxJk/JjBto+3HI46r2yGwwsJdk1rHdPRKHae9VgrlYZHcZtCpN7Q==", 
		"answer": "25e5a5rk0Avu+YAzQVwcUbkdhxAMRTZlWi8RQBrM", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71Fnk9pEpXRDzyfTsISveAnADomuKRKY0cXf3UbWCZ+P6zId0KViMg1h+vjbHpLf59EYDm71J7M6IcTFDbY5qxpCIxKT1xXJKJMdWnsBz6p5fdfpE2S65Zs2bN/99jniJIlL1Y3m8FzBgnDSWjm5fvoaptSi9FNc4xBAgmMdo/8c7LtKMyuij50GxhR+P3XCUWq4kBlWXocusq1GdsIs89cSDtSfI4Obwm/Ta6t8fawdc/5JwI1i9g6sBuD8oEd+9fBoL8ODGYFruJSzjIg0S98Tu33F6hqMuT2A34RNSl5FTItdyxdjqsyZwL99jGiGzt01awpA8WwKTNKm3kHzs5RUvcGgoYJp5tSI74RuUKUA+k3/cXilBhoV4+94NkAAjf25Dl2HhkDuFhXacPKfr7pL5g+fipfUj86Q1IEKVOUjNRIhccrLTZ3R3z+fbDLUcMt90HiXofdoovBv4I52D3isJ3twzPDfm8j6cgI38N2G/o5f3itF4F7pCwx+FmzlTcHzzMfESgPDdtg==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ba,ck,wa,rd,ne,ss", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040108", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Rzm54AkEj36zPP+dWLeB3cCt22KU699anSjVaHWa/++yJN+N0iAg1w783HUqqbl+0cana0b6J3fZCoGPpt9wd2Ml+n40nhPNIZClZJx4cVdHbEtqUf7O+Uh1R6vEeVGcg==", 
		"answer": "25S/epjwxBX+4pchXl7h0O/vOX7DQ2sftXqQRqZwMHjtFLfQa//72IJ4NFWdiEg5DqmKbFYaJbBGD1nX9INhVA==", 
		"explanation": "25awYZ/ykR/j5ZY0Ehj9xujsMG+QDGxRoniRW6BhfGX2RqbOLv/7z5hjKk/JhFU75n7D46z+/kcGjqQb7YuccSYGbctuzsSMxaT0y3xMJshNiY0y0JIWb7RHyTOoZtXPJfou3XuSN0nldDyuRGd8nTLeymtTuob74S++Wpo+zgM3hZN96Yg1MsOQmayW/ki0iRaL0nzRQbNgBEeNp8ep5wOVroQqtN6ZoyfY4OHrn7jS/tpLcQNbs4psI2iz16kO6iM7RMSgfQBK/aTDdEb9LD2wZwsT+Mnv03Ap0oosHXkm8Q1Dk5Zfccln04ukuj0if95/FyC/slFFyYA8VhmSYa6swmHl7FwldG4iaoQtlSN1ogCSPEZ/iX/QDAVfkIlqvtwYlg9meS9Bm2TpgSqHlHCdfZ+j+JXuleTls/l3/eMuJ1eFJkiYX4NcbL3EMnRm2PDbOa5ZIZphGDDjcZUP+yvwI4OYyywf0dVgPGL15CaMgY38N3O/oIb8ipR/Gv8QJNTX7NqiuU/OdSbyYXWWatvxXUjTR3X20k5suRww2zUC4WPUAZN6t/FsCOdtYsMYXJZ+KcKk9wU=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Central planning", 
		"option_b": "Foreign direct investment", 
		"option_c": "Export promotion", 
		"option_d": "Agricultural surplus invested in prerequisites", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040109", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut6wuVhfzhfvwJ2bRD24I436HXbNgMHDkRq7Be+Hq3IV0Z12azU9z9zbWsaz98hMCgL5S54nfdi0RfY4winpK1ut8+HQtRraHcQUrdPA=", 
		"answer": "25y2KMOjgUuq85AyWxD1hen3MCuBU3YZ41mKRKY0SXTiRufyYuzwi4Vyr0pLgh8H62fA3JMUUEs=", 
		"explanation": "25ysKIbywlnl+Yk5Ehf8ha+vZTmQB3cDqnGEErd8dTGyBLPKLsv335IxHlmInxtL/nfI47H49kdPpqZf4I/fdi0Rc4pjxMnJ1uD41GVEN4ZFnZJ7548TaOFSyX2sZ5TPKPsu3nyJKkCwajarDX5z1DfZmH9T6Iy9tSK4W9Q4zRwx1oBq4t8oNJvf1r6W+g2+jxCHnH+US7xgFEfZtMi87lHcqYw8sN2Ivzbe+vf82sjB9cgCbR1B/5ZzYlWv164G+z8rVMz0ZxwL+OrUdEf5MiGiKwcH+N/q2XolhoAsW2Ym8V9SioYWa81j2YrwvTwzOo1lE3O7pFZJxIFwSwKEdbH41G3y5VkwZXcua54tqywm4R2ZK1t5lGKGSSgRp48r194dnAUjfGtPjGLlhn+Kh3eGf4bv/5XugKjxs/l3+qZnOVOJOFmYW4IKbL3HZ2F92OqeTY9Sc803R3CmOcA89Tf+YIKc2nlcgM0ob1Hu4i/Zq8j0KyWKv5P3zPQXnhvOK31C/UNwbvjcmqI=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "In 1947 after independence", 
		"option_b": "In 1991 after reforms", 
		"option_c": "In 2002 during the 10th Five Year Plan", 
		"option_d": "In 2014 under new government", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040110", 
		"question": "25S8Z4Hn2Bftt4QnQBfx0PHrIHnVQ2MC42uLV+NkYnjuUefPYfv3x5AxIVObjl475XfV46T5+lYLz7xUqYaafDJDV4VrwdHTleIrHwqowcnEAPLM6PFGSko=", 
		"answer": "25S7YJj2xxyq8YovVl7hwP7qJ2LEGiDZX2F7nWJU7bsam3Zetyjk", 
		"explanation": "25S8Z4Hn2Bftt4QnQBfx0PHrIHnVQ2MC42uLV+NkYnjuUefPYfv3x5AxIVObjl47/XCGpqb/+VwChqsb7pyQZzYLPpxu25CI3unywDFAJ4ZNl5Bg64wWcvMAyjKicJTIJf173GeUPgXxaT39FmVmlT2Wmm5Zu5O+5y6vTZo+zlUbmINx7IgLNcOXmbqW7kKqixXC3XWVCLRqB1GKocOt5VfQ4IM/p8SOpD7P4eb82vvc5dIPIgpdsJVrI0uumKwc+z4xXsb0aRxPseLRc1noMmiqKQ0S9M7wlkBhz5FpSmYh+BsGioZacoB22pHptTwxK8gqHSa0pEFSh5VyW1ebdbG2xXz26UE2enRrTIQtvyI7tR2dO0Ay2n+USWxXm4N+7ZAOlBcjc2BU3G/lln+EjiWAfpnm6JT1k+3j4LVq+aZnJECOIFrZVZkJd7rOICsyz/GLArRIIN9oBWLPCZUa9DzrJZCbzTxBkM0oKjfm8CWJhsT6NyW1tdL4icZ/F6oMIsTX7Iu2uVHCZWP1Lj2bY8fkGSH+S3X5ky9mvxEg3iRQ7m3XDMls8C4YjHekUAa8XE9NEUyRAROfva/7ho8t", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Become an IT hub", 
		"option_b": "Develop manufacturing", 
		"option_c": "Achieve food security", 
		"option_d": "Promote foreign trade", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040111", 
		"question": "24KwcdH32B2q/oskVw73y/n6O3+QKmwVqn7DU6d7YGWjUaTNYOLzwJQxN1CIg1Vy/HGZn6vD41IbiqVe55rfIXhDSoQv2tWNwufyhGFOJcNWjpky5ZQbPOZFyzSietXXYPpn3X6BNUzkbjyuOH5HgDDCj3FTppf7p337YNV3who9hZM458c+L+uR6ryS/Ei1gwiWnCjLCIlrUUCYtsWk7gOVroQ0tNmEvjyZY5y05AfxZxQ1x4kMEBorpA==", 
		"answer": "25q2ZIizgFtk04zTrRp3KBF8dzQFtyO9", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEhfhhf7wJ3nVAHZL417DX6J+f2OjRqLDfeLwiZF+NRygg19y8zbHp6rg41oBiOhe6oGRfy8Kfct/xNGH2e35wzFANdJBiMB76p4abPFOyDijd9GbN/99jnqPZ1f1Yyy+ATBkmyfTmGhP6IK18We5VdY2zhY31pV96sEzMtaTma2Q50O3iw+BnH+YW61lA12NvMu7102grrEstNmIvDfV4LSr2vHAsNcFYQdArYN8dwH8tLoM+T4xX8/0bR9b/evJbFHjNGi0Jh1d+Ivw03dmyIYoT3B08xBHjs8WYNVnlpbrqHIkN8gqGDKzrQRE1Z1qWgXWcrKqkHjo4VsxfHQsWYRRsh4hoBuZJVFwjivPDCVC1Ill/d8LhwFgaTUAqHfjiTOCjmLPdZ3l54HojOf+4K5i4eMmJwGPJVnKV5kVar3BKydxxeeYCLRSf99lAjamM9o6vC3xJdaZ0C0Extg0JnjptCyWgI3lNWS0vZv3ieh4KLE0PtTX7M24olmLITfpJD2QadnmXAvkD2/s0hpguh0r3GEZ+yL3BoVmtXxPx2erfIqn7A9c4lObLSS8yA==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Only 1", 
		"option_b": "Only 1 and 2", 
		"option_c": "Only 2", 
		"option_d": "Only 1 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040112", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrl+ZElXw791/zxMGTFECIGrG2PVuNxaGHmRq7HYO77iZ5/IVCciFV493KGiqv0/lJInOhL5Y+RfisNectrzdOAxO34yi4D65MIJGXSeYOqW8G5HQZS3w==", 
		"answer": "25KqbZDnkT3v55clQQ37yvO/NGXUQ1UesXOHEpR1YjGxFLXHbeLw2oNjMl+dhFR1sBVOIAqLEwJFXt94vyFzvb8=", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJjylgqq84AjWw37yvO/IWSQE3cDsGqGEqBxfmXxVavLdOj6iZJyKFKGgFJ4smbKoqv+/l0Iz6ld/YuNMCsNeo5/zd6N0ur0wTFWMtUEk4506I8acvdFyH2vbZTPKPsuy3aQIlf5Yje+ATB7knHCgnkWj5G+9DP7cN8n0hAhhY5344g1MpeL0a3TuRTr1hXC3XWVCIprA1id9fmp+QPO4JA9tsKDoibJ4fftk/fdsNsNZAdAq5U/V1O5160K9yQ3XMG3KBFD8OjcZFrqJTvjJgAZuczswHF7yI8sU3109xBJkIdfbMFn35fq/CE1OsMqHD36t0xF1JE8WgefZ7K81Xuk7VorfGwqcY9p/D05oAGSIVp52l+USWxSm45/+90JmhZib3YAi3nyjjvLhXOKcofwq5T0hPywqbRz86AzLEXAIVTRWIYVa7SAMGJgz6mPBaMcFI1iFjamGdA+7jzqM5+b0XkM3t1gGHj1+C7ZpczneTf6oZf6gdplAK0VNcXM5sX10R/LbZqkYZLgK67wDEAFwQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Cold War politics", 
		"option_b": "Fall of the Berlin Wall", 
		"option_c": "Great Depression and World War 2 reconstruction", 
		"option_d": "2008 financial crisis", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040113", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1Rzs/ospXBmy7PP7PGqXECIcqmeGVuNxc37tW6rbIq3pwZZlZ0uGmFd/snTD47H48hMdgKReqYGZMDYLe8t/2tmf1vDyhGJEMNJLiMBz55kQbvBJwjrtYNubNPZrjkiJNVbkJx+0EnU0rTTXmDxmpIK1qmUJ9pPLYc1hT5lfq3NY3YDL", 
		"answer": "25a3ZoX63wzvt5UyXRrnxun2OmWQAmwV43uKQbdmeXP2QK7NYK80ts7XSNq3mjMeEGm4YNIF", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHV2Av548UGWwj3hcT6NHmQM24QrT+AXqZ1Yn36FKPHaOTwzJMxDlKNhFo84TbLqr318xMKjKdV5oOGMC8Meo5jhJCe3vD/hGNOP8NX2oZ99todc+BIjCmlcZTLNfxix23AJkv0JymvDWZ1gDSWmXlVvIyp5medW8h31B031pdq5N49KNLfyq2Q/EKqykaW1H7ReLFlHxSKoc+87kfctIo5oY2IqTvI4P33nbjD4tEPdwtGtolxI1qyk+gN8TksQ8G2fQZC/uqQblKtJyesIx1d+MXnlmds1JQgXmwntAhJl49SIsN82Iztsic1f/liEHOqtkZMzpc8TBKVYLKqkH/r9Vk7NX8lcY9//CwnpA6PaFFtiW6SWCVQmMBt8cJZkQF1eGNPjHvljCvLtG2Kbpbl5JL5yajkqLwjwq8mJwGTNFXcFpkUYPPQNW5ky/2eTbVZMItoBWLxMsAi+HnaL5iA1jcY1ZkwPXjj4SmNm8L7eWS0t9L9h8diBrYCI8XM5sX1A7s5lOLGIfo4xB7gomUT+g==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Provide all infrastructure", 
		"option_b": "Drive all economic activity", 
		"option_c": "Control key industries", 
		"option_d": "Continue production and distribution", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040114", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUwVwz7yvnsdXzZF2pRinGHW6IzYzHmV6jMYeD3ytd4I1mGgVR86yyESfFF/hMUFlDXWrp8vdopAQ==", 
		"answer": "2+ThPMa+gECzp5ZgH17Vyuv6J2XdBmwF43yMXLdmf32vFPabN73thIdjIk+Mg087vzbrorf78kdPiadJ6ouMPGIzbI4iwd6N0vTyynVEPcVB2s0yx5UTc/pJzTHtcdfULvFj1yyGANnPF8ZmaNXcb7V5cArQ", 
		"explanation": "27i5fJL72Bftt5EoV17iwO/2Om/DQ3UYt3fDe61weXCkR+fHbeLwxpp4JByAiV50/nnBuv/M+VpGz/kCvdnSIXtaLpgvhZCu2PLy1n9MNshQ2oN96o4Nc/gAwyuoZpTeI/FgwWOZG0v5bnD9VSktxCKbmm5Tu4a14Wf2FPM5wwc3l5Rx4898LtiT3OiV51/4iweQ136FCLtrA1ecpo6p5UfcsJAxo8yZtHLI8fftlerv/tcCa0ESj5R6LlKyk60Z/SQ8VMa3bVIGscffbVvjKSmvZwse9sXs231qhpE9T3w34ApUh8NSbc162JnwuTZwPdQqHD6qplZJxpg8VhmCca+9w3z33FsLfX85YIxirih54RuULRR9lXmOSS9F1I1q6tMR1Q1wJ1NOlTatwhiElmCdcp7m5ZS8huf+tKts/u9nIEjAeBz1V58XYKeAIWhgyeyIQeZVOpYnWmLFMtkh8jD4LNaR3DYD39Q5beMb0lV1sYUXIMrLCF5imQs=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1947-1990s,Government control", 
		"option_b": "1990s-present,Market forces", 
		"option_c": "Pre-independence,Colonial economy", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040115", 
		"question": "24KwcdHk0Aqq440lEi7+xPPxPGXXQ0EernKKQbB9f3+jRqLSYuz9zJMxMFWdhRtV20Lv44Tx7lwI0OonY7Gev6fosym1RDJ6SWfV", 
		"answer": "24G3KJ7l1Avi9pAsEgr6wL3vOWreDWsfpD+TQKx3dWLwFpGGfSzXJudADYxuqzJ8/2I=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHD3Rjk+YwuVV7RyvDyPHjDCm0f7z+AQKZ1ZHTnFK7MLrynnMc9Z0uInhtp92bKoqb18xMGgegJud/KMDUKaoMv3NiMl8re8FgBEsddlYcy8JVfc+JF3jWsYdibNPZrjn6MJkv+bje6RGBmmzLTmW8WoY373Cm/Xdt34RMmk5U44cE+OcWe1aGJ6VmxiQjOnG+ZTf1UHVWXu8em7AO/r481vN6euD3VtOP4ibjA9dsFIglB/4c/cV6wnqtJ9yx4RcCxKBFE//DCbljhJSzjIg0S98TuzzRH77YAHUg17RBBwpRXcYBwxJ3lqDc0f9llVTG/t1BF1dRwWgGTZry/1Sjn71ovcGgqcYN7uW0zpAuZOlVyk3iRDC1fkMB5+9MWkgpqZ2oAjnnsh3+EhiWcaJL37pO8hOb04Klx+7UmPUTAJlnbQoIOJYfIIidgz+iIAqgcJJ50Vxbpfdo4+SvxIYOYny0F1ZkwI3bp+iOXlY3lK2q5toHqzEL5zS0JO0GSewQ6usrtbkA=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "To cut government spending", 
		"option_b": "To boost financial inclusion", 
		"option_c": "To create jobs", 
		"option_d": "To overhaul the planning process", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040116", 
		"question": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgUxf/1r3rOivAEW0crGuGErR8eXLrFKjELvn2zNd3KFCFgkxy/HGGt635+VQc0Opjh+rPl/e6LYgXeEaaPAo8", 
		"answer": "25a3Z4H2wxj+/pMlEhj3wfjtNGfZEG9T3lXOFN+9G5Op5JmEPlaqYA==", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgUxf/1r3rOivAEW0crGuGEqB7f2HmRqbWZ/v7iZF0I1mbjFdy4XuGobyw8l0HjqZY4ICYMCEMcZtq2tGd3uv5hHNEJ9FBn44y8JIaPPdFwim/cZTaLvou3XqBM0DjJz+yFjBxlz7YhXFfq8O/8DG+WNUnzRA8gsdM5cEvfNSQ17yB6V6slUaV1W+ZCKlsFBSpuc+m5UqSp8IbusCAuCHI/fv33euT5NEbLwxdqIg/YkushacI+yJ4eNz0fx1Z+veQdVutJiewMwsPucLt1Xh81Ys/WCkw8QlDjoxGb8V9wtjmpXI5Mc5lByO1sUVUzpp7HwSCdam9nWTh9lAzNWo5bIV/tTk8pBzcHFx7iG6aQz5U2MBF1+Qw1SViZGBH3HfpjyzLlGrPbIHs5o/ogKjTr7Zz97EmPUiWMBzeU4kZd7LMLnR/iIYqvkgTkD7ypB1RdsTZR2A=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Central planning", 
		"option_b": "Privatization", 
		"option_c": "Foreign investment", 
		"option_d": "Cooperative federalism", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040117", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t7EoV17c7MnWdUrRGm0W42iCQeNxY2XiVqvLfeX7zddlKByEiF5vrTREGn5bnMxtUQeLcn81I3x7", 
		"answer": "25awaZ/02Bftt4AjXRD9yPT8dWXVBmYC4Zv/kfPLNHiOjR00TuVaIbI=", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgRR/hhfjsIWrSD2sCq3qHErd7MHzmUbOCR+P6wJY2NByKhVp19X/IpOX19FwBgKVS6s6RdScHbctuxtTJxeH2yHhVOsNX1sBx65cPfeZFyH25e5TPKPsuy3yBZ1L4Yjf9NHx1mj/fhHsWi4y2+C6oR9M4zlUll5Q4/s0ofMKPmYGHqF2qiRCL2H6CCLtoFEyQt8ek4leF4IM2sY2DtCWb9eTpiPfS89YOcUhUsJQ/YhuxmLoMuCc5Q8OxfF9J8PfVZRitJySsJQ8R8NHm0jRsxY0nUmQttCtOh5FTZM9h09SkqDo1f99vFCC1rQRJ1NRfVxaYc7S21yjh41oxenciZspjuSgxsk3N1+tcxJn9pdNugFQDnFrW", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Globalization demands", 
		"option_b": "Socialist ideology", 
		"option_c": "Geopolitical goals", 
		"option_d": "Changing economic needs", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040118", 
		"question": "24KwcdHw3gzm84tnRl7by/n2NCzDQ3IDqmmCRqY0Y3TgQKjQLun735J9KEzJhFV94HfVt7fl9Ecana0b6IiLdTBDd4VrzcCM2eDyynJEbIS0bXxipfzCwoIs39rx0hND", 
		"answer": "25m5a5qz3h+q/os2Vw3myPjxISvTAnIQoHaXS+EwPKy54el/gFbcJcEcPm9h", 
		"explanation": "25S+fJThkRDk84AwVxD2wPP8MCeQF2oU42+RW7V1ZHSjR6LBeuLsiZ5/Z3WHiVJ6snLPp+X++EdPh6lN7M6LeCdDfYp/ydOAw/230H4BJshAn5Jm5ZEaPPxVyzjtfdrNJe16w2uOM1awbjf9DX5yhjDFnm5Dq5eu5yL7WNM8xVUimZB9/4R8KMWe17uD51+sxgeM2DuYWq9tFlWNvMGmq3OOqZQ5ocjNsjPL/eD4lrjE8c1LbgFftpJ6Zxu4gq1J7CV4Xcm3Y1JE96TZb0f5KTy2MwcS98rvlnJgyIMnXmA6819Jkpdfbc5glqzsuSA1OcJ4EH/6t0xFh4Z5XgSZev2xxCjn70AzcTolap4tuCgjpAOTOBR3lG2OTT9FhpVo6sULkER0fHwAsHfjiX+EhiWGcoXm+JTxgObk4Lpi4qIkIFWZd2Pc2YBCn8ZjdP1Lb++nrnA=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Colonial era policies", 
		"option_b": "Government opposition", 
		"option_c": "Priority on agriculture", 
		"option_d": "Lack of investment capacity", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040119", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iOSB0qTyyXRTNMNKmYUy65xfePFWyTGiZNneLuouy22PKUr9bjquRHFn1DCWjHVTpIf74iaoFN4lyQM3mMd69IgoNNLf162W7A2siUaD2H+DTa53UUCRsI6r40KQrIc2ssie8T3dtPPrle/H+J4caxxasJNrI1izmrgb/SI9X9u9fhcL9eHGZFjiMCWmKRoh9/nm12dmyMJhbyButDtDlIZabdB+05bw/DczMMNlGDq5sARGyJdpTBKFNK633G3o+RUwezouZoVjsyA8ok+bOltpjmPcTSJV1I99+8IVmgtobi9RiXfsiyuKlGyZedPz+Y/7l+3js/vf++JuaOBVWfEHviFN0XTG", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBi5RonGHEpE0eWKjQK/HLu7x24V0JEjJiENr/nfIorH5+F1PgK4byMzsL+6VFW4bW6o228jH0bJh", 
		"explanation": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6byvkC2dRpnKGQKRxfnLmFKjELun735J9KEyEiFVvsnPFrKv/+loMnOha+s6eMCYKbZ9mxtOdl+L+wX1Fc9FFicB29pMJefoAziTtYNzeYPBry2rAM0qwZSuyBXRxmnHCgnkWp4Gx8CSvXcwy01U9kMd97scyM9qW2uiU+kKvkg7C8XqfUf10HkeN+M2n50ySqYM09cOMpTvU+ue5nPfQ5c0OZkhcvpRtbEywjugG9mofdfj0bwBE5vDYIUPkNCCsMhpd+Mjr33F/z4wuHWo7+Q9Uh4tTbNN6wJ2kuDcmOsFlBT6/rVB8yahybRKXZ7K2kGH3oEEtYH9xJa5oqig5rh+RLVpq2m6fQyJemYlo7ZAdmgFwPWlPn2PzwjCFwGeAaJuj7oPzi+f9qboj9bEoPlWIdVPaXIgfcbrWInQyy+efTbdJMpNuAyPyNMMrvCnrL5GG2ioekNgjPXj052qKnc78OGn285v3ncB/AKoUP97L6Mf3tUjEITPgM3yeY9/xSxvMQUD24QtkpBcriCIf+nDdC51z7G0Ihm68SE1qgWfBf2+khKpV5YzUP7o51rXe2DMDl/o4mpf21hIuRhC+nj9XuoWLD1hK21HaEd0KwQc6TLECG5je/2SVhjbTRHIedsrzE7vHwSNc0qPgm2Bzq5kaVJiHOhybi9AiiAakAPFwQWb5oZD8fewHBWM+/6Fihq22v8O4fbOgPmo8alq+TfwZ9phUegV+HwjYRS1BaaynV5ESWNxB7nv+nwJaQnlGF1+Au6oHSQzqi4TJYG6eUfEdHBuid6EQFoK4T0nLdcPpwSOJEreZ1USxTVYgTS7dJKgd6Qb+e5j7Kx3znG4k2IMPygoj34Xn67XJv692Ibn2", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true, and R is the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true, but R is not the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_c": "A is true, but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false, but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040120", 
		"question": "2523f9Hk3gzm88UwQBH0zOnsdW3CDG9Rs2qBXqp3MGLmV7PNfK39xpphJlKAiEg7+nPKs+X08kUKg6dLqaeRdCsCOZgv29+K3uX7hGJEMNJLiN8w1WG3iKo5orqfWEGcTTIigw==", 
		"answer": "25ehKJfm3x3j+YJgQgvwyfT8dWzfDGYC43OKWaY0eHTiWLPKbezszNW4VfsiB8D2SjWr2CphyHjT", 
		"explanation": "24Wtap360ln58oY0XQyyxvLyJWreCmcC43aNEop6dHjiFKDHYOjsyIN0IxyahFx1+3DPoKT+4xMfnadd4JqMPGIGbZtqy9mI2+juhHdTPMsEk4509psMaOZVzym4ZtGbLfFgwX6PK0z1dHmUCmNgkTDSynNQ6Ia15y64XNM5x1UihI5u7Nw5fMSX2LqW4EK0ggOQzzfRXLVhAlHZpdyn7UqIs8IvsN+I8TvV4PH3nv3XsMoEIgpX/5NsZl/8kacbuDotU8S9a1JM/uvUchTdMielLhoOuc3x2Xkp1pcrUWA3tAxDgZdZcIBw2ZX0vTw5Ot4qFjyvr0AAz5FwT1eQYbO8kGDh4VkrfXkqd48h/CgxtAydPF1xlCudQigRm5Rj+8JZhgtgdG5M3GXlgSuEkiWLeYXm54/siO3+tPlX+qY1LEePJ1mUFp0OarXJM3Qy3eaOAaIcO5prB2LkJJUI6Tf9KZiTnykY0tUpLDfg+yWdgY35MG6/85r8j9hiHLwBJNSHkEgu3Sxd/Gsc31f7aWFOpw==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "By reducing budget deficits", 
		"option_b": "By eliminating poverty", 
		"option_c": "By building infrastructure", 
		"option_d": "By funding public goods like healthcare", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040121", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1RDut5EoV17C0P/zPGiQKmwXsX6QRrFhc2X2RqKCaOz9wJt4M12diF87+3iGt631t1AAgbxe8ZrffyRDV4VrwdGHl8H0y39OPt8b2ACDYTdteurJllrGXr5rHLU=", 
		"answer": "24exe5Sz3h+q440lEg7gzOv+IW6QEGcSt3CREPL6rN5q2hScWtL2XdWV4rc=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH2yQ3v+ZYpRBuyzPPpMHjEDmcft2zDX6JwdTHhTefSe+/ywJQxNFmKmVRpsnXJrrXx+VoKnOhe54+dfCcHPp9nzZCN0vLyyH5RPsNKjsB94toWcvJSzS65ZsHYNOt8yy6MLk71JymyE3Vm2HHCmH1Yu5O05zP3FM4yzBAxmYo46Nw/fN6Rmbic+1n1jwiG2WuURrlhH1ec9eem70qd4LYwvN7NtzPY/fjwjvnH9dpLdgBX/4NyZkm7kqYK/Wo3V4igYBcL4fbZd1X5JWiwIg0J9tmj13d7yZE6HWgz5hZFl49Cd9J2mtjpvTwlOcxpASaoqkpHh5VyW1eFca+u2Wvh8xULfX85YIxirih54T+JKlh3mSuVQipDlZN/7MUagRFxeC9GnXXpjjafgXGKeNPR4pP5xef24K1r9+M3O0iWNEjdFp4ZZqfPNSVx7iPbkhZ/vlW8lmzq7QAy", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Spread of heavy industries", 
		"option_b": "Agricultural modernization", 
		"option_c": "Development of villages", 
		"option_d": "Rise of the private sector", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040122", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iOCc1ej+xzFyNsVQlZIy0ZQbeeZUzTaketPIYLZe/VuTbgXgazikAXQ0lXHGg2pZvIK3tTW0WN93yRtykYJ26No9KN6R3uiB7Vu9iBOHnH2eWv13HleQtMLo+EaftI0q9cmIpzfX++T0n/bHsNcFIiFcu49+X1WOkqka9yR4Gfr9MlJ/+eGQcUbiJiG3NE4b68TulkRa85FpSmwm8V9Ci5FTYdR20tj3sz41M9QqATytolZE1NRsTR6Adam9kHvh40EwZzoufZpssj48rgHcKVp62mKSSDlCgJJi/9xZkhZsantI3uQIovv+fpG7/3CJUbrBefo=", 
		"answer": "25T4YYKzxQv/8slgUAvmhc+/PHiQBWMdsHrBZp/Ta9Kg0XiirdPtxVfDQg==", 
		"explanation": "25Sre5ThxRDl+cUpQV7m1+j6byvgFmAdqnzDQaZ3ZH7xFLLMaujs3ZZ6LlKOnht/+3KGs6nx7hMOz6Va44GNMDAMco4vwd7J0OH5wWNAJ89KncBg4YwacuFF332re8abM/Ftx2+MZ1b1ZC2yFjBwkSfThnNGpYa14WeyWpoezhE7l8ds5dozKdCXmbyb7USqxhaQ032YXK5YH2iXh8up+EyS4Isr9cuMvSHerrTJqc2T4MwEZAFGrMZoZkm516YG7Go8WNqxawZO9aTDbljoLDHjMwEK+NnnxTR51Is/XH0xtAxDgZdZcIB0xJfzqDprf9liECr6okhTyNR+WhmTcrSs1Wyk9F06NWkkZoNssG0mpAyIJ0ZClFeSeCRUhoVt8cIc2URCPWZT3GLylzrLgnCbPKGj4pO8g+n8s7wjxqsiaUCTJlnKQoQTa/PJNCdm2PyeQeZeJosnAyrjfccr/Sr2LtadzHkE3tovPWXi9z7blTP7Ob91aEkQ5NpWVDHHxA==", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true, and R is the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true, but R is not the correct explanation of A", 
		"option_c": "A is true, but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false, but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040123", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2BT69oY0Vxqy7PP7PGqXECIBrHOKUbo0f3+jRLLAYuT9iYR0JEiGnxt/+2XPrbP15EcCiqZPqY+ZZCcRPtk/mIPEh7Cohn7PdAZqKfEeml7yggFelAM=", 
		"answer": "25a3ZoL23wr/5MUvXF7h0fzrMCzDQ3Aer3rBREzkA0DyxoNGDS26gg20tw==", 
		"explanation": "25S+fJThkQ3i8sUlURH8yvD2NivCBmQesXKQEqxyMCC6DfaOLu7xx4R0KU+cnht84HfCtqT8+0pPiqVe+4madGIMcMt9zdSc1O35wzFVO8MEiZRz8J9Yb7RExS+od8CbMvFiyy6JKQX1ZDazC319l3HXiWhfvoqv7GeLRtMhwQE31pR97twzLpeI2LvT+0i9iEaDzzuUTrttEl2cu9ro30uVs8I7vcyDtjvV87T6lfbA9dAYdxsSrI9xYF78xfhZq2doBYi9ZQJK8vDVZRTELiyqJkkOudvs2n1q38ImUykw/QxPjJVTcdR+05bw/D02f/1ZICD6l0xF1ZF6UAWTOP2s2G2k5lQ8YXU5JZ1sr20WqQ6SL11wnSufQyJCkY5468NZmgojbntBiHOnkX+Zj2mKPknq/sGPH9LpS9jN1xxYSDI=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Fiscal constraints", 
		"option_b": "Globalization", 
		"option_c": "Consensus on state's role", 
		"option_d": "Recession", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040124", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MU0Whuy9untNH/VBGsS43uKQap6ZnTwQKrHYPm+yJt9KEua0hlMTja1whZLseiv1IBDJs47", 
		"answer": "24GqaZ/g1xz4t4omEi7B8L3wImXVEXEZqm/DRqw0YGPqQqbWa63tzJRlKE7LDoIMgbB2DzNffMllftDTiw==", 
		"explanation": "24asepDn1B7j9MUkWw37y+v6Jn/dBmwF43aNRKx4ZnTwFLPKa63tyJt0Z1OPzUhu8GXSoqvk/lIDz7hU+5qWfyxDcY0vz9+f0vb5yXRPJ4FX2pNm5ZEaPP1OjDztROfubL58y32VK1H5aT79DX40gCPXhG9QrZH7+iH7Wds5wRI3m4J2+Yg/M9mLy6efqFm3xhaQ1W2QXLgkAViYrMu6+AOoqIsr9cyEvCGb4Pu5k/XD4tEdZ0hXuYB2YFK5masQuD4wQ8ehbxoL4fbZd1X5JWisMAAY69jr32Qp8oosT2wy+w1DzsNfdoBy2pTrqyFwC99rGyC8plYAyJI8bySjNLKv3m328102ZTo/asp9riQjoBuZaEd7mX+TXm5+ptBYs2gT9HRod3UY8wEd", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Increasing PSU efficiency", 
		"option_b": "Limiting foreign ownership", 
		"option_c": "Enhancing worker control", 
		"option_d": "Transfer of PSU ownership to private sector", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "040125", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRp3CGQeNXf3/3UarSYf//244xI1WahFVt92XSrqD+4xMOhqVIqZqQMDACd5hql5JKJUkWIwadNVZToK7z7TZM", 
		"answer": "24e9fpT9xByq440yXQv1zb3sIWrbBiIConOGEJjmRJD2JcWuQEIYM8lAWbQ=", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIP20hzk48U5Vx/g1rG/IWPVQ3EFsX6XV6R9czHnXbTLYPv72oN8IlKdzVR9skb1lraw/1Icz6lS5IubMDYMPpluwcOMl/by0nRPJsNX2oZ99toLdPEAyzK7ccbVLftg2i6UL1f/cj61RGNglTrTym9XpIaotQOyR9M51hAhgop949x8LMWQ2q2W7F74hQmMyGmYSqhwFBSNuo6840bcopc8ssiZ8TPV8LTrn/zG89tLZAFBvIdzI1+5kaEK8T54ZcCxehdN/vbVLRTuLya3IgMN9tnixG0pwos6VGci8QxSj4ZYdoBy35X3/CY/f99rHCC/43ZF0ZFyShLWYLWq333j6BUsYXsgYMp+vSEw4+SMHJDgeW+PMm1gvsVM4yM=", 
		"topic_name": "Structure of the Indian Economy & Demographics >> Evolution of the Indian Economy  >> The Background to Emphasis of Public Sector", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Public accountability", 
		"option_b": "Competition", 
		"option_c": "Operational freedom", 
		"option_d": "Revenue through stake sale", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110101", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbe7r25ZlIlCQzV9+/HnSpraw41sKz7hO+56QYydDcY0vzNma1PHk13hPNIZWn4F+qZYWevEAySWsecTXJe0uyHyPKgX0bj+7AWJxmiWWj39Zpoy2/CKoFNs5xFU6n5Rs4to1P9aTmaqS60a/lAmX0n+CCLRqUUCRsI6r5E2IpZos9cKL8TfY+/r2l/HQsM4HYwZctoh4PGeyq6YguGd4Zcf0bR9b+eXDaE7oYDyrIk4c+srn03lgxcIoTnkx9wtVwoxQIsVw2ZbrsTszf91mFD20qkpH+5pVdlfbNIm3kH3q5FAtZm4qa44tqCUw4QKZKVp3lGzcTSJV1JJk8tVZmgIjbWNBknjpjDjLiWvPfdPw+4X/jO75o/lg/bYpPVOZdVDRXYhcTL3ELmZOxMCyTescB5AnEjrlMcAq+Xn4Lo/UzTwL1cslIXTitD6W0sjtKWCoup/8gMBlVLwPONXQ6t+ytBzFeGPlKHuVY9nxVxywTHPt3Rp3vh02iCgeqHbQDcl5/CgBmj6/TwRhkSjuY3Golf5M5oOAcYc/1LfbphwBOgBfHu+SP/BJtxwR", 
		"answer": "25q2ZIizg1uwV+m/y6r0/hG+btiKc2Mw", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxCF7GzfTsdXjEAnYUrnqNRuN9YzHtW7OCa+PqwIV0K0XJjFh452THt6Cww1sKz7hO+56QYydDd5gvxt+dl/f4yHRNKoZQlcB36YoXfedJ1jjtddfaJPtjx23AJlbgYjqpFzB2gSWWnnMWr4Ky+2erRts01Bwxl4s45MYvNdCXzbvT6UO8xhOM2H6DW6llH1DZocatq1GZoY51osKfvTab9eTplvHQ8coCbQYSsIA/ZlizmacE8Sl4QcS1ZhxC/+Psb2jjEzyiMwsQ/MX3liYzhrYhVHp05wtHloZbZ85nlpH3/DMzPNh4FCe/42BJ1JdpTASferr4wm3l7BgzfHwuJY91vSAlrQqPaFVwniuURT9Fm5Ji/dEV1QZifmRHjnn1jDuYwG2KcIPwq5Xvxev/ralx96siJ0XAIVTdFp0OZLDULmRzxqmWCKdSOpFgVyPoOZU88zX8YJmSnzwO39cvIn7ktDqVk8P7MGu9/9L8ncRzF7YBOt3cqdy+pFTOb2PyMXiQb839WkjzQGn2xxxssgtlxCgb7SLxBo129BEDonCDXUVwlyrlYmjhxeQc3oqHbM4ix/T42D8VluA4loi32hIoBwW4jmpRs5CaD2hHyBTGC98XyxorTL0SVILesmSYlnrFT3lNbcvwBLqCzS9NyaPlgSF4p4ALR4WDKRfPmZ4lxxm1FP5tUGOtqp+5OfUTDGE+/7xliu6uosSvZ/qhPylqeBK+WucZ8pxVe0JyH0vICyBKcqu6V5MaSO5IkmPLhQ5HUmwJBErc6acJXgyvuYTcYSrbYL4SARPrYPMVH8/2QE7BMs2n9D7hA7GfkAv+S0wgDjeSMqRN5ATzb57zMBbzgHxl7cToN19PBJESOybhcGK3ouOXAwN6bzk3OIVUfwfcWFAXgD/XIvRig7NAIloPXO9ejQYW886lLXp0aAyp", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Only 1", 
		"option_b": "Only 2", 
		"option_c": "Only 1 and 2", 
		"option_d": "Only 2 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110102", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmoiN9Ev6cPJx+HlhHRZI8NWjpM+pLI7PNBJzzakesfULr5+3GGWLkH1Y3mpDHU0ljTFnjxSrYWy+y6vXdU5gBo01oJ74sYzMd6cmbif6UO2jwiFnEeferhlAluX/fzhsQO0qZF4sciLuDzS4P32lLjb+dkDbgFVt5J6Zxuon61J6iU0VIi7blJf+eGQckDsNC3jLgBd9Mrp2WYpw4EmU2Y5/RwGhoZVa9N62Zb3/nHpuSGQO3dbAz+eMYe32fM=", 
		"answer": "25T4aZ/3kSuq9pclEhz90fW/IXnFBiIQrXvDYONxaGHvVa7Mfa3fi5zQM2F6+7kXxj//Nn8sPrc=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHSwgrv5ZEpXRCy1un+IW7DQ3YZomvDV7tkdWP3R+fBYePtwJN0NRyhqRtf+3XNqqvj+F1InOhf7IiWfisXd4RhiN+Pl+H0y39OPs9H2pB+5ZQRdfpHjCmiNNbeYOpmyy6CIlbkK3mqDHl3nHHfmTxCupa+tRu1YNIygCc3l5R344gsLtiJ0KyW+w2sjgPC33SfXLh8BRSfutzo/EuF4Ioxpo2JtDTS+v3tk/fdsNcYIgtdsZV2Z16ukqxJ7CI9EcqxewYL8/2QaV3qKCSqIAYJ8MXkln191cIvUmoh519JjMNCasUzxYzlqDd3LI14Gj+/401Oh5l9VRiENLi732br7Vw8NX4uZoN+tSI7sk+oIFE+qG6dXyNf1INk7MIclhBvZC9FhGbsgzaFkyWbdJajypPvgPrkqbZtsFOogtnFrEZ67dMFt2qw8P4=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "A and R are both true but R does not explain A", 
		"option_b": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_c": "A is false but R is true", 
		"option_d": "A and R are both true and R explains A", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110103", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDbe7r25ZlIlCQzV9+4XXUqqf15BMrhqtQ4ICMfyxEbctrzdaA2e3jzX5Pc8lC2oVx65QQcf1DjC2hddrVKfBpkS68KXbkZi24CXV6gHGHylVC6Ia25S+6R9MtxRFygo99rdsoPcOanrvT+kK0g0aL0juBWrJgBFeNvMGmpwOdrI43tsyZuD3VtPX3nrjW89EFbQVbvMZ8bFSuk6EH+T4xXsb0VBx45eXEZFnoLjzjdU407Yvl2Xd81YctHWY6tAtUg4dTIsF90tjwvSoxK8RlG3OqrEhJxJ15TFeqeo6s0Xzh7VAxYTp4JaN5/CU8pgeQIVN2jm6YDDhZkcB58dwc1QtlPX9SlWDhljrLhWubeYHz+YnvgPuwnLdQ5qIzLEyFO0iYAs01cfPQNW592OCPBLxZN99wEi7gPMcrvCr6KJOZ2ipN0dckb2Ty9jmQlsTwKieweUsV3L0p/0p8YwF+ZUJQ", 
		"answer": "2+T4Z5//yFtqIB4th9O9apMH4n7ZyUrT", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VxEh/xxujtNH/VD3tRp3qQUbF9cnTwFIPLbeb3x4R+KRuazV9+9H/IqrH5+F1PgK4b7I2Qfi0Od4gv2NyI2er+ynYBG8MEnoV07ZQab7RFzzKje9nSI75+wm+OKUz+YHm8FzBI1iXejzxbqYiy+yD7W9x3zRQ4mZU46MszMtiS0KvT7Ei7jxWL03WCCPAkBlyYoY6p5UfcqI0v9cCYsjqb/ee5jveT8ttLchpdu5N8Zl/w16AG72Z4RsCxZlJK/+CQdlzoMi3jLhpd8NijwnspxIdpTXs78ApFh4caIsF90tjws3InN8JnVTqu401Th4BzHxWTNLy03Gfn4UE6cTopfMp5tCh1ogCSO1d3lX6PDChUl4l4998X1QUjeWpUmWTtizGKlGDPfYb344/ujPzp7Pls/OMzIUTAN13LX55carWAJidxxeSLH6NUNpF0HjTjfcY77i/8Odab2XkZ2NxgKnTo+iWUm861Knypp5f0ztVlVL5AIdnK5c6L8hzzaSryYXmWYML6UBz5QHK40AJgtgop0WEV5XLQCZp27yge3mq4TAR2nSvlLHOn1qpU78Kda48l1rXl03IAivt8ipjj3RIyC0S6gXNMsYWLRlNBjVXYGo0CxwYgA7kIF9bS/WKEkX/eSmgEcMDKD5SJ8DhJzub8i29p/8JCFd/CbBjVjp5yiBajBL13WnOtqYX6KO4UHmFs/rdiyf+op96yev23bGosLz6+WuRQ/YZeZkVoUQ/YAy1BaaynWZNeTuYP13bFmQhFTnwJFVbN9aYBUwPqmdDJem/TZr8ITkyiZbwGBt39XQfAO7G92jHNA/+dm0P+S0U9Ty6ULr5N9Qj8c4/7IQD/039s8MLtclBJQcMZMzOzcXOpqaqAAhI2ZmwoLYRTc0jbThRknTCDA/Bkhq4OYxcjBrvnHVUQnx9GizfdABh2pE0KWqioTkdneelNKVwZwT6yGbQMHAjCg3oYgVqZgi3qaepZOF8ib2HTikL0noB2jfb6h53NSsPqJLEekqkKK71SSonZERwP2vfh6ejuGHgwCWM3KvfNTaLfv1u2B9DkrsrZzEhH0P4FM1EvLDaFyYvR9Xp/IKlKL39M/WMLpdzTdgPq3IZN0EJ4Qlz/8FKkcnMgohR+a53/KomcOoms/0JWAi3dUqoDj/l02y32MJ/CZxI6CmYm0QaecpLZ0jaQNKjyxb5FRQ+q3prDBYt/6Qh4ws+9g0JPv3twl2zuAnXTduv0qBNRLGhxRLqaHh1UiFcG3Dm61137MoHtlOYNi7ZI1rwH6AP54NlxdKe+JVzmICF0OPvcYsk=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 3 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 4 only", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 4 only", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110104", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fQa+vyzJRlZ3WHiVJ6tWWGjaTk/lwBjqQb2YKefiwKcIwv69+E2u3j0HREc8JBnIl87Y4Wc/oAwzvtcdfULvFjx23AN0nxaTe0Cncr1A3YuWhXvIa28CmvFIt36QFyk4po5ckvNc2a3eia5kmtlRKQ1XqdQadlBV2Wu46p5UfctZA6tMOEqzPP/fv32ujB+dMKcAFepsZDbWiolrwM9S82RYjmKDtfseLfYkH+JSzjKABd6dns0mFq0osmUyk1+hsGi41AZ9Nn253qqHI9PsRkGSr6n0pz05VoWhqTeqn4gyjN9BU2e3kkd5piriwhpAvcLVdxlGSRRS8d1IN+8sQMhwVvPW5OmDbzkjaZiXGafZ+j/YHwkO3j4Plf/JAzKFWFOFnWQs1IJZrUZ297zeGXBKFUJ5pjVybjO9Ag/zy5IZiQnzgJ3dAuJmTz5iuNm8L7eXWoup3rh8B/EaxAOtDX7s67qR55Z00+QyG0rawyGfYlUMmo", 
		"answer": "2+b4Z5//yFtHIoXS+8L1n+t46019wTFK", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48VzEgz3w/H6Nn/DQ0sfp3aCFbA0XnD3XajMb+G++ZtwKVKAg1w70XnLrqzk41YKz6xe74eReTYKcYUvx9bJ0uf4yn5MOsUEioxz6pQWcvMA+DWoNPraNPdhwG+MZ3X8ZjezDX5z1BLZh3FfvJe+8GesVcl30xAm1pJorcEyfIbGivDT6lT4rAeV3XOQWrFlHRS3sMa6/g/ct4o39dqMonLP/PG5mfDS+cwGYwYSsIA/d1O516sG9ScxRdyxbVJ/+eGQYlvgLSG3MwsYvtij0nFvz4wgSWA7+l9JhMNTYc992ZXtv3IgM8xkGzq0pARFyoR0XgSfbri8kHzs5RUxcH8vJZ5i/CQ7ogCOOFtsm3+ZDClSm45k89ka2URgaGNUiWThjn+KjmHPb4Pq+YnokOn84K9i/rYiOgGJOxzMXohcdb/BKWl7xO7bHbRTMJp0BGLSNdBu/zb0LZ+AyzwIkNslI37i4i+d0tn9OHH6tpH2gNt7HbxAJt3E58W+vluHcivuNHGXJsX7TUj/QXDhkwhqtA02iC4eqG/ZHIxt/CwB3m6iRkN2lzTzIDyjg6oc646dcM4+3bX41TdQnPFumpf4xBA5SRD7gnkDpoyaD1RawFXYXt4XzRsnGIgPKJji5myCkHvVRWgeP5+6QfrLgy1G3qOlzmVy/54BQcycKR/Xj90yiAO5BL1XVHPkp4j4MbwlBmUi9Lt/za2CuMe2fOewKWBqax+xUOFQ55xeZkJ0F0vYBitBb7WnVd0OTeFB3HzEkEd7U35dAFfJ9bxIDESvp9TAb3nXebQPThfsZ6YWB9zxT0vGL/C9wT/HRr6SkQerTUYkQDOHIKQE6gm8Opv6LR+203xs/IHLM0VSS40WMGfDeGq3q6qNDEYZcCEoIZ5Tf0KSWFAgkTjKKfBzhKgOMBwkReipFkRWkwlfkzfRB0xJqQwTWqu5SVwpar1NJUgUjSOwA60MHC/ehy4Pg1OS1mK+afxEMlwwfnfTgEKgi4Bpm+rqloeOBJTjI7lb24MVLaVPSZ/YCxdcjfvt4+SgBWQ8RkN2OvHHUOPd8H/6A8b6q83dhX9ExLMBIks+IH6YyZvc9jNjJrFGYH4KvH8Ko4rXbxai2JtQz1VsEEHk8AHqRGIl9hd8fNP4Zd7VK5fl8V5bVifSW61Wiv10nSjhI9rdawoyAm0h0TSEd8bPyjGNKeyvgKUAAhCu3p7DUZkt6E1/y9KxxgxBpT81jnjvAnjTcfP/6QpdLXI4W6aWFU9Ukh4nxnbxyVvhMYrqk64Mzp5AzLwc7w374hF6jlCCRkTJI1Dl0/uXo3LDuwAyia5mWm+tUmdkwQJkQPkvsndhVG0kUbF4tbX8OL3d3myqIIixwoJN8V5RVaKKO7ipsMa+rVWoDshrAi2XSIoaffhvSA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_b": "3 and 4 only", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 4 only", 
		"option_d": "3 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110105", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fLfa3q24J0Z06Milpp9n/IpOX19FwBgKVS6s6PfCMNcIJhz5CA2aTeynVIMoZGn4Z99p9fdfpEyS2oetDeLv1rkS68KXbkZi2wAX5g1GCWvnRTuob74iaoFNk4zgY3mJRt/ogoNNaLmaGd7EiogwiG2XWFCJRqFV2Y9dmn/k+Y4IM8ut2Z8SLX9fr3k/bUsOIFURxTq4NyZlWo1/pJyCY5X8a9ZhUL5uXDIVv9MCewIgpd+9Kj1GF6z4wsTnp0+BpHhoZEcYBP2KvwvSY1MshkAXPp43BIwtRsShWafb74w23n9FotNW0kcIZp/CknqBmZaERym2WSRSJW1LxlzcQYgQFueGFU3CKgtjeOkmDPa5bx7sD4jP75s7Bs/LBnJk/ANFjXRpkVa7SAN2tzxOeSA6Ee6irjBictTxS+A5QaydCCkg==", 
		"answer": "2+H4Z5//yFvHpGQswfmI+t/GdIBD3YAt", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk48V0Ehfhhen3MCvdDHEF436AUbZmcWXmFLTWb/n7xJJ/MxybiFx64HLPraKw8lAAgadW4I3fYC4CcIVmxtfJ3uq37X9FOscEmIV064gaPP1OyDi9cdrfJfBtyy60L0DiYnmqAWJx1DXfnHVFoYy15me0Wpo2xBoigo526ogsMNaR16Gd7w2xiEar0n+YSf1mFFKWp8vo4k2YpZI9u8mIvzHeyPrFlMvc/dtLbQ4Sq456I1e5lqwA9i14RcC9ZhlO4/eQYFrpYC2gKAAS9MLwwmcpyYRpSWExtAtPj4YaItNm1ZCkvSFwEo1cHCCspldWxoZ9RhbaNJe5x2ns4UczdHZrS49lrjh54Q6SLBROuSuxTSRQmIFl8dIQhkgjampSmTbzli2EjmLPfZf15IP9ke3j4LZlsrMrKE+OPFLfFrkUYKqAJWJ+w+yNCKIcJ5dmA2L2MdQg8jD3J9aD3ipN1cozKnnz/SuV0sv6KyWTvZbwj5RiG/8BNdnM7N2y8E7GcSrlYXiQacX7VAHzD3j9xQtpuAgozS8EqGPWDMlr+m0fm3qlSkEkgij2aW61j4JS1oymcJk0xfD+kXIEkPFqmtvg0Q85BwW3nnADoYuSShxN2EffEMgU10kiCbUFEYTCsmyYkTbVSHMDcMP/EryUgztA1aP+nnFyrJUKFZyCLRfVg9AhiCO5BOQ5VHXqvYP9fegdC3Bs6r5wxOOouc37YvyxIGFqfA6+X+Ncs5BSZwx0HALeRSNdb6+6Xt0fT+QP23vEmBFJU3ZGCxr4860RHQWmucuIb3jZdrQYTgrqYqdFGtq4WUjaOfXpyjWJErCT1UO3WUIsTS+RNfAZ6kf5d5z+IR62nXwk+M/hclxaSoIQOWfyNHu1pK2NAgg9Pz88O55CdwfcRVAl1D3MMvdzn75AcQttTam1HlVWlx9L3zrbGF1Xo0leXrbtaV0jI6h5Lmcf5Dn1BagaHBnEgnZKml6ZggviLfNKPwkNenCagELhl9JFkPHukIuSGZiiObUekoEGKbJSSp2WD1QQk+ft7ODsUXw4FHlubvHGHsvftEb3Qsng4tfSwBxfwLMNeh86ITabnZrdsDstIqxXanQKvGMJvsXTYQ7qzYcZ0FNnXlrh/EKkUWsguB96YJSrXtXZM9uk90JaEyCHQ7FCjLxo0S3qO9bfY1ooBnB1nwKTc8HZxiaacez51blJERCnztnKSZlirEp8wtW31UlE6y99jmiiH37fIvf/4QhVNnk4WLGcDlJPxgQq2i+92hP4MY6zx6dJnL9N3fUa70zyoS54gFOFTArKZmXv0vmOumPIqnsv9aRXVGPjXXp/3RhkYvk99zRXRSwzCZF4vbi1O7DX3m2uO5K7xYkJpV9aBvaTeuz3/dTyIePMO+Xh2JKIKnah5ZtsRPeqItcLLn/DY30Qov71IojLYw7TPWWAkriXHzuCIDgb5HZ7iGyLTVhjKyC2SMZTETtbk8JmL7gfqsfqtwpscirpFLVh2OE9k14ZHFxYRPLolnYNCOptOouPYR9l/kVcDPkaZnuybQp5cdlUm3e9TiLjqyiyh/pnEJfjlAc5LgqZwiDIdHTS8at3Ii2pU8fLxZKKQi2tt/E2REMctaFG0gyMFTwQenZr4xvFiOQvS1CLYBkqN/0TychVSNb5ohcHlNQzDwIUejnMEnqQFZzNVpIYSpKh3LYoppMdjzRHEZQCd5yPQhjZ0XyMLU3JnDkXvT/yvp9oOGE=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "4 only", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110106", 
		"question": "25C7Z5/83BDpt5UsUxD8zPP4dWrZDnFRt3DDW61yfGTmWqTHLuD/w5hjZ1mKglV0/3/F47Px5VoOjaRe+s6TeSkGPoJhy9+E0qi3x35PINNJipR765RTPP1O2ji+YNneLuouwXiFNQXkbjS4RFVilT3Di2hT6Jez8GeoQNsjxRg3mJM6lz/XK/NPipJZO/GBpNso1Q==", 
		"answer": "25S6e57/xA3v+5xgcRHg1/j8ISnVMgGGy2xsAKU5MH/I37QR", 
		"explanation": "25C7Z5/83BDpt5UsUxD8zPP4dW/VD2sTpm2CRqZ4aTHwUaLJfa3qxtd4KVqFmF518XOGoqv0t1AAgLpf4ICeZCdDdY52iNWK2Or4yXhCc9BFiIlz5pYab7RMxTaoNN3VI/FjyyLAJEr+dCywFGR9mz+aynVYvoao4Sq+Ws53xQEx1rt24t45LpeL0a3T5EK2gUaW2WmcBP1xH1iQvsvo4VaPtMIstN+KtCbS+vO5n+DD/8wfcUhdrcZ4bE25haYE/SQsEdukbRxP+OrXIWDlJTqmIQEP/IejwnxshpE9XH0x+RpIlsNfcYBy1ZvxrjMkOo9OW+z2H830sTmTtMRs/j3x", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Absolutely Correct", 
		"option_b": "Partially Incorrect", 
		"option_c": "Correct, but it only focuses on short-term economic variables", 
		"option_d": "Incorrect, as it has no impact on economic variables", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110107", 
		"question": "24W0aZ/92Bftt4wzEgr6wL3vJ2TTBnEC43CFEqJ3eHjmQq7Maa3pzJt9aliMi1J193KGpKrx+0BPjbEb5p6LeS8Wc8t63NmF3v720HhOPYZLnMBz8psWcPVCwDjtZtHIL+t8zWuTZ2DmZjWoBWRx1CXejzxFvIKv8Cq+Ws51wbfse1cdpYlwMdMw1qqzIQ==", 
		"answer": "25S6e57/xA3v+5xgcRHg1/j8ISnVMgGGy2xsAKU5MH/I37QR", 
		"explanation": "24W0aZ/92Bftt4QzEgr6wL3vJ2TTBnEC43CFEqJ3eHjmQq7Maa39xZJwNVCQzV9+9H/IpqGw8FwOg7sb65fffzIXd4ZuxNyQl/HjzX1IKc9KncBz8psWcPVCwDjtZtHIL+t8zWuTawXMaSyzCHl/kXHcn29C6I667S62XcA+zhJyhpV36d0/KN6Q1+ic+g2/lAmVyHPRfLVhA1GfutytpwOIqId4ptmMpTfW8frt2vHAsN8IYR1AvpJ6IdsvU7FMUKAnQ4hFdU3Dgxg=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Absolutely Correct", 
		"option_b": "Partially Incorrect", 
		"option_c": "Correct, but it only involves financial resources", 
		"option_d": "Incorrect, as it primarily focuses on short-term objectives", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110108", 
		"question": "25OxZJ2z2Beq440lEhz+xPP0JjGQMWcWqnCNU680YH3iWqnLYOq+3pZiZ1qAn0hvsmPVpqGw8Vwdz6xe/4uTfzIOe4V7iNmHl/D/wTFEMtRIg8AjvcpPb7RC1X25fNGbH8FR8VG/GAXkbyuyEXd81CXejzxTu5e69yuyR9I6xRsm1oh+rdw0OZeg5pes13KHxMWqmUdhzenOUglKBNT77Uc=", 
		"answer": "24C2YYX21VnZ44Q0Vw2+hcn6O2XVEHEUpj+1U694dWijdbLWZuLswINoZTvcX/qayLN26do6uul6bDE=", 
		"explanation": "24e9b5j83xjmt5UsUxD8zPP4dW3fESIVpmmGXqxkfXTtQOfVb/6+z55jNEjJnVJ0/HPDsaD0t1oBz7xT7M6acTAPZ8s+kYDZxKT13TFVO8MEr4578J8bPMdUzSmoZ5TPKOxh22mIZ1H4YnmJAX56kSLFj3kWnoK3+SKiFPsi1B09hI5s9Ig1Mt6L0KmH4Vu9xjqM6HOUCIlSMBSJp8Gi7kCI4IE3o8iftDab5PXrjuuT/9hLcQ1Euog/cE+9g60auCs2VYi1YR9O9aTRdRTkLjymIBwc7c7nlnV7w4NpWWwi8RNJko5TbNQz4pDhrjc2MN9vWXOuq0EAxZh9URyFNLyq1Sjl41YqZ3s/YIZ0/Cs8rQOZLBYnsnbfvSU8R10nGHG96Qor", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "United States, Tennessee Valley Authority", 
		"option_b": "Russians, Moscow Planning Group", 
		"option_c": "French, Paris Regional Committee", 
		"option_d": "Germans, Berlin Development Board", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110109", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQF2cDrmzDRapgeDH3XKLLfK39xoVjIk+ZglV/+3jB46P19kcana1Is8ybFE73onh/8rVPZAGXq+uT", 
		"answer": "25K3e4H/0BequsUTXQj7wOm/O2rECm0fonPDQq91fn/qWqCOLsDxx5l0Mxy5gVp1sjuGiqv0/lAOm6FN7M6PfCMNcIJhz5CA2aTR1nBPMMMI2rR36pQab+dFyX2bddjXJecu73uUL0ribi2kRD00pjTRg3NYqY/75Su6WtQ+zhJyn4lx+cE9KN6J3Oia5g2sjgPC6UiwBP1CKGTZ+I6b5FWVpZZ65zlsyC/lv7N7I6mPUqpzbw==", 
		"explanation": "25K3e4H/0Beq5YAmVwzhhenwdX/YBiIirGmKV7c0RX/qW6mFfa3wyIN4KFKIgRt+8XnIrKj59BMfg6lV54eRd2IOcY9qxJC12dD/wTFsPMhKn5Qy1JYecrRJwn2LZtXVI/suy3aFKlX8bj+0AXQ0nT/Sg39XvIqt8GerWNs5zhw8kcdE4+kyOJeL0a3T3Ei2iAORz36UCItlHVicrI6J/leUr5AxodTNpjPItPW5iP3U+dEFYwQSu4NpZlezh6UM9j54QcS1ZhxC/+OQaFrkNCGiMwcL/Ivq2DR9zodpaFoVtCtOh5FTZM9h09SksyIkNsJkVRD6rkVUxJx5TFeCfLj4xG327UZ/YnM/bcp5tCg8s0+dK1driGqISWxVkZNo7NkJgQ1sc3wCehc0YwR0DHEaXyMuKs2NWA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Gosplan,Soviet national planning", 
		"option_b": "Monnet Plan,Indicative planning in France", 
		"option_c": "Tennessee Valley Authority,Regional planning initiative in the USA", 
		"option_d": "FYP,Soviet", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110110", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fLfa3q24J0Z12Lgk5vsmLOpuX/5VoIhqYb5ojfdSEMcIRiwdPJx+j2yn9IPcEb2rx8144eaPFNyTO5NIWbFPZrjl2PMUz1c3mICnl7mnHfh2xarY6++zO+UJojyBBykI5q/tx8MtaL0Ked6UH4gwWN0nScQb4kAViYu46U5XCIoZY9uMiDpXKJtMDxn7jmw54Cbxheuot6bU+5k+gd8C94V8GmewYL/+XEaFvjISTjIg0S98Tu33cp1o4oUykI+ixSg5dTb8V9wti3/BQiPsNpEHOzrlRMwpl5UQOTcP2s2G2k5lwtZm5ra4t5tSI7oAPcLVdxlGSRRS8RhIxq8JAlmzd3fHtFkXPuln/fwEyBeJriq4nxleT1rbxt5qYjaVWIMBzeX58PcfPOJnN7xeeaAeZZMJBpGC/vPpU+8Dj3YgYri0EScp5QhVYL4EcyHQ0=", 
		"answer": "2+T4Z5//yFtqIB4th9O9apMH4n7ZyUrT", 
		"explanation": "25C7Z5/83BDpt5UsUxD8zPP4eSvRECIQ42yaQbdxfXD3XaSCb/3u25hwJFTJmVQ79n/Upqbk/l0Iz6lV7c6cfy0ReoJhycSA2eO3xX8BNsVLlI9//d0MPOZF3zK4ZtfeM7IuyW+JKUD0JymvC319mjTYiXkWrJap/Cm8FM4/xVVgxpNwrcs5MsOKy7HT3EW9xjWNynKUXP1RH12Wu4Lo/k2YpZB4vNme8THe+uDrm/Ta6tsPIg1RsIhwblK/17sQ6z49XIT0fxNYse3eZVHoJGisKQtd9s2jwnxshocoT2U98QxSwoJYZoB+2Yvw/Dw/K8xoGTb6plxByoRwWgTWe7v42WX07FAycHQ/bIRq/Cx1rw6IIVtwm2fcSS9emo9m99NZhQhicy90lHOgsTCdiWCbPKbt4o/ywvuwhrB19+4eLECSdWzUV4MPKfPJKW5mw+iPCKIcMYYnPS31OMUmvArtIZqd0XkE3pk0J3KnpXPLwt65eWSzvpf9zsB5VK0BJtjB5dL3uVLDdDD1M3SSasLuXEjkR3m40AFwuQw30WER5maYG4xrtT4dm325T01n0jPhfnukgq0c7I2cP54j3PH53iYZl/o4npXzlBk5UQG3gm9Ot4qLc1Jzw2PeF8EChAY6BLETVJXe52OCh3/VWDwBdsXzQbyPxmx96a+xqHN8sZMLGcyPIh2bo9AiwRbxAPFqWifkpZb1OPEQBHAp/vJ0yeKvuMeydrO0IGQkYRO5Xq9K54dQfAd8GA7OSWRbaL3uZZIISOVbkkDEnghGB3ZaRVne/qwBSQGu6tPBemKec7gTABvncboLFI7sRkKPNv6nyzXZEv+Tmwe/H0okWjOSL7EBpRTze4D3ZCe7lnph/873Nx0bd5cWKCL+cWWt5fLDAhV6ayQgaJ5Vb0KVWAQlgDvOIvdzzaYCfw05AbyvHBAZhBhIljCSAV4FtU8RUaqgSVBnOqVELlUYwzD39j9DMJ2/v7vvKuRI4c/mHA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "3 and 4 only", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110111", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut5EoV17Byuv2MH+QNmwYrHHDW65kfHTuUanWLuTq2td3Lk6amRt9+2DD47z19kFPiqtU54GSeSFDboduxo/LzN5X5wJezj6SPqlPqXgn7A==", 
		"answer": "yOzqMJ/q1VlGfRbzBOU8ZjgyH3s=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHA3g/j8pFgZxD7yvO/NGXeDHcfoHqHEqJ6dDHqWbfOa+D7x4N0IxyAmUg79H/UsLGw8VoZiuhC7I+NMCwCaoJgxtGFl+H0y39OPs9H2pB+5ZRfdfoAnWT/LJTOLvpr3C6qKFb1dzH9N2R1mDjYykBYnIu+5yK9W8gyjFVjz9UgrcEvfMOX3OiS606tlAeW2TuQRq5zFEbblAbyKIuDgdPjk4dComtKDQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": 1917, 
		"option_b": 1945, 
		"option_c": 1950, 
		"option_d": 1928, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110112", 
		"question": "24GwbdHA3g/j8pFgXxH2wPG/Om2QE24QrXGKXKQ0dHjxUaTWYvS+wJl3K0mMg1h+9jbRq6zz/xMAiehP4Yvfdi0PcoR4wd6Ol+f40X9VIc9BicBz4o4abrR3wy+hcJTsIewunDG8KXbkZi24CXV6gHGHyllXu5f70DKpW8oywRtymIZs5McyL5ej15uH6Vm9iwOMyDvDCJx3GFWX9c2n/k2Isos9po2xvwHP9eD8l/3d5J5YIj9XrJI/Rk6umLgM+SR4X8mgYR1F4qTsb2f5ITymKgsT7Yu3llho0osnHUg58Q1PgYJYIsN8w5bwrjs1LI8c3CTrZV3d2PHhtTl1BU2D", 
		"answer": "2+T4Z5//yFtqIB4th9O9apMH4n7ZyUrT", 
		"explanation": "25S+fJThkS7l5YkkEinz172teSvEC2dRkHCVW6ZgMETtXajMKf6+zJR+KVOEhFg783jC47X/+1obhqta5c6WfiQPa45hy9XJ0vzjwX9FNsIEjo8y958JeeZBwH2IdcfPYNt73GGQIkT+Jze8EHl7miKWnnRXvMO49Cq+FM85xBAg1o5s/ogvLN+ay63T50v4jwiE0G6URr5hUWCRsN2tq02dtIs3u97B8SHO9/y5m+uT5NYOIgtdqohrcVK5hOgA9modUNugbQBFscHFc1v9JWivLgUYufvs2nVnws5pfnMx9xdJkY9ZdMF435mo/BolMcprByr240VOw9RzSx+TZq70kGng70UrcH5rYIlisiI4qAzcOFh/lGWVQisRmY9v+9wK1RdqcGZMnWSgljDLlG2KPKDs/Yn5kajFrrBs/OQ0aUKFO0jKV4EVf7bEZ3d+y+eVBKhbc4x+BDbjMJUa9DDqYJ+a2TUY1dcjKjfw9TnZgsznLWy5pp74nNhvVK8SOdzM5865pBzDdCahNXLTcsPxGRj/Q3Xs2g1ku1gkxiVQ5WvUAZ1+5zRNnXG+XVZrnmfldHmzgrtYqoCXP5o51rXf0iQZneA4qpX+2xN8Tgr7mXdKocSNSltGwlqWGtgVzQcpTKAJEdby/WGS1UHRWTwIbc+0sg3GYuPRrON0E4ei/NAIKw==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "2 only", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3 only", 
		"option_c": "1 and 4 only", 
		"option_d": "1 only", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110113", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrl4os0QAey1fTwO27VEWcV42uLV+N1dH7zQK7NYK3xz9d4KViAjlpv+2DD46Dz+F0AgqFYqZ6TcSwNd4Vol5KPFUceOeAL0L1kF5enQMZX", 
		"answer": "25OqaZ/w1FvS8sIJ+AtFv9W4PT6iEZRY", 
		"explanation": "25OqaZ/w1Fn99pZgRhb3hfv2J3jEQ2EetnGXQLo0ZH6jVaPNfvm+wJl1Ll+ImVJt9zbDoKr++F4GjOhL5Y+RfisNectu3JCd3+G3ynBVOslKm4wy6J8JefgAzTu5ccabIvttwWOJKUKwZnmwDWhxkHHTiXNYp46iuWeuWtY+yxBygo99rfszKt6azeia5V29lAeW1W2UCK1oEFqXvMCvq06TpIc09fGDhTre5vH/lerWvJ4tcAlcvIM/akj8g6AMuCs7Ut2maQZOseXeckPoMmptToobaSvhNQeyl3w3jXyZ", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "United States", 
		"option_b": "Soviet Union", 
		"option_c": "India", 
		"option_d": "France", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110114", 
		"question": "25y1eJTh0A3j4YBgQhLzy/P2O2yQBWcQt2qRW61zMHLmWrPQb+H305J1Z1+Gg09p/XqGtKTjt1UAg6RU/oubMCsNPpxnwdOBl+/+ynUBPMAE2oVx65QQcf1F32LvyHqNsKV18TMrSCekPZUfJw==", 
		"answer": "24a3a5jy3RD548UhXBqyxvLyOH7eCnEF43qAXa17fXjmR+XVUL+RjipANdEqBxWWCVN3", 
		"explanation": "25y1eJTh0A3j4YBgQhLzy/P2O2yQAGoQsX6ARqZmeWvmUOfAd632wJB5Z0+djE9+snXJrbHi+F9PjqZfqYqWYicAaoJ5zcPJwOXkhGFTMsVQk4N34NoQcvhZjDSjNMfUI/dvwmeTMwXxaT39B395mSTYg29C6Ia4+im0WdMy01V+1pJ24cE3OZeW1+iQ6V2xkgeO1WiFCLJ2UVmQrcusq0afr4w3uMSIonLn+sDxn+rW9tEZZ0QSrIl8alqwnrsduCs2VYi3Zx9G5OrZckCtJSusKQEQ8M7wln16hpYhWCk19xxTkIJCZ4By2IvzuSBy2faTFTRL3Ic6wNtZ8up8FA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Capitalist economies", 
		"option_b": "Mixed economies", 
		"option_c": "Developing economies", 
		"option_d": "Socialist and communist economies", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110115", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrl4os0QAeywOX6OHvcCmQYpnvDRqtxMGH2RqLReq34xoV8Z1OPzVJ24nPUorH54VZPiqtU54GSeSFDboduxt6A2eOohjNeTv/Fkr16S/CMnRoUAWg=", 
		"answer": "25awYZ/yk9BH1YaxDsp+xF4cFnm7jI0=", 
		"explanation": "25a3ZZzm3xD548UDWhf8xL3tMHvCBnEUrWuGVuNgeHSjRLLQa/7qiYF0NU+AglU7/XCGqqjg8kEOm6FN7M6PfCMNcIJhz5Ce3+HlwTFAP8oEiIVh648Nf/FTjCqoZtGbL+lgy2rAJkv0JzqyCmRmmz3aj3gWqpr74S++FMkjwQE31rt22cA5LtKZ1rqWpA2bjg+M3TuYW/1wGVHZtM2r/lGdtId4tMOepjfJtl9VeRr+yXX2KG5z4zFGwGk=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Soviet Union", 
		"option_b": "Hungary", 
		"option_c": "Poland", 
		"option_d": "China", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110116", 
		"question": "24KwZ9Hj2Bbk8oAyVxqy0fX6dWjfDWEUs2vDXaU0fXDxX6LWLv7xyp5wK1WagBty/DbPrrX15VIbhr5eqZ6TcSwNe48vzdOG2ev6zXRSbITPALwqnzyyEVuIX/liz1Zj", 
		"answer": "25qrY5DhkTXr+YIlEA7XFlBicz1rND0abQmmpfI=", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX2wln+/4Q0Ei79yfTsPSvVAG0frHKKQbc0X2LoVbWCQuzwzpIxJFOAg15/snfIp+Xg/lwBiq1J7IrfZCoGPoJrzdHJ2OK3yXBTOMNQ2pN955MecP1TwX2kepTSLe5r3G+ULlP1JymxBX56nT/RynlVp420+C6+R5Z3/BsnmItx5s18M8OX3LqAqEC9iBKL03WUTP1QGVGLsMin+UbQ4K0rvsyf8R7a+vP82vHAsMoDZ0hRsJRtZlio16kH6z09Q4p1mQeW8JnBNj872CRICQwY", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Joseph Stalin", 
		"option_b": "Mao Zedong", 
		"option_c": "Milton Friedman", 
		"option_d": "Oskar Lange", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110117", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MUpXBr7xvzrPH3VQ3IdonGNW61zMGbsRqyCeuXsxoJ2LwPLAPVFjpy4nJeHTaPCKlv+0g==", 
		"answer": "25i5epr2xVnr+YFgQgz7xvi/JnLDF2cc4bd0dsqEwuZeP1pWSfzFmUI=", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJjw0A3j4YBgQhLzy/P2O2yQD2cHpm2CVaZnMGXrUefPb//1zIMxIVObjl5osnfIp+Xg5VoMiuhI8J2LdS9Da4VjwduMl+361H5SOshD2oN36o4NffhJ1jipNNfULup8wWLAG0vEbzyvAXZ7hjSaynFXuoi+4We6Wt530Ac7lYI4/tEvKNKSmaGAqFmwg0aD33iEWrxwFBSYu92/7lHe8BF6WOQZTVXbhhn604PaHw==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Central authority directives", 
		"option_b": "Production quotas", 
		"option_c": "State corporations", 
		"option_d": "Market and price system", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110118", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQE24QrXGKXKQ0ZGjzUbSCeeTqwddlL1mAnxt4/WTUprbg+F0LhqZcqYiacTYWbI58kpIBHe+zKNVkRcscCz702JP5", 
		"answer": "25y1eJTh0A3j4YBgQhLzy/P2O2yQTiIypnGXQKJ4eWvmUOfBYePq25h9ZxrJnk965nOGrLL+8kEch6FLpc62fiYKfYp7wcaMl/T7xX9POshD2s0y0Ykab7RNzS+mccCbM+d92muNZ0T+Y3mtFnlilSXTym9Tq5e052epW9YyjFUUg4l7+cEzMtaTmbif6UO2jwiFnDbRW61hEl2fvM3o+EaftI0q+Y2ptDHe+uDrm/Ta6tsPIhhevohxalW71+UF/TkrEc+7fhdZ/+nVb0CtMievIkz7eldOI9D8h5Dlih6+HD2g", 
		"explanation": "25a9ZoXh0BXj7YAkEg7+xPPxPGXXWSJZinKTV7F1ZHj1UefSYuzwx55/IBXJzW9z+2WGqraw9hMclrtP7IPfZyoGbI4v3NiMl+P40nRTPctBlJQy55URaOZPwC7tddjXYP993muDM1awaD/9EHhx1DTVhXJZpZr3tSGpW9d30Ac9kpJ7+cEzMpeL1uiX4V6slA+AyW+YR7MkJVyc9cmn/UaOro89u9nNojfP57TpiPfX5d0fawdc/4FwYlev2+gI9CY3UsmgbQEL4+HDbkH/Iy2wa04c98+j0nF9w5AkVGcx519WkIpVZ9Mz9Z3qqCAxM8RwEDf6s0hByZp1URDWfa74327w5Vt/dGk4aolkvTkwpU+LIUB22miTQSFQmoQr+9MWmwtudGpT0DbzlzyDwGScPIfr7sDPiv75pa0jx60uJk+8O3jdVYgScaHBK25oz+3bHapdPZFuGSW8feEm9Sq5KYXU3nkeyco0Knqn4yKcgMi1LW2/85X2mNFkGrIFOMWF+ce2qU+HYGPtJG6AJs/9Sw3zWzzq3AJg9xEriDUY7SLdC4Zx+iAU3kq4TARjnTHlfnKsk7BIqpGLa51x0efj3DZQn/t5k4i7lB8pU0SvhXoDopaWWV1byBTFG84TyxtuBadBBpPC4mKYhn/SR3lNecHkQaWI0DgI3+D+gG5wtpNOVI+aJQ/Snsdm7BKyBPNtR2bhoZz8ObwFBmUi9Lt/za2opIq0c+ehIiUrfAm4WuZY55BVKBVyBQOdCCVda726FpgdTu5A33zPhEsIVGpKDRrN6OgcVQHqn8rBem/aI4IIDwrncI8LJ8b9XEKPNOOsiDHFFbDcmlO2WlZlWiONJKNN6gGwf4/9Khy+mmsk6c3kPF9SSoRbfDTmd2P5pLDZNwgGcQUrLINEe1PcXRVkhDLCKfdug6BaMCwlSLvnEENWl1Fchi3GC1UFp0QbTaDtVFsiaq5KNl4DwzqwH7RfTA7FkDMOi0XcxTflLftFMkxjemqXz0XumJdoi/b/h53BDNvwbakT180TOr9NRY7TX0gZmefr/a2gE3ktRml4K+uIUO3F8Ev/EM33ts/DhV9Ex6oaOVN7IDqEh5DU+TktLqZbZmZDqWpZhcTWawWrzYFP0BB4XFTi+0jqRicopVF8aIfuZJ3JOZ6hsFlRVinOT7xH2Pl70iLrONbUd1Z/FHY2mUeRZZLjyTCKPJD15rgHBgyr2JfKScp94El3wNW8xBYAnzN8nDzrGDbbIvT0+wpRLzxvQ7GNHx1JjhJi0jWn20HmMIqkk+YPgbNUy7AAoQP54jJmil2FSUPNI2Dv3eKRpXWGsUFh3aJmHGOgVH1iwxVoBOM+8XEuQT5hSKZmtbXgIKXRjGTvIY74wI0D8FBVRbPfPbS1upXaMK3GO6zj14GPb2Lt8J1nDfuoZdcWYHnLcDgR5KvnZ4CEZAfTP2SK2K6WET+HKi4b+XB6kiKBQBBpPyCnUtlYDXZdlsJmL7gfqsfqt3ZrT3rBDrhp1eEZl1pXAllXTaahrHlEC7hrKs6dMkx07EIZBK8CYmilbApib9kG3GyiRjWh5iyyl/poC9T+hhFqaASUhzCAfDXP+OpgIy2pH8bM0YOLCwe3tP0vTxFf8+hXkQuDCXEYdSVloALNmuh7QRm/fhE4N/8eh8wZStf5vwsJ1sg0RgIcfXzWXS+qHpyEQ9pLGJKmxrsi64gbyDlNCZACOIiLVAbMgWebE2tBPENMYgSOgh/74ot4xdvNHhWA4iSzxtDhCVbQs3NUm9LzWMaZWMKpF0bN+4glFdsLH2k=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Imperative planning,Centralized control & state ownership", 
		"option_b": "Indicative planning,Uses market system and private sector role", 
		"option_c": "Functional planning,specific sector", 
		"option_d": "Decentralized planning,less government role", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110119", 
		"question": "25S+fJThkS7d3qxsEhP91um/O27HD3tRqnGHV7NxfnXmWrOCbeLrx4NjLlmazVdy+XOGiqv0/lJPhqZS/YeefC4aPoprx8Cd0uC303BSbITx8lneAmgRo8zZEABP4pVw", 
		"answer": "25y2bJjw0A3j4YBgQhLzy/P2O2yQFGsFqz+KX7NxYnD3XbHHLuTwypt4KV2dhFR14TT00xCBlJkhyTHhpUo1eqlQ", 
		"explanation": "24KwYZ32kRTl5JFgXBvlhfTxMW7ABmwVpnGXEqB7ZX/3Rq7Hfa3uxoRlamu+pHI783LJs7H18xMGgaxS6o+LeTQGPptjyd6H3urwhHxON8NIicwy2JQSffpZjDGkf9GbCfBqx2/AL0T0Jzj9F2Rmmz/Ryn5fqZD74SisVcgz01U7m5d9/8koNcGamauW5lmqhwqLxn6VCK1oEFqXvMCvq0qSqZYxtMGBqHLv/PHrn/7c4ttHIhxausZsd1qokqUM9j54WNv0aRFI5PbRdVGvwinB0qt+orTpj9e71VESLg==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Imperative planning models", 
		"option_b": "Regional development planning", 
		"option_c": "Laissez-faire policies", 
		"option_d": "Indicative planning with imperative inclinations", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110120", 
		"question": "25ateoP23w3m7slgXxHh0b38On7eF3AYpmzDUaJ6MH7tWL6Cfv//yoN4JFnJmlNy8X6GqKz+8xMAiehe6oGRfy8Kfct/xNGH2e35wy4Dg8Z3holZTTu0JwmymLQtbA==", 
		"answer": "25y2bJjw0A3j4YBgVx39y/LyPGiQE24QrXGKXKQ25XkzlA2sRsJb/zWIlZc4Jg==", 
		"explanation": "24WqbYL23w3m7slgXRD+3L32O2/ZAGMFqmmGErN4cX/tXanFLuH735JjJluAg1w7/3fUqKDkt1UAnate+s6WY2IFe4p8wdKF0qT+yjFMPNVQ2oVx65QQcf1F3324etjSK/sux2OQIlfxczCrATB7hnHfhHpZuo66+WerWNs5zhw8kcdE4/w0OcWa36eB7QH4jwiG1XiQXLRyFBSctsGm5E6Vo8IoucyDvzvV87TwibjH+NtLYwtRqpR+d178lqYa7y8qExk/aPFeYvOtmz9QonK3WAs=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Imperative planning", 
		"option_b": "Informal planning", 
		"option_c": "No planning", 
		"option_d": "Indicative economic planning", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110121", 
		"question": "25y2bJjylgqq5I0pVAqyw+/wOCvZDnIUsX6XW7VxMGXsFK7MauT9yIN4MVnJnVd6/HjPraKw+FAMmrpJ7IrfZysXdst4wNmK36T4wjFVO8MEnI9+6JUIdfpHjDi7cdrPM6EsXihkXO9lzfAK8SZYw+3zjw==", 
		"answer": "25C7Z5/83BDpt5clVBHgyO6/Om2QUjtI8j17loyT49so4nyuHyulyuz8", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJjylgqq45chXA370fTwOyvWEW0c43aOQqZmcWXqQqKCeuK+xJhjIhyAg19y8XfSqrP1t0MDjqZV4ICYMCoCbptqxtWNl/P+0HkBJ85B2oVx65QQcf1DjDGkdtHJIfJn1G+ULkr+Jyu4An9mmSKWhXoW+dripGe6Wt530hA2g4Rx4898L8Oeza3T60K2khSN0DutRolsFEacs8G67g/cpYE3u8KAuDGb5vH/lere454EZEgD5t8uI1Kv17wB/Wo5UsuhehNf9KTRb0f6JTrhLJDpS083XZQBI6wCOoD1/Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Green REvolution", 
		"option_b": "Liberalization in 1980s", 
		"option_c": "Declaration of Emergency", 
		"option_d": "Economic reforms of 1991", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110122", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3FKbMaq39xplyK0mahFR1qErIkLHx41YCiqZPs862fiYKfYp7wcaMl/T7xX9POshD2pdz99oeePtQ2DipNNbCYPNn1muEZ0DzaDeyCXlxh3HqhF9ZpoC34DSyW9RtgDwm1ot9+80uPdCa3eie6V+zgxKRkDuERrFtGlHZvMO47lGdtIsusI2dvTPV+v33nbr5F6/I8aWHlwkNc/JYUMWu", 
		"answer": "24asaYX23Bzk48UpQV7m1+j6eSvzDGwSr2qQW6x6MHjwFLPQe+i8w5fMRLuVjJ48ILkUn+pACQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHgxRj+8oglXAqy0fX+ISvZDWYYoH6XW7VxMGHvVanMZ+P5iYBwNByZn1p45n/FpqGw9UpPgqFD7IrfdSEMcIRiwdWal+3khHBCMNNWm5R3pKYRSPxFjD6ietfXNe1nwWDAM03xc3m0EDB5lTXTymlFrcO082e2Vcg8xQEh1pJ24cE3OZeW1LiW+kysjxCHnGudSbNqGFqe9ce7q0KQs414od+YtHKbwPz8iP3V/8wOLkhdr5J2bFX8s+gA62osWc30ax1Z4+HTdRTuKCeqJAtf7RPvCj+4SHi0Pd3jssQ53g==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Statement is false, Conclusion is false", 
		"option_b": "Statement is true, Conclusion is false", 
		"option_c": "Statement is false, Conclusion is true", 
		"option_d": "Statement is true, Conclusion is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110123", 
		"question": "25u3epzyxRD88sUwXh/8y/TxMivZDWEesW+MQKJgdWKjQ6/LbeW+xpExM1SMzV10/nrJtKz+8AxNAa0Lh/VnFzHO8gr1T2zXTg==", 
		"answer": "24a3a5j8nBr/+5E1QB/+hfv+Nn/fEXFRtnGPW6hxMHv2R7OCa+7xx5h8Ll/JglV+4TSdxmwD1OLxVlG6d5DtrhOi", 
		"explanation": "25u3epzyxRD88sUwXh/8y/TxMivWDGEEsHqQEqx6MGLsV67NI+7rxYNkNV2FzV168WLJsbaw4l0DhqNeqZqXdWINf5l9x8fJ0uf4yn5MOsUEnI9x8Ylfc/IA3yS+YNHWM75+wm+OKUz+YHmBCkR8kSPTjHNErc/74S++FMkjwQE3m4J2+Yg0NdCX1aGU4FmxiAHCyHOUCLltAkCQu8284kyS4Isr9cyOsifJ9eD82BvJM5RsEAIcNAOkzMidI4o=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Mainly economic and financial factors", 
		"option_b": "Primarily administrative targets", 
		"option_c": "Largely environmental sustainability", 
		"option_d": "Socio-cultural factors unlike just economic ones", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110124", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3z54BgXRiy1fH+O2XZDWVRpXCAR7BxYzHsWufRYe73xtpyMlCdmEl6/jbAoqbk+EEc0Oomh4t+DxqtmJEJ9td/2RsF", 
		"answer": "25u3epzyxRD88sUwXh/8y/TxMilZk1zXnAWVy1+35Z8x6OYs", 
		"explanation": "25u3epzyxRD88sUwXh/8y/TxMivAAnsC436XRqZ6ZHjsWufWYa33x5R+NUyGn1pv+3jB47b/9FoAwqtO5ZqKYiMPPo1uy8SGxfe3xWIBPNZUlZN34NoLc7RQ2S+oeM2bJf1hwGGNLkawYTi+EH9mh3HqhEherZG+8yipUZZ3zhogm4Zs5N45fMeT2Kad4UO/xg+RnG+ZTf1lEleMp8+87gOdrpEvsN/PbR+xhyVPsxsynMLzYaF39A==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Imperative planning", 
		"option_b": "Indicative planning", 
		"option_c": "Informal planning", 
		"option_d": "Normative planning", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "110125", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmoiN9Ev5t+b2uXjzWdEc9ZIm4587ZQYPOdVxSm+NNfUNfB63GeFNAXnbi21RHxxhyKWmXNVoYK3tSOyQt8l0xwmj8dE4/o5PcSQ1+ChoRf4rxLC2XaBQLx3GE6cpo675ECVr887oMGZpCDa+LT/m/vH/8wYIIkgXoaJ7PyiGW40kwWi15A=", 
		"answer": "25T4YYKzxQv/8sUiRwqy9732JivWAm4Cpj3Wwp/h42rtYypUKGgM3ijo", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCy0fX+ISveDHAcomuKRKY0YH3iWqnLYOq+wIQxK1manhto53/Soqf88hMJgLob6oGKfjYRd458iMeAw+y3zHhGO4ZXlYN75ZZfeP1WyS++fcDCYPd9jnqSMkCwJwWzLH9jkSfTmDAWvIu+tTW+Vck4zlU7mIR3/9o5P8OTwOiA/EysgxXC1W/RTbB0GVWKvNSt+AOPr4ExuoCOpD7P4eb4lrjV8d0fbRpB/5F3ZlX8nqZJ/is7RYi6ZwBG8PDZd1GtMCSiKQAU98yj0nts1cIvUmoh519JjMNSa9Z2xIvh/CE/PMRrGXO8okdUyIZvHwKYeLSz1Sjr9F06Zzo/fJpor20BqQqOLVJxiG7QDDhZkcBq7cMchxBqcmEAlWWgli2ehSWNaYej/4j5xfr1oaps/OMuOgGGNFDLU8+87nxIKiVKZsO6HYIuKbPT", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Economic Planning  >> Introduction to Types of Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "A and R are true, R explains A", 
		"option_b": "A and R are true, R does not explain A", 
		"option_c": "A is false, R is true", 
		"option_d": "A is true but R is false", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120101", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/2CUuPJwY4xMF2azU9z9zb1rLP58kdPgqdf7ILffyRDe4hgxt+E3ue31H1APchNlIcy7ZQZcOFFwimkddibIfNhwGnADkv0bjizRHxxlTXTmG8WoY374S++FItuk0Uhybt2vIgINNLf6qeF4UisxjOM1XSfCLxnGV2co8usq0uVp4p4vMOJpCHP5v34lrjS/tpLZwtdsYlyalj8kLoG7z4wEdq1fBdYsfDYc1v4JyDjNwIc98Xm0jRtw5QsUWYk+RpIlr9YMIBa2JztvTxwM8hrETaosARXxppoWhPWYLL41WXx7FQrcDo/bY8tjyIjqAqIaERxlmKIRS9QmMBq8NRZhgtgdG5M3HvvhjqHvGvcPKfr7sDvkOvzpapwsqwhaXKPI1XdQs0MabLOKW58zamYAqhIIZ50AyfifcIn6DG5I4SdzDAekNguKzfu+i+flMT2MGC0sJv8nZR5Ev8DN8HM/cq7uU/TISbiLnOca8LxSkjgQG/skxptslgC2iQR/CL8DZlt8D4el3G+dUpXlyvlb2jhgrZZqpGafpo03vDiySFQjPx5i9vyzA0wRg21zWhLq8SLR1kP/lvAF8gThAQhCLENVJ/f9GGDkHjTTnhNVsDyCKmJgyBN2+f0nHIn/U1qC0XNCp4AL5Wn3RH9rpo=", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqol5tyMTgvamx+yDS5tdxxbQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHm3wn48oYlVhv80fj7dXjFAGEUsGzDXaU0Q371XaLWLuP/3Z5+KV2FzUt383jIqqv3t1oBz7pa+YebfDtDd4Vr3cOdxe32yHhbOshD2oF84NoYbvtXxTOqNMDTJfd8jmuDKEv/aiD9AnFnlzjYi2hTrMOS+yOyVdR3zhQmn4h27MQ1L8Pf1a2S7EiqlUrCy3OeCKphA1HZvsut5QOIr8I5scKdpXLY8frtiPnfsM4HYwZctoh4I0+z16wM7i80Xtj0fBpOseXXc1X/KSmtZycT/cLi2DRsxY0nUmQttCNItotTIsR2xorhryE5MMMnHTqu40dB151oXhufZ6n41Wvr7loyfH84JZp/szs8pQqYaFU+mWSSWD5Qh5Qr6dgQlgwje3pSiH7lkH+KlHGdfZD37oS8rOb0qbhtsq8iKEWFJ0+YQoJccbvFZ1R93OCeGeZRPJtiG2LVKdQ6+TT8LoLUjXkEw5kpIXTo5jickdm1OHb6mpz9h9V4VLMFN9XA+9j3sVjKaDHkJT2Hbs60XAv/QXP12g0lpxQkxi8Z5mWUSIdw4W0ZlnvwWUtomzPpb32t1rNT7oeCPb4z0YtJ1Xm97JpyPiJMkeo=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 3", 
		"option_b": "only 1", 
		"option_c": "1 and 2", 
		"option_d": "None of the Above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120102", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iP3J4e3k0nRSJcdWm5lzpJUKaPhJwjipNNWbLfFqy2LAIUriJymxBX56kTWWj39Zpoy27GeyWpo/yQZylIh35ogsKdWT0Lub7Un4jwjCjSLCHP1YH2actN2n5QPUksti9eSDtTvatOP4ibjV8d0CbA8SvsZ8cVKvnrtJ9yx4QceibQBf6KTRb1CtNSanIhwZ/N3m2nt5y4cnSSV05hpXl4pEa850lpvhsiYiPsFjDza+41RMxppyVhmRNLu3wij24UU2cToia454rzknqA6QIU5/jmKTQmxQmoQr+cIWghBrP5sO7CZCESoPxq7xCbx2K60=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiITtmvDYON9YzHNe5OCeuX7iZR+NU6Mjk87927Wr6T+9kcGgKYb74GNMANBWIw6+w42FTFjZvVfnfAwyw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywgrv5ZEpXRCyjdy2dWreByIFq3rDQKZ1Y37tFO/wJ63/25IxJVOdhRt4/WTUpqbky10zgYUb34eMZicQaIp9ycmIm6T2hGFTPMtNlIV88No2cvBJzTPtcdrcKfBry3zAJkv0JyqpBWRxhzzXhDAWp5av+S61Ud53wVU/mYN94Yg6M8XfyaSS5kO9gkaH33SfR7B9UV2X9cah+AOer40z9fHPgT7a+vr8nrj289EFbQVL/4BwcRuVmawA+RZ6Edihah5C4uzVZRTkLmjyfl1JuePmlnV7wZcsWSkg/B5SwqpYZslylpbhuTY1O41+GnO7p0tQ09R9HweadbO21Wyk5VYwe3UmfMpksm06swuZOhRqlSudSChDkZN4vsQRkERgb2ZTlWWgjTnLkGqZeYH38sD9i+ywtbdn97EjLFeFOVPIW4gScfPUL2Zmiv2TCOZfPIppAzD/fcIv73n/IZWd0T5N+NxgP2Xo5CWKl8m1OCWutpy0l9F3Bv8QOtDLqdy+pFSHdSvkYXyaa4v7X0j0QGn63wdrsFgxwCRQ4WzbB4R6tSIL3mq4TARnnTLueG64qrBg5LaGes4j1vT/0jxQ0MYx35LklBwwVAv7jnBRoIGcWxxmw1DfH40QxRpuCrUCHZjWsmzWhnPGTm4IP83kCLuO0GxH3KPhgXd4rYQXFY2AKFnOhNoj2hO0F/h1WnfgrYjtffUbSnAk//J0y/+trorpJeesbGYvYQ6iS/YZx51UKAF0BAXJFz0Pd7m9FpEfU+dK3myKlgBaTnxcCU7Z6akEEUS9o9DALmueb74LTg7ncfMGEt7xWkaPPP+qxz3MRr6SkQe2VkMtDjaYN7UB9kf/fMz7KB+6h212+ML8clBVQMMTNTT2dXi85ZeLDhQ/PzskO8pGOkDHRActmjmDJu5mn6IOdQs+AamqFl4R1gVHmn77AFxMsUJeVqu5RV8rI65ALk8CxDb1BageSFzejj9KjVmJzDb+MLpFNEwnfmDTm0OgmpZpj+upg86MBcbnbbAU1ogRJvZaSp6WFlUYj+Dw/ejhHWUjA2k3L+jYTO3Qs0e2Fse0psbMwFBE2bMNOEt5BZm4Zg7E3pPo/77lINQhNg==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "Both A and R are true but R is NOT the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120103", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/2CUuPJwY4xMF2azU9z9zbwqrbm8kAZjrpa8I/fQC4CcMtg3cSF3urywDFDKoZp2rZ794wab+JB3jy0dZTSLr4/lz3UZ0b/aSq0AHVmkTWWnnRT6IWy5zSvFNg71RAihI52+Yg6M8Xf3Kuc5kK1jwXCzHeQRrNtH1PZvMDowk2YqYNnicPc8RvPtOP4ibjR8c0OZkhdscZra178mqcN/SZ4Xs70bBdG/ufCYEDkI2igJh4U7crv32dkhoQmUWU74xpCwopYItR709jRsjskOskqJie7t0FT+5ouHz6CNLyx3W3goEEwNXsnaY97tSwhpE+MJ0J7iH+FDC1fkMB5+9QMlgEjeGxPknntizzLiWuKbYbi54nojO3jnLcwsoozaU6VIVDRWIgYJafIIid8z+yfTaBTId9kEizyL9QivCn1IZia1jcKkNs5b2Pv8WqendvwK2u3tpztstoiVJYUdtfK6t6ktViHbi2hM3yDb8+0UAb0Wm/swQdkuxE/yTUZ52yYCYd7tSkCi3y8QEpj0inheHWumL9QqouAfIE81sni6joZm/w4kJ23wBU5BwK0gXNMpY2RSBxO31GWHcIV1gwtGPQSAJfF92CTm2LDFD53O1zRDMKVI3dcVDqJB+fl", 
		"answer": "2+b4aZ/3kU2oTH6dJ7jRLB/nSQexbLE+Sg==", 
		"explanation": "2729KJf83RXl4IwuVV7h0fzrMGbVDXYC436RV+N3f2PxUaTWNNHw9ZkiZ3WdzVRu5nrPraD0t0cHiuhV7IubMCQMbMtszd6dxeX7hGFNMshKk451pJgGPOBIyX2qe8LeMvBjy2CUG0ukJxCpRHZ7lyTFj3gWp4375yarXd53yRs2g5Rs/8E9MN6F2Lya50P4hwiGnH+eXb9oGFqe9cCp/0qTroM09cSDsj3W8cj3rvDWsOgCcR5XrJB+cVqllug59Cs2Ed+1e1JKsebcdFH9MiGtM04b9tmj03dmyI0kVGp05BNHjI1fbMcz35aklTw0NswqATu7twRXxoc8UAKCeLS21Wyk4kx/WDodbJl7uT4joB2dMVU+k2XcHXUCwMBf9tVZhQhicy9DnXrshzvLhmqdPIfr7sD7iv71srdu960zaVWPdUzUV5RcZPPDImlm2OiXTbRTP5onHiymLdkv8jfwLpHU3jcJkNovIGXj/SSYhsT7PiWuu5e5i9d5GrANL5Hs/Yu2vE/IISXuImiAY8+0VgawXX3o2golvhYh3TIE+mvZBIBl9DkEkXDwSEpg0iPveX6tn7BbqpaGes4/0uHl0jwRlLRxkZj42RgASTi1uXdG8pSTTlIP2lXFXsMI0EksDacEENbe/C2CnXOQRnMJesK2Dq7HxylF1eDjj3V0vNANVJyHOBjXg80riBG+DfF2QmLp6I/3fegdDyQZ9Ltlz+nhhN66Yfa3bEwkfA6yWOsVs5xFKBV6AkvfBDdKZPihWN0KSeUPwmfDmQRBV3NMFhrD/egbSQW+r4TBYH7bcacZAArrbL1FEsD8DlfDNP+nwT7ORouUkAeuU0UrDjuRMr9N4Q70OoL9MFO2i3ho8MLsJl1CBI4SMjP6e2X5sauGSwE1fiBlJ4wHe0vZTgYtlSrKKf4nnagWdQo5WOimF1RWhBRLij3bAF8FtU8RUaqgSVBnI6dAMU4QwT6hGKUMHr0UAAej+9BZfhDmKi/ynDs=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "3 and 4", 
		"option_c": "1 and 4", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120104", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/2CUuPWxoAxI1WNzXY7xH/VtaDj4VIdjrFarp3fciMAdYx9x8WH06T2ynUBNt5Un5J74ZQcebRTxDy9cZTTKe0u2GeTLkr+Jz+yFjBdmjXfiztF6Ia4+im0WdM0gBMngpJq6IgzKcOT0KaW7A2xiEaW1H7RfrR3B1GKo8+66lqd4LI0tMPSjTyKtNzwibjk9c0fZxpc/4N7dli9g6EG9mo1UMyxKBpC/KTWYELiMmigJh4U7crv32d9hoYsS2w4+w9Lh41CIvx9hNjFr3IxMY1vGzSzrUFF1dg8VxLWYry0xW3goFk+Z30uJYNjuDgmtR2VLUc+m2WYDDhUl4hl8dwWkh0jQWET3F7pkX+cj3eEPJrtq5DujObzpbV6srAzKFWFJhzbWYMKbL3DImMywuCWTalac4tvEmLoONAqvD/2MtaX2jcZwtgsJm3i8GqJnsz7N2y0tNK5stoiVJ0FP9/Cqc2lv1GHTDryLm+WJtjgWBz1Azzw1k51pRc1xzIV7CLNG4Bx8m0BkX2xRQRpnSPlYG/hkLFOqoyPa4c+3fTgnTYVjvF0kIv60RMoewqMhXZAusSQSRxbxVGWGMILyAY5BboGVJfD9y2VmmTCTn8ZP93iALyCzilGzvCuzOJxeiJgx6ALLNrr7HjMC3g=", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH13hXm+JIpXBmy1un+IW7dBmwFsD+CQKY0c37xRqLBerfCx6t/dRyonht6/DbDraL5+VYKneQb4YvfZiMPa45riNyIxePyhHhPN9NXjpJ74YlfffpEjCmod9zVL/JhyXe8KRawTzCuRGd7hjqWg3IWuJGy+yS+WMN30wEzgoJrrcszMsGW16uW7A2wjwvC033RXLVhUVqcsMro7UyO4IE9u9mfsD7S7vH92ujf8dAFawZVg4hDbWiolrwM9S82Rdv0OVJK/+CQNRTsMi3jKQEJucjsxGZsxZZpa2An4hpVlIJEY9lykYukizcjK8h4G3O/p1FDxoB1UBnWcLS8kGbr9BUydHEuJYJksW0zoBmTOhR9m3uVWC1dnZN/vtQcgwFvcn9NmXj0whaFwGOOf4evq4j5xf/xs/lisrAzO06OMhzaU4EVYKXFNSd7xKmPBaMcIZBrEmLpO5U69Dy5M4KVyzxN2ddgKnTo+iWUm861PWCstp72ntlzGqtAHtSF6MekvxzDaCehL3KHJtvmVhj/XHm4xh1suR9lxC4T6W6YBYZ78CEe3ni/WwRqkzPpY3Kgmv5Y75SLc4Eh3vDiyXI4nbR6mpf+0Qs5Q0SvhX5X8q2RS1VOjVrTG8kCwEk6A/QAEJnB5i2X1XvfWXlNcsHyBLqJgy1G3qP4gGVorIQcXI2CJQPejp4n2AejDvx6XSf5p8b9OOoQBms897d/3q+OWwcD0iBqhMIknDR0ZEYW", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "2 and 3", 
		"option_b": "2,3 and 4", 
		"option_c": "1,2 and 4", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120105", 
		"question": "25y8bZ/n2B/zt5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRqHqaEqVxcWX2RqLRLuzt2phyLl2diF875X/Sq+Xk/1ZPqYF4yqffYDAMboR8ydzJ2OK3lSgSZ5x4lLx8xdo3dfNIwDSqfMDeJL5gy2uEZ0P/dXm+C31khjTej3JFoZW+tSm6QNM4zhQ+1pd07MYyNdmY5aaxqGu5kAmQ2X/RW6llBVHZutmm7lGPqIso9cKL8TPX+LTwlPzG48oZaw1Bg4hcI3q4gacK+T49VYi4aRtY4uHKLFLsKTqmZx4S9cLg33F6hr4neSkE5hBWjZBTZoBylrblqDs/McxmVQO2okpOzpp7HzSZebCxw3vt71t9LvdrUlqiu3b79j2qdBXnig==", 
		"answer": "25T4JdHXk8nxPCTobUK9kVAomQSZ+68=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH13hXm+JIpXBmyzvjmdW3VAnYEsXqQEqJmdTHiR7TNbeT/3ZJ1Z0uAmVM75n7D44PZ1HAmz7hJ5p6QYyMPPoRpiIHQhLCt+H99Pe5NnYh+7Z0XaPFEjCmlcZTVJftqjmiPNQXzaDStFnV8kT/Fg2pT6I264S60Wts7gAU+l4l25MY7ANmvy6eD5169gkaDnFWQXLRrH1WV9f6k6k2SqYw/9e6CvD/S5+fwlfbv/voCZkhcsJI/ZVqqmLpJ6z45Rc30ZwVF9PbDaV39YCelZw8R9Yvq2HB81ZY7VGwnyBFnhpVZYcFn05ykvXI9NtVvEXO/oEtOyJllHwCfYLX40Sj271k6NXwkd8pvszk94RuULRRuj2mQRS8RlY5vvsALnBJiaWoAj3PjljCZk1mBSJvmq6bVpsvZ4Klx/bMoOkCMdUvZRc0dJb/BKWN/y/uQTaJTMIpqEizyfcEm/S25LJed23kZ2NxgKXjy+i6YhsT6NyW8vIC5i9d5GrANP9KF+ce2vlLObyShKHPTT8XwUAmwZmi4xA929wwtzWEW4XDLHMlr/CAI3mq4SFAkk2ftbXauhP5e/5GHcYsiwLXjzzURlv1ino/+2xN8TwW/zXxCvoiaSxxJwkaWCsUChA4hGrETGpvU/HnWgXmQW3AMZo73QauCzTha2++xnG5xutAHW8yeIBjVhNcoz1ewD/k5VmjiuoLwM/0BA2oruqZ5z62ktMW1ev69bhR9Ezcdlmcx5RQSK4cXdf4=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "A - C", 
		"option_b": "B - D", 
		"option_c": "C - A", 
		"option_d": "A - D", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120106", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R+fDfOi+yJViKFCcmV536zbFrLfi8lAb0JRVwYGIMCYKest7wNXJwe3y02IBI9NQ2oZ99o4XPPZZjBSjcN3aLr5tz36JM0T8biqpFzB9mnHCgnkWioy29yaiFOo7wRtyl4tx6sZ8K96L0eic+g28jwCE2WnRTq9rHBSNvcvo/UqZt5F4usvNpTretPr4jvHc/t8HaxtG/4p6Yl+5hbtJ8SR4RcCxKDx70ruQXVq8YAqsMwZd687g2Xlkw4wtWG105wtHloYWbdd904r3tDsgf8JsVTi/ugRJyZBpTAOEfbirkFTqshUdencpZJMtjCE0r0+aKUJxiG6YDChUl4Vl6sIYmQ15eGsAjHrhjDGCjmLPaZ3v4ov5xcbAg/lf/PBnB3GjdVrXVZgPYLeAKmhgz6mUA+ZdP5NiASvnKdwg+3npL4CRzS0UkM0oLnmn1iWUkMzseVW2spzFgJQiVJ0PItmF7ManuF3UaDnkJT2Hbs60Vw31Szz+3BwlpRk1wSVcqG7ZGo56tT4On3K1CU1qljLzeG6ol7JV8IOadoE/kQ7dJKrbfZpAFV0dwkGfapg=", 
		"answer": "zU7G1qWV8YfycggEM6gleZY=", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX23Bzk45ZgA17zy/m/ZivREWdRrXCXEqB7YmPmV7OCWuX7ibV+Kl6IlBtL/nfI46H58xMBgLwb74+JfzBDbZ9u3NXJ2PP5wWNSO89U2o90pJEaZbRJwjm4Z8DJKft9gi6BKUGwczG4RF5Et3HSg3gWpoyvtSG0V88kgBg9hII44sZ8PduT3L6a6VmxiAHCzHSHTa9wCBSNvc+mq1eUpcIausCPsCubxPj4lMTdzNA4dglGuot6bU/8xegA62o2Xtz0aRBY/ujFdVHhOWigKBwP/Mj3mjRr05ZpVH10/QwGhYZYZ9Jy2pT9/CYiKsgqITu/42ZPypZ9RlemeLy2kGzt5BUxem5rYJJ9sCQ2qBuQMRRzn2WIRSNf1IRu/dUXgRZicWZanWLpjTHHwGeaaNPq/8D4jOywo7hv/uMhJlPANBzVWZ8ZJb/JKm5mz+3bH6lQNt9hGDCmKd0rvCrtIYKRnzADkM0oKjfi9yWXncDseVGyttLXvvc6VLAOdsXN7Iu4pFTCc2PpIHOXKovxQRj8Rn/xxwJ89xskxC0V7CLeB5s/9G0AkWy1CUdhnDPybXCojLtYqoOeb5w+0vbknSYf2OR0npX53RM7ewqHg1ZN8oeQQV9D2EffEcNLhB0mCfQjG5vT83TWpXrRRTwMccq2FaCCgwJ4+aPzgXV1/5UDRYSPPxDBj9pm3B+0QfN8UGOtronrfe4UGm0otvJ9y/+msoqodvKoKSUjYR6iSvtL+pRdYRh6BQLSC2R7aL23FpkXR+ZKwHDO20dASGhME1/et+gHU0S+osGIfGXSZvETCF72a7ZFANr5WkKPPP/pwT7NE6yIh06/U00/Ty6ULr5N5An0OoP8ZAe7lihh4dXgPEUbS4VXLzPyYG75qrSNDhQpdyU1ajfPvtnkGIqVDTMw2/qGH54=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": 1, 
		"option_b": 2, 
		"option_c": 3, 
		"option_d": 4, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120107", 
		"question": "24KwcdHk0Aqq440lEhj91/D+IWLfDSIepT+XWqY0XnD3XajMb+G++ZtwKVKAg1w70XnLrqzk41YKz+B12a3WMDEKeYVmztmK1urjiDFFNtVUk5R3pI4XebRJwjS5fdXXYPF+3mGTLlH5aDf9AmJ7mXHFhXFT6JKu9DWvUcgkgAI7go9x44goNNLf8Iawtw8OgPn76HRgcmI4u2c9SICC", 
		"answer": "25ysKJPh3gzt/5FgRhH1wOn3MHmQB2sHpm2QV+NnZHDoUa/NYun724QxIVObzVh0/WTCqqvx41YLz7hX6ICReSwEPH6y4C3dgn2asS2k3T4RCt4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHd4Tqt5MUzWxn8zPv2NmreAGdRr3aGQeN9fjHqQLSCb+/3xZ5lPhydght54H/IpOXk+FQKm6Be+86eMDUKeo4v2tGH0OG3y3cBINJFkYV665YbeeZTgH2ketfXNfpnwGnAJETgbi28CHlngCKayltXpoez/Ca1R5Z31BAxnol37to9KMTTmbuc60S5ig+RyGjdCLxqFRSUutytpwOIr8I7usGBsDDU5vXtn7jc/p4PZx5Xs4lvbl6yg+gZ9Cs2X8G6b14L+OrUaFfsNCGtIE4cudv2xXwpwI07HWo7+w1Ci41XdsV3lp3iuj0iK94omTcU9d7yx7yjm+7oYTRn7A==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "It advocated for state ownership", 
		"option_b": "It brought together diverse stakeholders for coordinated planning", 
		"option_c": "It emphasized laissez-faire economics", 
		"option_d": "It focused on rapid industrialization", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120108", 
		"question": "25a3ZYHywxyq9oskEh39y+ntNHjEQ3YZpj+RXa9xYzHsUufWZui+55ZlLlOHjFc7wnrHrav5+VRPrKdW5IeLZCcGPsNB+PPAl+X5wDFVO8MEuY98948TaPVUxSuoNPfULfNn2nqFIgX/YXmYB396mzzfmWhF6Ku04me/Xd531B03hYI47scxMd6Lza2W+w27iQiWznKTXalhUUCW9eem70qd55F4pcGMvzzS+vO5iurc89sYcVcQC1kBMEniJIHXOdyYkTb1UQ==", 
		"answer": "25uIS9Hjwxb6+JYlVl7xyvP8J27EBiIBsXCEQKJ5fXTwGOfVZuTyzNdUJFOHglZy4WLV5OXT+F4ChrxP7Ivfdi0Aa5hqzJCG2aT2x3BFNstNmcBz4IwWf/ECzP/mTehzOz1Vp6oS3Xii5A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHd4Tqt5MUyXRL3her+JivEDCIGrG2IEqxhZDHgW6nBfOjqzNdhNVOOn1p2/3PV46P/5RMLir5e5YGPfScNascv39iA2+G30HlEc+NHlY596ZMMaOcHjB6iednSNOpryy6QNUrmbj24ADB1lzDSj3Ffq8O68TGyV9934homnsd74sYoLt6dzLyW7A2siUaS0HqfRrRqFhjZt9u8q1SVtIp4scSLtzfJ8frt2v7c88sYZxsSvoh7I1qsh7oG+SkwVNv2JkBckvT+Y6qnx2O7N6yf9g==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both proposed concrete programmes", 
		"option_b": "Both focused on academic advice", 
		"option_c": "NPC was focused on academics, while Economists' Committee was practical", 
		"option_d": "NPC proposed concrete programmes, while Economists' Committee focused on academic advice", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120109", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q440lEhf2wPzsdWTWQ3YZpj+iVrV9Y37xTefyYuzwx55/IByrglpp9jbPraP84lYBjK0b/YaaMCYGaI5jx8CE0urjhGFNMshKk451pJMRPN1OyDi9cdrfJfB6jkeOI0zxOHuOPo+6vztjbkg5lKDQy3tB", 
		"answer": "25ysKIHmwhHv88UmXQyyxL38MGXEEWMd7z+CR7d8f2PqQKbWZ/v7iZhjIF2HhEF65n/JreX2+EFPi61N7IKQYC8GcJ8v2NyI2er+ynYD+I7O5vdOUZtTtl/O11rz3Q==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHS1Q/j5IoyS17CyfzxO2LeBCIzrH6RVuNnZGPsWqDOd63szJR+KlGMg19+9jbSq6Cw9EEKjrxS5oDffyRDf8tszd6dxeX7iDFAJtJMlZJ78JsLdeJFjDK/c9XVKeRv2mePKQXiYiqtC35nnTPajzxQp5H78SKtUdY40Bg3mJM4/cQ9MtmW16/T3EWxlUaL2H6QCLFhFRSNuo6840bcpZEstM+BuCHT+fH3jrjc9p4fag0Sj4p+bVW1ma9J2yU1XMGnextE/6TZbxS8eX3za04K8cLg3jR5yoMwWG109V9Vi4RYa8Z61ZnqqHIiMMFvVTq041dIxoR1URDWXbO82Wmj8xU7cGwuaYV9sSg7tU+MJFVwlGKSS2xBho9o+8MK1x4ZBUw7zfPK0lPBN6PBMak=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "It advocated for decentralized planning", 
		"option_b": "It emphasized laissez-faire economics", 
		"option_c": "It pushed for a central, authoritative organization for development planning", 
		"option_d": "It supported complete state control over industries", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120110", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q440lEjz9yP/+LCvgD2Mf436NVuNgeHSjeqbWZ+LwyJsxF1CIg1Vy/HGGgKr9+lobm61eqcaxQAFKPoprzMKMxPe30HlEc89XiZV3pJUZPPVH3jy/fdXVYOxr3XqSMkbkciu0Cncr1taPNQ4pKzeZ/TD1YjgNc3k=", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz1BT6/4QzWwT3wb3rPW6QDWcUpz+FXbE0cXPsWK7WZ+LwiZh3Z1WHmV5p/3PCqqTi/lYcz6lV7c6ZcSsRPopo2tmKwujj0WNAP4ZUiIlx4Yld0/FL+X0BIhJJaCmkLVtqbA==", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmzxRHvt6cvXxzz3L3POWreQ2Mfpz+XWqY0XkHAFKbFfOj7zdd+KRydhV4783TJr6zk/lwBz6ddqYeRZCcRc45rwdGb3uHkhDlSJsVM2oFhpIAecf1OyDy/Z52XYPl7z3yBKVH1YjCzAzBylTjEymxEoYC+5me9W8h3wRIgn4Rt4dwpLtaTmbiB50mthRKRkDuQRrkkAUaWuMG84k2b4IE3ut2IozPP/eL8ibjn+NcYIhtavpR6Zxu9h7gb9ys7WYi1YR9O9aTEbhT4MCSqIRpd7cPmlnVu1IsqSGUg4Q1HjsNFZ8Nn2YqkvTw0f8RnBSG1tUEA05x5HxSZermxxGHr7kZ/enxrY4t/sSgnsk0EycnyKTYHhoQ5d5UIEFL7", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both emphasized the need for abolition of intermediaries and fair agricultural prices", 
		"option_b": "Both opposed agrarian reforms", 
		"option_c": "Bombay Plan focused on heavy industries, while NPC focused on consumer goods", 
		"option_d": "Bombay Plan recommended complete state ownership of agricultural land", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120111", 
		"question": "25G9e4H6xRyq440lEhf80fT+OSvUCmQXpm2GXKBxYz2jfKjVLun3zddlL1nJr1R28Hff45X89l1PjqZfqZqXdWItf59mx96I26THyHBPPc9KncBR65cSdeBUyTjtPPrrA7cuyGeOIwXzaDSwC340kyPZn3JS98H364ihID2yW4b3gT6FWeSA", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz1BT6/4QzWwT3wb3rPW6QDWcUpz+FXbE0Y37gXabOLvr7xZFwNVnJgF564WPUprayWhrvOqvYb7VjWQtdar1NmQ==", 
		"explanation": "25G9e4H6xRyq440lWwyywfT5M27CBmwSpmzPErd8dTHBW6rAb/S++ZtwKRyIg1875n7D44vA1BMOiLpe7IrffyxDbY55zcKI26T8wWgBMtVUn4Nm99ZfdfpDwCipfdrcYOpmyy6JKlX/dS28CnNx1D7Qym9Zq4q6+WesUdYxwQc31op97NspLtKMmZyb4V74hQmP0XSfCLp2HkGXsY6s7k6TrpEsp8yZtDab4Pz8k+qT49YKcA1W/49xd16ukrsduCM2EcmwbABO4vfZb1OtKTuwMgsOudnm2nV9w4ZpSWZ05BBQh5FCe4wz05X0sD0pMshkAX/6okpEh5Z9TB6VNLO9023381wrfH84J417nJd8K9QtXf5NnOjNcHM=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both emphasized the need for social welfare measures", 
		"option_b": "Both opposed state intervention", 
		"option_c": "Bombay Plan focused on heavy industries, while NPC focused on consumer goods", 
		"option_d": "Bombay Plan prioritized laissez-faire, while NPC emphasized state ownership", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120112", 
		"question": "25y2KIb70A2q4IQ5QV72zPm/IWPVQ0Aern2CS+NEfHDtFKbMaq3qwZIxCV2dhFR183qGk6nx+V0Gga8byoGSfSsXao5qiJin58e+hHVINcBBiMB76toLdPFJ3n2sZMTJL/9txi6UKAX5aT2oF2RmnTDag2ZXvIq0+3j5AIvHjMR0GfslkGy8PnDMhA==", 
		"answer": "25e3ZZPyyFna+4QuEh/+yfL8NH/VByIQ42yKVa19dnjgVanWLv3x24N4KFLJmVQ78HfVqqaw/l0LmrtP+4eaY25DaYNmxNXJ+dTUhHdOMNNXn4Qy65RfeedTyTO5fdXXYP1hwH2VKkDiJz6yC3Rn1hiURIWDjNREx9PV3eQ6wUg=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHR3hTo9pxgYhLzy73+OWffAGMFpnvDU+N3f3/wXaPHfOz8xZIxN12bmRt09DbPt7aw518OgehU/JqTcTtDaoQvytGa3ue3zX9FJtVQiIl399Zfa/xJwDjtYNzeYNBe7SLALkv2ayy4CnNxkHHUkzxlp5Wy8DP7RNY2zhs7mIA0rc0xLN+eyqGJ7Un4lQ+PyXeFSbNhHkGK9cqt/UaQr5I1sMOZ8T3dtPf2lOvG/dsZIg9dsIJsI1Kyk70a7DgxVNv4KBBe5aTfbxTsYCSsMEMW/NKjxXdoyodpaWE9519Ci4VQZ9J22Jvh/Do5OMVmHDSyt1cA05x5VgXWcLSrxGHq40F/Zm45ZJ5ouyQwsk+aJ0Y+k2WYWT9Fholq8tkDlBBqcmECwvOowk4sEFGHeC2u5kSzZw==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both focused on heavy industries", 
		"option_b": "Both advocated for rapid industrialization", 
		"option_c": "Bombay Plan allocated a significant portion to basic industries, while NPC focused on essential consumer goods", 
		"option_d": "NPC emphasized heavy industries, while Bombay Plan focused on consumer goods", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120113", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q440lEjnzy/n3PGreQ1IdonHEQeNkdWPwRKLBeuTozNd+KRyAg19u4WLUqqT8/kkOm6FU586beSQFe5kvzsKG2qTjzHQBJc9BjZMy65xfaPxFjBOsYN3ULv9ijl6MJkv+bje6RFN7mTzfnmhTrcPz2xeYHZo2zhFygo99reozMdWewOij5Ey22UTJHSgaY8izJeZ7kbI77TJD", 
		"answer": "25K5ZpX72Bjkt7UsUxCyxPnpOmjRF2cV43yMRrd1d3SjVanGLvv3xZtwIFnEgV5t93qGqqv04kAbnaFe+sLfZyoKco4v5uCql+X5wDFjPMtGm5ky1JYecrRT2S29e8bPJfouxmuBMVywZje5RHx1hjbTynVYrJao4TWyUcl1Mniks4MArqh8LRoMdqvqUQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHU0Bfu/4whXF7CyfzxdXvCCm0DqmuKSKZwMHXmV6LMev//xZ5rIljJjlRv5nfBpuXx+VdPmaFX5Y+YdW8Pe51qxJCA2eDi12VTOsNX2pR9pIoNeedF3iuoNMDTJb59y2KGalblYT+0B3lxmjLPynNQ6I+09ia3FNk4zRgnmI5s5M0vfP6Rmauc5lmqhxWWkDuFQLgkP2S69c+m7wOIqId4l8KAszPCtMT1m/aT9dMbaglBtpx6Zxuon61J6iU0VIi7blJD9OXGeBTsLizjKw8P/s6j33pt05E9T2Ax519PjMNTYc992ZXtv3I0OttvGTyqrkFO09RIVx6FNLmxxm3251Axdn9rd49rsCg2tQqYaHN/lG+URWtC1IVm7tgYhg1wPWBO3GbyhyyOknOGcpSj54//hOSwtKti9qozIE6OJhzZWIlcdrbMISph3++dBKVVNpFkDmB/HnfHypVP3xH6EcDSsmpp", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Gandhian Plan supported heavy and large industries like NPC and Bombay Plan", 
		"option_b": "Gandhian Plan advocated cottage and village-level industries, while NPC and Bombay Plan supported heavy and large industries", 
		"option_c": "Gandhian Plan emphasized mechanization of agriculture", 
		"option_d": "Gandhian Plan recommended state control over all industries", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120114", 
		"question": "25CgeJ3y2Beq440lEhf2wPLzOmzZAGMd43aOQqJnY3SjQK/Deq3xypRkNU6MiRt/52TPraKw41sKz65S+52LMDEGbZhmx97J2OK30HlEc+hFjol96psTPMRMzTOjfdrcYN1hw2OJM1H1Ynn1KkBX3XHXhHgWoIystS6vFNM5xhknk4l76Mx8KN+amamB/ES7kwqDyHKeRv1rFxSNvcvozEKSpIoxtMPNgT7a+rYKhT9XprZgtLSVadjICeIz", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHU0Bfu/4whXF7/wPD9MHmQEncUsGuKXa1xdDH3XKKCQN3djoQxJkmdhVRp+2Lf46r+t1oBi71I/ZyWcS4KZIp7wd+Hm6T7wXBFOshD2pR9pJsRPP1EyTKhe9PSI/9ijmqFJkH8aDq2RhdYOo2Tf0VzTf7ekWMuas8=", 
		"explanation": "25Gtepj91ln+/4BgVBfg1um/Jm7DEGserT+MVONgeHSjepfhIq3U6tdaMlGIn1pr4neK47H48hMDgKZeqamefiYLd4phiN2M2uby1j0BMM5Flox36p0aeLRUxDjtd9vWLfd62muFYFawZiypDH9mnSXPymhZ6Iey5iSuR8l3yRs2g5Rs/8E9MN6F2Lya50P4rgPC2XaBQLx3GE6csY6P6k2YqIt/po2buDfMtPv/2urW48oZawtGtoh4I1qyk+gM9CM1WMa1fBtF9qTdblDoMibjLgAZ7Nj3xH1oyos6UCkA/BZVwopbcsFgxZ2krjc2M8hpATa+41BIwtR1WxKZeLK/2Wvl7BU8enQtaYNuqG03pBuLLVFw2n+USWx2lY5v9tkYm0RzeH1TjHPjljadhSWOcpej/4j5xev/rbRq5rciLAaTdVXWVYEVa7LULmh8iv2UGqdON4wnBzDpMNo69Tf+YJqVzT4IncojLnvitCOXltjmLXej85P1gdpxB7YEM5HG5t+jsVvCISrvJWiActn9XBuwe3T9kwdopxk22yRQ4GvfAIV28iUZm3rwXUxh0inlaXjhkLFOqoPOWI8/1/3l3Dxdkfprj5Ll0Rl8Vwi6gz9XvcSPXVlcyFrCXswJhAgiGLETGpfF+3uT1WDZWHUCcYygYwMfENoL7mMk9KesqucK", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "NPC favored complete state control over industries", 
		"option_b": "The NPC endorsed the views of the Gandhian member", 
		"option_c": "The Gandhian member questioned the NPC's authority on industrialization, leading to an ideological deadlock", 
		"option_d": "The NPC unanimously agreed on the role of heavy industries", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120115", 
		"question": "25S2aZ3qyxyq440lEh391/i/MWLWBWcDpnGAV7A0eX+jQK/HLuj9xpl+KlWKzU1y4X/Jrbaw+FVPqKlV7YaWMCMNest7wNXJ+eXjzX5PMsoEqoxz6pQWcvMA7zKged3PNPtrjiauF2a5Jyu4A3FmkDjYjTxCoIb75yi3UZo4xlUhgoZs6IgsM8Cay+iS5kn4jwiGyWiFWrRlHV2DtNqh5E3edHc8fr6KJgHgX34F9xqRmg==", 
		"answer": "25K5ZpX72Fnv+pUoUw373/j7dWffAGMd42yGXqU5Y2TlUq7BZ+jwyo4xJlKNzVRr4nnVpqGw9FYBm7pa5YeFdSZDbZ9u3NXJx+vgwWMBMshA2ol84I8MaOZJzTGkZ9mXYOlmx2KFZ2vARHmxAXF6kTWWnnNBqZG/5me4UdQj0hQ+1pd07MYyNdmYmamd7A2xiAKXz2+DQbxoGE6Yocen5QH3nOa/9sfuqXkOhonL1KGy", 
		"explanation": "25K5ZpX72Fn8/oA3VxqyxvjxIXnRD2sLpnvDQbd1ZHSjRKjVa/++yJl1Z1WHiU5o5mTPoqn57VIbhqdVqY+MMCEWbJhq25CA2vT413RFc8Rd2qVn9pUPefVOjD6ieNvVKf9ix32NZ0T+Y3m7BWZ7hjTSynBZq4K3tTS+WNx60wA0kI575M0yP87fzaCB51i/jkaB02+FSbphUV2Xsdu7/1GVpZF4nMPNsj3V4Ob4ieyfsMoDZ0h8j6U/b169ma0NuD43RsmmbAEL8uHedUbsLGizKw8T98Lt0TgpyoM7WmwmtBZIhpZFdtJ604uo/DM+O415ATKupgRJyYB5TQGTeqmx32ak9Fp/cWgic48tuS46rwCRIVc+nXmTWzhZ1LRj98NZkQ11eH1HmXjjh3+CjiWKf5zt5I31hqjgqLBv/bAoOUmZdU/QV50ZYfPUL2J72KmJCLVMNpxzHjTjfdQ+7Cv2IZWc2ipNxNZgK3Lx8SaWgsDwN3H6o574gNp/GrhAP9+FwMWzuV2FRO/8lZSb1fQYVZcO2bnQsg==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both Gandhi and the NPC advocated centralized state power", 
		"option_b": "Gandhi supported industrialism like the NPC", 
		"option_c": "Both Gandhi and the NPC emphasized large industries", 
		"option_d": "Gandhi emphasized local self-sufficiency and opposed centralized state power and industrialism, while NPC leaned towards central planning and industrialization", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120116", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q440lEjnzy/n3PGreQ1IdonHEQeNxfWHrVbTLfa3xx9dwZ2DLiV5493jSsaT8/kkKi+he6oGRfy8Kfct83MKc1PDi1nR9cYZFlol16toIdeBIjBqsetDTKbl9jmySKET0Yiv9FHh9mD7FhWxeoYC6+WetXd8g00pwoUwGS2eHlH+wOG3AIPitpg==", 
		"answer": "25K5ZpX72Fno8okpVwj3wb32OyvcDGEQrz+QV69yPWL2UqHLbeT7x5RoZ12HiRt2+3jPrqT8t0AbjrxeqYeRZCcRaI5h3NmG2aZzUcxY4M/YSXM1SPn4usYU", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHU0Bfu/4whXF7CyfzxcniQBW0StmzDXa00cTHfFqPHbejw3YVwK1WTiF8793XJrar9/lBPnLxJ/I2LZTAGQskv2tWa2Or20HRFc9FNjogyw5sRePxJiy7tddDNL/1vzXfAIUriJyq4CHY5hjTag31YvMOt/Cu3Vd0y01UzmIM45cEvfMSU3LiH4U6xlQvCyHSGSa9gAhSasMC8+UKQqZg9sY2MpCbT++bwjuGT198FZgBb+JU/c1O1m6ca9zowSIixZQJD8PfZe1HpYDumKwhQ6t7l0H1qz4cnXnB4tBxJj45DbMlnz9XmvSE1O41jGzevsFBSzpFvE1eXern43WHq6Vg+eTo4cYt5uW08rxuZOkJ7lH+VQyId1Jdj99MR1RNmb2oAjnPmjjqIlGCLPJrtq5T0gKjgrLhttbBnKk6SMBzIRIQSZrrQK2JhiBi+PLG76e+z3ZTLWlk7VIM=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Gandhi believed in local self-sufficiency and minimal state intervention", 
		"option_b": "Gandhi supported heavy industries", 
		"option_c": "Gandhi advocated complete industrialization", 
		"option_d": "Gandhi emphasized urbanization and centralization", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120117", 
		"question": "25Sre5Tgwln+/4BgWxPixP7rdWTWQ3YZpj+kU61weHjiWufyYuzwiZh/Z0iBiBtv4HfMpqbk+EEWz6ddqaeRdCsCOZgvzdOG2ev6zXIBI8pFlI576p1fffpEjDmoYtHXL+5jy2CUZ1X/dC3wDX5wkSHThHhTpoC+t+lW95bKE0B8oq1kTVhGGLg=", 
		"answer": "24GwbdHU0Bfu/4whXF7CyfzxdWLeBW4EpnGAV6c0ZHnmFKHNbfjtiZh/Z06cn1p3snLDtaD8+EMCiqZPpc6cfzYXf4xqiNmH0/Hk0GNINtUI2oF84Nocc/lN2TOkYM2bMP982meDLlXxczCyCjKff4NVawn9t9wEOo7GsXoo", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHU0Bfu/4whXF7CyfzxcniQBm8Bq36QW7A0f3+jRrLQb+G+zZJnIlCGnVZ+/GKK46b/40cOiK0b4ICbZTEXbIJq25zJ1urzhHJOPstRlIlm/doPfeZUxT6kZNXPKfFgjmaBIwXxJzW8F2R9mjaWg3FGqYCvtSi1FPM5xBwz0ZQ46MszMtiS0KvT+EG5iAiL0nzRYakkEluXodyh6VaIpYZ4ocLNoT3X/ffwn+uT4MwCbRpbq49lalW717oc6is0Ec+mZwVf+aiQZVHuJSa3NQ8R8NHiwn1myM5pXGcwtAxTkZdXa85y1JTh/DY1KchmGiO3pkpUh6B0WgSTNLS81Wn3oEI6Z39rd49rsCg2tQqYaF1w2niJTj9UhZVu8MRZsw11eC95mXfywg+HgWucPJLt78D1i+Hkqbh3+7UiOgGBPFHdUs0dcfPVN2t7zP2SA6EcIYp1Fi6mPtoj8Sz3KYKd2ipPl8T7sYXXugjBfhCi6j1b8w==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "The Gandhian Plan led to rapid industrialization", 
		"option_b": "The Gandhian Plan influenced the focus on rural development, cottage industries, and community participation", 
		"option_c": "The Gandhian Plan advocated state control over all industries", 
		"option_d": "The Gandhian Plan called for urbanization and centralization", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120118", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R5vMWeXniZN4IxykjFN65nvH44Lx+VcHhuhU+Z6QYydDaoNqiNmH0/Hk0GNIMspNgIFm7ZURPPJPzyi+NNvdYOpmyy6iKEjyZiD9NHx1mnHXhHgWhoKv/Ci1VdZ38BkzmIlx4898H9iS1KGH/Ei92Ua+0irRYbNgBEeNp8ep50qGoZYxusPNpj3O+PC5nvHA4NIKYQ0SvJR+ZU+v16kH/GouWMS4aRVOse3eZUH+NDqqIh1dxcWxlllmwoc7Uyk59RxOi41TcNkz15bg/CY1PMVkGj+1pF0A0JVvHx+XZrC+xWSk5lotNWkkZoNoqDR1nQHPaGFsmGqSRTZQgIlk8JAYmwAjfmpOiGThjjaRhWHPbJ/i5Y71i++wtrBs/qIzLEXAJU7RWI4Vdb/FZ2h0iv+SAapdNJonJDXnL9QkvAX3dNa30C0Z0d4lb37p8D+Kht/8PHb6o4D2g9tiEbtAJdTJ74altVDOYC3iJD2RY9/gXBqwW3T53U5tshkz0WEZ5mbNG51t/CgeonCHQU1nmmfvajy1nrsc7I2Cc4Em2vvrnTMCnbR7kInl0R4oGEYaTfax1aDmidZzkfuuS/en", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "25K5ZpX72Fnr85MvUR/mwPm/I2LcD2MWpj+QV69yPWL2UqHLbeT7x5RoaxyNiFh+/GLUoqn57VIbhqdVpc6efiZDbYZuxNzJ0urjwWNRIc9Xn5My5Z0edfpT2H25fNGbLP98yWvNNEbxazz9DX5wgSLCmHVXpIqh9DOyW9R30Ac9hohr6Mx8NdnfzaCWqG+3iwSDxTuhRLxqUVWXsY6G22DQ4JUwvM6F8TretPL8luyT59EebgwSt4dtbhuqnqQF+S09Qoi1ZhYL8uvEdVXqJWiqKQoI6t/x33F6hqogTiki/QxPjY0WY8x60ZbhuHInNtliVSeypgRnxpp4Vx6Xev2I3Gnqp0Z/cHc7bYt+tT51rgHcOEZ7iW6OWiVfk8Bn8dMYmURgb25GiGXtgzGYiGyfPJLt78Dsl+f9r61q/KRnOkSMMxHKU4EVZL3DIisyw+fbDqlSJ41mBDamKdpu6DH8YJ+a2ywexMspLnvu7iuNm8L7dGGouoT8gJR7G7sFOsKF5s33pFTCISz1KXiBJtv4WAbjDY+4Zf7ekv/XIpBqBt5gzvE=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1, 2 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120119", 
		"question": "25iWKKP8yF75t7UlXQ7+wLrsdVvcAmxRtH6QEqF1Y3TnFKjMLvr2wJR5Z1WNiFR3/XHf/OXM+QJGz4Va+5aWYzZDTYRswdGF3vf6hCMIc+FFlIR67ZsRPMJJwDGsc9GbE+lv3G+KZxa5Jx24CX93hjDCg38Wi4Kr/DO6WNMkzVVm38dU7MEvL9KFlK6S4V+9xL3kR1rIGYZV881z5plJTD0=", 
		"answer": "yIa81+O/xBe+s576qbzvh3A=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHD1Bb6+4BnQV7CyfzxdXvCBnESsXaBV6c0XXDxTK7Req3txpR4JlCAnlY75nmGs7f/4VoLiuhZ6J2Wc2INe4hq28OAw+3y1z0BOshClpV36pkWcvMA3zKufdXXKe16jnqJK1Gwbjf9F2V2hzTHn3lYvMO9/DG+FMMywQdyhot549t8CN+Wyuia5ku0kwOM337RRLhgUUCW9dqg7gOVrpY9st+MpTvU+rT2nLjA/90CYwRbrJI/c0m1masA6CY9Qoi9ZlJi/+DZYBP+YC2gKAAS9MLglmRlx4wnVGczuF9PjIBad8R62J+krD08Ns5jECD6pUtD0od5W1eZev2q1Wzt80EtfHg+cYNism06p0+LLVVyjmPQDD9el4lq8pAOkAhlfH1F0DbhjDvLkHCNcJrgq4/ri+3is7Fq4uMoLwGLMEWYRYgfcbzSNCdGwuzbPaNTI5NiUDGmDdkv8nn1IZ+Qny0F1ZkmIGLp8CuNm8L7eWO1odLQgNB/FfgTdtzM8c6z8FnEbi3uLGTTZ9vkSwfxTHS0kw1quhosxige7yLdBIxy8CMZjT6/TwR3nSTpbXCohbMc64yKP40ww/z43D4Zi/k6cwKaP1/+iW/+RDZXEo+yDg==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": 1, 
		"option_b": 2, 
		"option_c": 3, 
		"option_d": 4, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120120", 
		"question": "24qHV67M7ibVyLofEhv/1fX+JmLKBmZRtXaPXqJzdTHqWqPXffnswJJiaxyaiFd9v2TDr6zx+VAKz6lV7c6bdSEGcJ99ydyAzeXjzX5Pc8RFiYV2pJURPNNBwjmlfdXVYO58x2CDLlX8Yir9JTk0tj7biH1P6LO39Cn7dpN38BA9hot9qtt8DNue1+iwoQ2OjxWU2WiHSa9lCFXZhcKp5QO46cILtN+bvjba7fW5qvTS/pwdWfabPUCFr1E29A79wUxh", 
		"answer": "24a5eof81Rjz9sUQXh/8h0jBz0zec0lqLnh5jGDGyaU=", 
		"explanation": "25+5cZDjwxjh9pYoEjDz1/zmNGWXECIiom2VXad1aXCjZKvDYK34xpRkNFmNzVR1slHHraH4/lIBz6tU552LYjcAaoJ5zZCe2Pb81z0BJc9IloF14doWcvBV3ym/fdHIbL5vwGrAI0DzYjepFnF4nSvXnnVZpsOP/SL7RNY2zlUzmo5/4804fMCWzaDTz0y2gg6Lm2jRWLVtHVuKut6g8gOTpsItpcGEtybS+vO5l/nB99cFYwRbpYN7I1izmqUc9iMsWM2nKAZD4+vFZlytMy2vIUMO7M3l33dgw4wqRCk1+hsGhoZVZ85nxJnotSg1O41uEDCzsE1PydlxXhyferr4+mn94UUtdHEqdoItkiwnoBadJhNt2m6RXCRQh4l4vt8X1QNxfHxTjnnvlnKHhXOKcNPn7pb5iefgrbxt5uMmJ0XANlPVW5gSbKfZZ3dz2P2SDq9MMotuGCymPtog6CvwIoOA2j1NxNZgO3/itCmWnM7wKXH6vJS5spZFFa0WOdXE8MqL8hzIc2PdY2iDasLyTQX1QWi43AglthQphB1SqHHQCZl2+ypNt3C0QEUjgWfhfGyzmb9f4sKacM443fbgyCEZjvE4mIn4wwk0BS/op8KpFNgXUedBy6aA3TQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Sa,rv,od,ay,a Pl,an", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120121", 
		"question": "24GwbdHA0Av8+IEhSx+y9fH+OxLDQ3QYsHaMXON7djH1XavOb+r7iYR0K1rEn153+3fIoKCw4FIcz6VU+prfYysOd4du2pCd2KTgzH5SNoZBmY9865cWf7RNwzmoeIuZQrJ0KL864UuIXXBuFf3nXg==", 
		"answer": "24Oxe4f2wg/r5YQ5U17CyfzxdwGocmzjVeQZIOEpfLYGtP4=", 
		"explanation": "25mxY5Sz9hjk840pFQ2yyPL7MGecQ0gQun6TQKJ/cWLrFInDfOznyJk2NBy6jElt/XLHuqSwx18Ogehd5o2KYycHPoRhiMaA2+j2w3QBOshAj5Nm9pMab7RBwjntZ9HXJrN8y2KJJkvzYnX9B396gCPXmWhfpoT74i6vXJojyBByn4l8+NsoLt6e1aGJ6VmxiQjC2XaBQLx3GEfZusjo5FeUpZB4pcGMvyGbwPz82svS4sgEZglLvsZPb1qy160H7iMrWMe6bRYL/evTYFitJSusKQEQ8M7wlmBh1Is/VGcztAtOkIxDZcgzwJHosDM3OoBmECW/rwRJyZBpTAOEfbirnCj08loyem4ia40tvTghrgGTJU0+m2WYDD5UkJVo994e1QBmbWpOmHPugTrLj2vPf5bt/5L9ieHqpb0j4bo0PUSNJhzsXoQPJbfFJGJ83vuaAa9GNpsnFjL2L9ov/zG5IZ+Z2j1NxNZgKnr3+z2cgI32Nmi3ppzwmt1zB/8BONWF78SkpFnVITD0MmmSb8X1WwT1D3j9xQtpuAgozS8EpCLZBIB4+yQDmT6nQFBs0gDhYnipn/lPqpSHbIc+3bXj23IDnfh+0ony2BQ9SRD7m3ZPvoWYSk8NR30BZp1SOc+Tfo9uRj2vIg==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Bombay Plan", 
		"option_b": "People's Plan", 
		"option_c": "Gandhian Plan", 
		"option_d": "Visvesvaraya Plan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120122", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iPqIzuXn1nBKMtVM2q5z9psGffoAwy29e8feJL56xmvAJED+cyu8CHlukTWWhH1CvZG+tSi9FNw+1hByj4J5/4gsMNaRypSd1EOKgweR03XRAI8tSxSxsI6u7k+I4Iss9cmEvSfP8fC5iv3c4NIOJRsSr4dtd1K/nrgI7CM3X4i9ZlJf+eGQcVjsLiaqKQld6dns1XF61cBGob74yMAygqt/GsIrKfO+", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "25+5cZDjwxjh9pYoEjDz1/zmNGWQAHAYt3aSR6ZwMGXrUefBa+Pq25Z9LkaImVJ0/DbPreX2/kUKz7Fe6JzfYC4CcJgvycPJ0+370WVIPcEEioV99JYaO+cA3Dy/YN3YKe5v2mePKQmwbjeuEHV1kHHXjmpZq4Kv/Cm8FN4ywxA8gpV54cEmOdPfz6Gf5Ey/g0aS0HqfRrRqFhSxvN3o6EySo4cqu97NuTvc/PjwnfDH9dpLdgBX/4h6Zl/8kacbuCg3Rdy7ZV9e4aTAbVXjLiGtIEJd7sPmxHEpyo0qXGV09xBLj5ZYa9R604ukvTEkNttvGSr6s0VS051/VgeXYLj42Wak5FA8fGkiaoQgsSw+qAGbaERslWiZXz9Uh8BB/8kYhRZidm5TlDbOgy2KmWSBO4Cj7o3sjenjqaoj/a1nLUSDMFLMRIwQbKnBM259xKmSA6BQJpppFCfifcY7/ir8MYOR0S1N1d8mIGXz52qNnY3wN227vZH8zth5F74MdtbK/86lvl3JYiatYW6GZcO0WBuwW3T9kz5kuRstyTgR/GuYOoh1tT4UjWq1RAgkhS/pb3Thl7dR74bOa4Fx0efl0zVQn/tumon51RM/QkS4gXBQt5bfW1MP2VzTXt0CyxkiCfZ1auRooNDoy9snm+p2D/1X", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is NOT the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120123", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kR7l4YAyXBP3y+m/J27ADHAFsD+MXONnYHTgXaHLba3/25JwNByGixtv+nOGpqb/+VwCluhM7JyaMDIRe5tu2tWNl+35hGVJNoYVw9Qi99oeb7RpwjmkdZTWL+hryi6UKFLxdT2uRGB4lT/Yj3gWrIat8Cu0RNcyzgFtqokprfw0OZe0y6GA4EO5iweB1HqDQf1WFESWp9ro5E3coYUqvM6YvSbO5vX12ujB+d0OcUhusdQ/V1O515sI6isxSMn0Whdb/vbEIVvjYCusKB4Y68r332Js1cIVUzp0wBdDwqheZ9Jy0Znw/AA1L8J4AXO1rQRFw4F/XgOfe7P47GawoGE3cDoMZI5qtSF1kwqMJ0Zq2mSSDD5EhoFnvtMLkABqaS3314xv204krgmd+MTYam/3", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kU2oYXwG2MTAZOqfNg6CyLlF0w==", 
		"explanation": "2569cdHh1Anl5ZEzEg7gwO3+J27UQ2sf42uLV+MlKSWzR+fAa+vx25IxLlKNiEt+/HLDrab1t1oBjKRO7YubMDYLe8tE2tma3+r2yXBCO8dWk8BA4YoQbuAAwzPtddPJKf17wnqVNUT8JymvDXNxh3HXhHgWvIu+tQC6UN0+zFUAk5d3/9x8M9nfy72B6UH4hRSH2HKFBP1lHFuXso6n/0uZspF6Zd3DIrGCiTd4NWBHMA1eVA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 3", 
		"option_b": "2 and 4", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 4", 
		"option_d": "1 and 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120124", 
		"question": "24GwbdHYwxD5/4shXx/xzfztPCviBnIesWvDVKx3ZWLmUOfNYK3pwZ5yLxyanV54+3DPoOX19FwBgKVS6s6WYzEWe9QtxHC7/jTEmgk9j3w9wL7ucA==", 
		"answer": "25S/epjwxBX+4pchXl7i1/T8MHiSgXXFT7lExcvr+a97mEydng==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHYwxD5/4shXx/xzfztPCviBnIesWvDQrF7ZnjnUaOCfOj9xpp8IlKNjE9y/XjV46r+t1IInaFY/IKLZTACcst/2tmK0ve38HlEc9RBio9g8N0MPP1O3zSqfMDIYPdg2mHAIUT5dXmtFnl3nT/RynFTq4u6+y6oWcl3wRs21pRt/dgzLsPf36eBqEu5lAuHzmjWCLRqEluUsI6q7kCdrYd4vMCdviDP9frt2vvc/s0CZg1AvpJ2bFWv16EHuAM2VcG1LwEL8OPCaFf4LDy2NQ8Rudvs2n1qz4c6HUAgtA9HlIZSItR709jzvStwOcJ4VSCusUVUwpN1WgTWYLL41Wb39Uc6NW4jYMp6uSE57A2ZIVp52mSaDCpQho1u7MNZlApnPXxUnXTpjjaRhSWOe4Hq6JXwkf3iobUj/6I1IkSUJh5SDdHuUetpy6phOPFHLQdv", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Irrigation", 
		"option_b": "Agricultural prices", 
		"option_c": "Land reforms", 
		"option_d": "Public distribution system", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120125", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17hzPrxPG3ZAGMfoHrDXaU0ZHnmFLHDfOTx3IQxJk6MjBZo4nPFqqP59BMdirhU+5qMMDIRe5tu2tWNl+35hGVJNoYVw9Qi98VfQPoRjAmlcc2bKPdpxmKJIE3kYj39D3Vt1DjFmWlTu8O18CK/XdQwgBI9gIJq48U5MsPf0KaH7V+ugwiW1XSfCIFqQxStvcuxq0+dqYZ4ocWI8TXJ++H3nu/c4tVLZAdA/4Bqd06ukugZ9Cs2X82wKBZO5+HcbkTgJSa3ZzITqovX3nFwhpUsT2x05A1DkoJEZ8QzwpD2syc3N41vDSe/rVdJ0ZE8WxaCdf2732To5VYrfHUlJYtjuG0npByZKUZ9kiugQngRoIhu55AJhwt1dGtFmDbjjTKbkmCHeZ3w4pb5xfr1o7Zu/6YpLUCUPFPWRc0aaqGAImR9xOaWBKUcIZphGDDrf07BaySHQD3jwMs+2d5XAEs=", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH31A3r/oklVl7z1/j+eHzZEGdRsXqTXbFgYzHzRqLSb//7zddzPhyMlUt+4GLV46z+t0cHiugKsNrPY2IWbYJhz5CMz/DyymJIJcMEiIVh4ZsNf/wAxDSqfNjSJ/Z6y2rAI0DmYjWyFH1xmiWWg29FvYaotSa1UJo7wRw21pNw6Ig7LtiK16yE51+zxgCNzjuXXalxA1HZpcKp5U2VroV4gcWIojeb5vHplerH454PZwREuoI/alWomOgd8C94X921ZhFO4qTfZxT/JS+qKAAc9Yvn02Jsyo05UGw64F9Ci5BGY9J6wpHhr35wLch5GiaooEEAxphwUBSXYLS33iSk4Vs7NWkuZp5irmAmsQqfIVJ3mSufRC1dmIVl+dUK1TBreHYAj3PylDqPwGScPJKj4I7zkuT1pL5msqEmOkTAM1PKFp0TabrDPip/y+KeH7UQc5ppFiDqNNspvC3xJZvUyzZNxNgpI3j1tC6chMj5NnW3tpztj9g2B6sSN8XA7sKyoxzTbmPgJXmBY9jnGRz4Sjzt3Qd0oh1lxiQV7HGYB48/8SQLmHuiTEpw0jXla3WumK0c44zOVoA12vSu5VvCL0MK5e0DVMSuEdM9wg==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "3 and 4", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120126", 
		"question": "24KwZ9Hjwxz69pclVl7mzfi/I2rCCm0EsD+CQKZ1PWLzUaTLaOT9iZJyKFKGgFJ4smTDs6ri40BPhqYb/YaaMHNaKtt8iNKM0evlwTFIPcJBioV84J8Rf/EfjuP5MrNIZJ+jbVYl56GXBw0=", 
		"answer": "25CgeJThxVnp+IgtWwrmwPjsdWreByIWrGmGQK15dX/3FKXNauT72tXrepzE5YGDjWfEHv2XZfaz", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH31A3r/oklVl7z1/j+eHzZEGdRsXqTXbFgYzHsWufLff7rzIQxK1WCiBt69WTPoLD840YdiuQb+5uNcS5DfZlqzNmdl+HjxzFWNtRB2pBg4YoebvFEjD+0NNHDMPt82i6DKEj9bi2pAXVn1DDYjjxRp5W+5ym2UdQjgBc9ko59/og1MpeL0a3TuRTs1hXCzGmUBbRqFVGJsMCs7k2fpcIMvcietHLJ8eT2iOzAsM4ZbR5bu4N7I1r8lKcE6Dg9Wc26extd9KTFb1DoMju3JgAZ8MXklntvhpYhWCk3/B5KjoZYZcVglp7lvzs+OI18FCGzrFFTh4d5XAOZZq74326k9F06NX8oaoRisTR1lQeZMRR3lG2TXiFUkMB78dwQlh0ucG5LmWTzwj6Jj3CbPIfr7sDvle3zqb9q8eM1LFCVPE7dW4gScaCAKGEyz+iYBeZPNpxzGDCmPNsqvCn1IY+R23kMkMkpOXjz9SbZgML5PCWzvdLqhtVmHbEHdtXA/867v0zKZC31YW2Bb8TmUBz5Sm+41xt3vhYiiDUY7SLIB5pruCQDmnugTEpglynjaTykhL8eZB54tmF1Ycr3yIdAagv57A==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Politicians", 
		"option_b": "Expert committees and government bodies", 
		"option_c": "Industrialists", 
		"option_d": "Bureaucrats", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120127", 
		"question": "27i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQCGcI43CBWKZ3ZHj1UbSCYfjqxZ5/IljJhFU75n7D44b/+UAbhrxO/YeQfmIUd59niMSB0u3lhHdOMNNX2oFg4ZsMJrbDuuB7sFJrNb8ergD1amc2", 
		"answer": "24WqbZD+0xXvt8hgYRHxzPzzdWreByIUoHCNXa59czHiWqOCfuLywIN4JF2FzVFu4WLPoKC8txMpmqZf6IOafjYCcstdwdeBw/e3iTFzOsFMjsBm69oabeFBwDS5bZibBPd8y22ULlP1JwmvDX53nSHaj28Wp4X7xjO6QN938Bo+n4RhrYV8DMWQz6GX4UO/xg6X0XqfTf1nHlqdvNqh5E2P4I0+9dqCozmXtNLslPzS/dsFdgle/6Jqd1K5hOhEuA4tRdH0fB0L4fbfdVHuNGi3Lwtd/MX132ZmyI8sU312AaS0IMEAstrB6SdaSZSPEg==", 
		"explanation": "25q6YpTwxRD88pZgXhf5wL31IHjECmEU436RV+N9fjH3XKKCXv/7yJpzK1nFzUly9X7S47H/t1YemqlX4JqGMCsNPq16xtSI2uH50HBNc/RNnYhm99ZfdOFNzTOoNMPUMvUuzWGOI0zkbjazFzB9mnHyg25Tq5ey4yL7ZMg+zhY7hot9/og9MtPfybqc/Ei7kg+M2zuFQLgkFFqPvNyn5U6ZrpZ4vMPNlyfV8PX0n/bH8dJLRh1GtoNsI2+0krsMuCk3X9ugYQZe5e3fb1XhYDixKBgU6sLs2Gcp04wtWHsn9xBUh8N/bMR619/3/DE/MsBjAT6/rVAA05s8TBiVfby0nCjh41oxenciZsYtvSMx4QqSPl1slWWRSSJFlYwr9MUKgQ1geC90lHP5wjieiWGKPIfr7sD6ivr9tbVi5qooJwGPMxzIWYEVZrrFNCdzxO3bHapdPYwrVyfoLsA89Tf+YIKc3i1N1Nw2Knvo5CecnNm1MHb6upz6gsFlHakFepHA+N6+pF3FbSatYXydYovnTBvkTnX20gxpslozr8p1h8Xc6m40iv+N+LgP", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Preamble,Social and economic and political justice", 
		"option_b": "Fundamental Rights,Right to equality", 
		"option_c": "Directive Principles of State Policy,Providing humane conditions of work", 
		"option_d": "Fundamental Duties,Duty to protect the environment", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120128", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kTrl+ZY0Wwrn0fTwO2rcQ3IDrGmKQap7fmKjUanBb/3t3JtwM1mNzU9z9zbBrKT85BMJgLobwICbeSNEbct8x9OA2OH0y39OPs9H2pBg650NeedTk32ReoWbFPZrjl6SIkT9ZTW4RCI0oDnTylpDpoe6+CK1QNs7gCc7kY9s/ohvfOOX3Oi34V+9hRKLyn7ReK9tH1eQpcKt+AOTpsILocyZtHLr+/jwmeGTpJ4/ag0SjINpZlWon+g6+yI9Vd24bVIDxOrZblqhYBu3JhoYucrt0jRKyYwqSHsm8RFSwo9fcdRgn9ooqdpnPAHYDtt0Ekw5j+c+", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMKz0Bfut9FiDjOhcqdWsOppL5xfivzNNg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHDwxzr+ocsV1Ky4fTtMGjECnQU40+RW613eWHvUbSOLuzwzddCIkqMg09zskXFq6D04l8Kz6xS+pqNeSAWaoJhz5CZ2PPy1mIBP8dNnsB2640RPOBIyX2idt7eI+pn2GuTZ0Llbj20Cnc0vT/Sg30Ru8O/8DG+WNUnzRA8goZ0rdgwPdmR0KaUqHmwg0ayzn6QRb9oFBSKsNq7q0WTspYw9dmFtHLa5+TwiPnH+dEFcUhducZ1dkionqsMtGo9QN21ZBtf6KiQYFrpYC6xJhoY68Xqwm0lhpI7Un898BZIhcNXIs18xJno/DE/Mt1rBiD6pUtSh5B5SRKae6211WbwoGE3cDoPbJhovzk8twrcGEZ3lGiVXCBUh8Bk+JAqgQV3eC9wk3rpgSbLj3CbcJrt7sDsl+H+o7Bz/qY0aVWPdV7dFpgPYLeAJnQyzfySCaNQOpFiBGLgMsdu8Dz+KYWY3i0E39dgLnnjtC2WhMjnN2S0sJe5utxzVIwFINTL/cP3g1/PZCf0LXjTYsLiUAz1XDzo3BlgpQtlyiQE/2fdBslr/ShNnXu+XVZlnmfhYnjhhapd/ofOeIEn1ufi0DcejOc034ny0hE5RBCyg3gDpoyaD19AwkTTDMwTzR8rTLIEEJPD82GfhnuQX3QMa47lCamXxj8I8+31h2A6rNAeWY2AIhDVjZ4qyRm1Ev54RWKvlj7QiWuo/ZeJkirLc2qtFA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 4", 
		"option_c": "1, 3 and 4", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120129", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+zxhj5t5EoV17CyfzxO2LeBCIyrHKOW7BneX7tFKLReuz8xZ5iL1mN0hma07qsdAYYOIMgpXXhg8Ui", 
		"answer": "yOztOHH3L7LXut3LQgRjBdHCk+s=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHD3Rjk+YwuVV7RyvDyPHjDCm0f42iCQeNxY2XiVqvLfeX7zdd4KRykjEl4+jaX+vCgt3obz7hX6JeadGICPoh93dOA1ui31n5NNoZNlMB064gSafhB2DSjc5TaLvoux2OQK0D9YjepDX5z1BjYjnVX75D70y6tUZoOxRQg1rd07MYvfOOX3OiQ50C1jxWR1XSfCLxnBVGd9c+7q0Lco4c2od+MvXLa4eDxlera5MdLZAdA/4VwbEm4nqYI7CM2Voi1ZhYL4fbZbkbkNCG5LgAauc/mwHFlyZIkWGcg9RMGg4BCa9Z6wpHhr3IxPN9lBiD6tUVSzptpTFeFcb6s33r3oFQxcTo4cYt5uT533F9BcaKOeVwOWu/nsMzAjg==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": 1947, 
		"option_b": 1948, 
		"option_c": 1949, 
		"option_d": 1950, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120130", 
		"question": "24KwZ9Hk0Aqq440lEhj71+7rdUjYAmsDrn6NEqxyMGXrUefyYuzwx55/IByqglZ2+2XVqqr+qBHb1SQYldNRlKCsulmh5MFr", 
		"answer": "25+5f5D70Avm9olgfBv61+i9Xkkdi7xnekUXzCwwojS0Cg==", 
		"explanation": "25+5f5D70Avm9olgfBv61+i/ImrDQ3YZpj+FW7FnZDHAXKbLfOD/x9d+IRydhV47wnrHrav5+VRPrKdW5IeMYysMcMtHwcPJ2+H2wHRTIM5NisBz6p5fav1TxTKjNMPeMvsux2CTM1flajyzEHF41DjYym9eqZOy+yD7QNIygBAzhIthrdE5PcWMmaeVqGS2gg+Dm2jRWLFlH1qQu8no7kWar5Aspo2jtDrJ4bPq2vvc/dMCdgVXsZI/d1T8mqcN/Tg2WNK1fBtE/6iQaFrpNTu3NQcc9cL512BgyYxlHWg68F9Dk5ZfdsFx2p2kuyA/KNliVTSvqkBFw9RoVxLWd7K13WH381wwez04JYNjtTk8oBuVPlFt2m+JXiVfk8Bi6sNZkwtxcG5UlWDlwiaOgXecPkfFNSJ7bpETE77oQ97YZF4=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Lal Bahadur Shastri", 
		"option_b": "Jawaharlal Nehru", 
		"option_c": "Morarji Desai", 
		"option_d": "Indira Gandhi", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120131", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV178xOnqJ26QDGRRt3eGEpN4cX/tXanFLs7xxJp4NE+AglUkskrI8uXRt1AAgbtP4JqKZCsMcIpjiNKG0/23+H8Tc+dK2oF28pMMc+ZZjD+icM2bNPEu2maFZ0L/cTyvCn1xmiWWtnIF6KL75jO6QM8jzwcr1oV36dF8P8Wa2LyW7A26n0aO3WzRdLMwUXCQp8ur/0+F4IM7tsKYvyba9vj82uzcsO4KcARbvot6bU/+DgfzVN+9hMdoOY4cKbqvSg==", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kU2ou//Q2AbZiGVbdoMovrUDhg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHD3Rjk+YwuVV7RyvDyPHjDCm0f42iCQeN1fjHmTLPQb6D9xpliM1WdmE9y/XjHr+Xx80UGnKdJ8M6dfyYaPoVg3JCN3vbyx2VNKoZFmYN98ZQLffZMyX25e5TrIexix2+NIkvkJxCpFzBhmjjHn3kWu5e64TKoFNs7zBolk4M45Nx8KNjf372d61mxiQjC1XWVTa1hH1Ccu9qk8gOdroZ4pd+Cpzvf8bT8gujW4spLYwxEtoV6I0+z17wB/Wo/Xt6xehxG9OrEIWPlKSSmZwcJucfi1X9swsItVHsx9wsGkoJEbsly253qqDMiJo1rFjC1tkpUxpZ1Ux6CbfH42Xz3oEc6dnUmaI9juCwhqACSOxRtk2ySRSpYl4Fl6twA1Q1te2NVmXjjhzvLkGqDdZD6po39juH+p/li/KdnLUSWMFDXRoAZa6eANHNgy/2eCq9ZIN3BWeboCbQdcHFqaY7H/c6B", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 3", 
		"option_b": "2 and 4", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "3 and 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120132", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iOSB0qTHyHBPPc9KncBR65cSdedTxTKjNMPaM75qy32DNUzyYj39BWM0lT+Wj39Zpoy2/CT7V9s1yRs3gsd+4tp8KN+amauc/UOslB/C4HWjTbx3HlrZ/fzhsQO1tMIxu8uBpDfV9/H92vbS5NcEbAle/5Zwb1K/jugI+zg3Qtv0exdI5evCchYX3rFevtztUnhx2BgIRojP", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "25+5f5D70Avm9olgfBv61+i/IW7CDmcV42uLV+NEfHDtWq7Maa3dxpp8Lk+ahFR1snfV46T+t1YMgKZU5IecMCECfIJhzcTJ0O3hwX8BOtJX2pd74J9SbvVOyzSjc5TJL/JrjmeOZ0vxczCyCnF41DTVhXJZpYq4tTe0WNM02RgznY526og9P8WQyrvT+0i7kgmQzzu/TbV2BBSLsM2n7E2Vuoc89dmFtHLY+/n0k+vA+dEFJRsSr49pbE+9m+gb9yY9EcG6KAFf9OHCaFrqYAGtIwccvtij03dmyI0kVGp08BpQh49Zcs122IyklDdwLchsECGopkAA05s8VgPWda740Wak3Bc6dnUlaodkv202oA2VJlFqpincWCMRkY179tEKnB5mPWZUjzbpjy+EknGOcpDmq4nyxfv4oalq/KRnOU6MPF/RU55ccbvBMyd7x/maDrJZN99xFjDvMsA9vDjqMJOXyypN399gO3/itCmWh8PhK3z9oNL+nNthALdCYLaVmUe9m6U4YP7rpYDTJg==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is NOT the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120133", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YLy+6IdhNV2Anl474mTJpLf15EBPgK4bz4eJdWI6e4p9iOCF1urkhE1PYYZilZJ/8ZYeaPEA6jS7cZTiJf98jl6MJkvjJwWzVzBQkSXTmHFfpob75Su6Wpon0hw9hI5s5M0vfNaR3eiB7V63kxSB2TuQRLFrElWNvMGmq3+S9MIRsciDpTvd7bT9n/7a89cObAtbupU/alX8ha0a9z8qUs2nVBx8+eXEIUPoMi3jMwYYucbi33opwJcnXn09+xFVwoxQItR709jUsDM+McRkEnOZrElNzodvVhiYK/8mupuMgkT2q8JFp5rBhj0p", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kUqoTRikMfo2huO6iLkTw9A3OA==", 
		"explanation": "2569cdH1xBfp44wvXA2yzPP8OX7UBmZRpXCRX7Z4cWXqWqCCfuH/x4Q9Z1iMmV5p/3/Iqqv3t0MdhqdJ4JqWdTFPPophzJCb0vf40WNCNoZFlox955sLdftOjAmlcZTrLP9gwGeOIAXTaDSwDWNnnT7YzW8WuJGy+CapTZolzxk31pB5/ogoM5eby6mV/A27iQuSzn6ZTbN3GEKc9eih/UbcmYc5p429vTPV57TtkvnHsNEedgRbsYN7I1+5ga0F9zo1VMagaR4L9uvRbUetISanZx0J68r303Ngw5FpdH109QxVh5BFZ8QzxZ3nqD0iPsEqGza/p1cMh5VwUxiVdam91Cj25UYwYGgoYJkh/Cw7pU+YLUB7iGaVQilV1JRj+5AWhwBmby9PmjbwkDaEkmybZdPl5JK8k+niqbZ24eM3O06KMF/MRc0da7eALml73uCaGa9KNowlJHdwItLCuSum5/lp+oyzJQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 3 and 4", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120134", 
		"question": "25GxbNHn2Ryqx4khXBD7y/q/FmTdDmsCsHaMXORnMGPsWKKCZ+P9xYJ1IljJn154/XvLpqv0/l0Iz6lf45uMZC8GcJ98iNKIxOHzhH5Pc8dUipJz7YkecOcAwzvtUt3NJb5Xy2+SZ3X8ZjeuRqeJ5zYZlHEB/fwdg55CD7E=", 
		"answer": "24GKXbSxHm4A89/yf9ZfF9Op1Z8h7g==", 
		"explanation": "25SoeIPy2Arj+YJgQhLzy73vJ2TXEWcCsD+CXKc0YnTgW6rPa+P6wJl2Z0yGgVJ46zbHp6/l5EcCiqZP+s6IcTFDf8tp3d6Kw+34yjFONYZQkoUy1JYecvpJwjrtV9vWLfd93WePKQXEbzz9B395mTjFmXVZpsO4+imvXdQizwAhmp444McyNcOQy62XqFmwg0aSznSWWrh3AhSWs46n5USTqYw/9d2fvjje9+Dq2vnd9J4OdAleqodrZl/8g6AMuC8+V823fBtd9OrVcketLy7jNwER8Mjq02cp5IM6WG10+xEGlotTIsFjxorltSExM94mVTqu41ZFxJtxUhKYcLi8kGng6kAsYXcua55+/Cw7pU+RJ1B3nGKfTThYm454vsQW1QFtbnpSmTb0ij6fwHGHedPz54HylqjipbRi+60iLQGBOVXfWIgYJaTJM28yyeGaA6FVPZgnEiHpM9oj9Tq5I5ma2zAZ2dYuPDfm+i7ZlcL0NXb40VUPAm5H+pAxJttg8ZJwHQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "TRUE", 
		"option_b": "FALSE", 
		"option_c": "Partially True", 
		"option_d": "Uncertain", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120135", 
		"question": "25y2KIb72Brit5wlUwyywfT7dX/YBiIWrGmGQK15dX/3FKbSfv/x35IxM1SMzV5o5nfEr6zj/14Kgbwb5ojfXgs3V8tOycmG0KTjyzFTNtZIm4N3pI4XebRwwDyjet3VJ75NwWONLlbjbjazWzLp87AZTbbdveIeFrfAoXPH", 
		"answer": "y+XpPc6/2cEE4rEbgCrb924XnwI=", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgRR/hhfjsIWrSD2sCq3qHEqx6MFviWrLDfPS+mNsxdQzY2Bc75nmGsaDg+1IMiuhP4YvfQC4CcIVmxtfJ9Ov6yXhSIM9LlMBG7J9fUt105X2Mdc3UJ7IuwXzACUTkbjazBXw0vT/FnnVCvZey+in7UtUlgCEgl4lr68cuMd6R3ui65kmxh0rC0XqDQ7hgUVXZpsah7VfcppA3uI2OtDzP5vX1k+LW9J4bbglcsY9xZBuomOgIuCc3Q830eBNZ5e3TaETsNCexPk4c98+j1XtlyoMrUns14BZQh8NXctBh2ZnntHIZK41sGjCvsEFEh5tyHxGZZ6m9wmHq5xU8enU7YJhsqCQjpE+aLVB7iGqQRT9c1IFl+pAQmwdsb39Pjnf0izGMwHabfYfm+Me8le3is6lm8bcuP0STdVXWFp0TabrDPip/y+KSA6Eelp3Pa5AW14gPPKu+rFmtsQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": 2013, 
		"option_b": 2014, 
		"option_c": 2015, 
		"option_d": 2016, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120136", 
		"question": "24KwZ9H71Bju8oFgRhb3hdTxMW7ABmwVpnGXEoZicX32VbPLYeO+5pF3Ll+MzU9z82KGsaDz+F4CiqZf7IrfYyERf5t/wd6Ol/D/wTFxP8dKlIl849o8c/lNxS6+fdvVYPdgjjzQdhGvJcWR5LzONw3jBNky3mbEf7s=", 
		"answer": "25i3ZoX22lnZ/osnWl7TzfHqImrcCmNTG8rgxGm+TBItqctVvZur6Q==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa3x3v54AuVhv80b3aI2rcFmMFqnCNEoxydnjgUefKa+z6zJMxJUXJoFR15nPN45b5+VQHz4lT5ZuIcS4Kf8t9zdOG2unyynVEN4ZXmZJz9IoWcvMA2DWoNOTXIfBgx2CHZ2b/ajS0F2N9mz+Wg3IW+tPqoWePXN93zxM0n4R9rckvL9KMyq2XqFmwg0aB03acQa53GFuX8t3o+0aOpo0quMyDsjeb9fr92v3V9tsIdgFEuoh6cEjw16QM+S4xX8/0fB0L5ezVIUT/LzisNA8Ruc3sxDRg0pFpT2wk+B5Fh45TbNQz4pDh/CA1PMJnGDa0p0VUzptyHwWTcrG903zh5BUrfX9rYJxisDs8rwjcJlF7nnjcQyoRvY5v99FehkRmfmBOk3v5wj6FhCWbdJaj74XvjPr14L9s4OMmaUyPJ1mYUpQSZL7JJCdzxO3bDKJdI4tmFS7jfcUi/Tf3KZiTnyoZwswjO2L18Wgx6zuIBVVGzohL9rfynvYE", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "C Rangarajan", 
		"option_b": "Suresh Tendulkar", 
		"option_c": "Montek Singh Ahluwalia", 
		"option_d": "Arvind Panagariya", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120137", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+zxhj5t5EoV17cxOn2OmXRDyI1pmmGXqxkfXTtQOfhYfjwyp59Z1qAn0hvsnPVt6Ty+1och61ftszr+Rtbsz7AiJQD6X6M07cp", 
		"answer": "yOztOimz8LBMRaHaCvEbetjxN+M=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHd0A3j+IshXl7WwOv6OWTADmcftz+gXbZ6c3jvFLDDfa3tzIMxMkzJglU702PBtrbktwVDz/kCvNzfRCoGPqVL65CM2uHlw3RFc8dX2oEy9JYeaPJP3jDtctvJYP1hwX6FNUTkbi+4RHZxkDTEi3Bfu477/Cn7fdQzyRR1hcdo4ckyMt6R3uiD+kK7gxWRnFKFCL92HkGevdro/0ybpZYwsN/NsjfV4Ob4lrjS/tpLcRxTq4M/ZFSqkroH9S82Rdv0fB0L9eHcaFboMim3Ik4S94vn02Jsyo05UGw64B5KwpNEa89h34ztuSF8f8tlBie/sU1OwNR/UBuadb+3wmnw6VoxNXslYcposj4gswaSLxRqkmqIDDxdlY54vscchwEjaW5JkHnyhzvLlGrPbpbk4o/yhOSwrrxm9rBlpsGFyKVktVgdpdBpCjh0bw==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": 1947, 
		"option_b": 1950, 
		"option_c": 1952, 
		"option_d": 1955, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120138", 
		"question": "24KwZ9H12Av548UjWh/71/j7dX/YBiI/omuKXa11fDHHUbHHYuLuxJJ/Mxyqgk518X/K/Ofbk5n8z0WMAYscVucTMYa5", 
		"answer": "25+5f5D70Avm9olgfBv61+i9Xkkdi7xnekUXzCwwojS0Cg==", 
		"explanation": "25+5f5D70Avm9olgfBv61+i/ImrDQ3YZpj+FW7FnZDHAXKbLfOD/x9d+IRydhV473HfSqqr+9l9Pq61N7IKQYC8GcJ8v69+c2ef+yDFpOtUEloVz4J8Nb/xJ3H2kepTPKPsu4EqjZ1f1bje7C2J3kTWWgnVF6IC0+CqyQNcyzgFygog46MYvKcWW16/T4EyqiwmM1XSEW/1nHluJsNyp/0qTrsI6sNmatDfVtODxn7jQ9dAfcAle/4FwdV6umaUM9j54UMawKAZD9KTDdVX5JTvjLgBd+Mjr33F/z4wuHUA68BZHxZAWZsVl05TrrD81MdlrGXO1oU5FxIB1SRKFNqaxQ0AoAxq259ljvvHY3Z8=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Lal Bahadur Shastri", 
		"option_b": "Jawaharlal Nehru", 
		"option_c": "Indira Gandhi", 
		"option_d": "Morarji Desai", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120139", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRkGuCRqZ5dX/3R/3+YNr2yIMxLlGZjFhvsnLPp+Xk/1ZPoalP4IGRcS5DWo55zdyGx+nyymUBEMlRlIN76NoXfeJFjDSjfcDSIfJi1zHAG0uhJwmvC2Z9kDTSyn0Wroyp4Cr7UtUlgDY3mJNq6IUvKNaL3OiQ50Kqgg+M3W+YR7MkLVrL9eum6kGQpYZ4sciAvjHJ9eDwmbjX9d0ObBxAvop2cFqonqcHuCU+Edi4aRxF+OrXIWjjc2iHLgII7c7nlmRm0Yc7Tik78l9VloJCZ4B02Y7hrjw9OsN+BnOGrRAA9IB9SxKFNLW51Cjw7xU+eXMsa8p9sCw7sk+LIUB22miZQjhDlYwr7sIQmhZqaWZFj0rutTeCg23Pc5Wj/4j5xe7/rLVs5aopLgGBJ1mYVYIOd7bDMzgwLzSsQbNwAUGuKoh23hNgRQ==", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHd9Tqq8YQjWxL70fzrMG+QIGcft22GH7BgcWXmFKTNYf/6wJlwM1WGgxt6/HKGp6D9+FAdjrxS6s6bdSEGcJ99ydyAzeXjzX5Pc8Rd2od78pMRe7RT2Dy5ccebIb58wWKFZ0z+JymxBX56nT/RylVC6JC+5zG+UJo201Uz1oF3/90xfNGQy+iX4V67kxWR1XSfW/1rHxSJusKh6Frcpo0quNiBsCbS+/q12vnf/NEcawZV/5VrYk+5hOgd92ouXsG3bVJf+eHZcxTuLyagIhwT6oejxXxo1IdpWHEk8Q1Ph41VZ9M/lpnquHIxPNljAza2ugRDyJpoTR6UYam9kHzroEY3dGoia40tlSMxqA7bOxR6n32ZQCNBmYVl6pAYkgFteW4CGax9VbOsFHPiQ22sgdXVmA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "3 and 4", 
		"option_b": "1 and 2", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "1, 2 and 4", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120140", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iOSB0qTZ4FIBMcNHm413pJYab+cAyTurcdfPKehrjm+GM0DiJxe4DGJh0yKWjnlXvIv7ySmJUdskzxty3rUxt4gfOdmLy63e+1m5kgPC33SfTrFtEkCK9cem6FGZoZE9sY2auCbTtPf8lOzB8dICeA1W/5ZzYlWynqYOuCghEdy8bVJo9OrEc1Gvrp7WEzIxsw8TAJfIj6bVMg==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "25S+fJThkTfv/5c1FQ2ywfj+IWOcQ0w1gD+OV6ZgeX/kR+fGa+7ywJl0IxyInht493jSsaT8/kkKi+hL5Y+RfisNectmxtOb0uXkwXUBEMNKjpJ3qYkLfeBFjCm4Z8fXJe0u+maFZ0H1ZDW0CnU0nT+WpFh16I6+8DOyWt0kgB07kY905M80KNKbmbyb7Q27jgeO0H6fT7h3UVuf9cOp4k2IoYs2vMOK8THU++T8iPnH+cgOIg5Xu4NtYle1hKVJ8SR4RcCxKBNJ4uHeYlGtLy7jCQsV696kxTRqzoM7VHo59QtPgcNaZ8F304r3tDsgf/liEHO9sUtXzpp7HxSZeru02Wvw8xU9cG48YI9j/Dk9pE+fLVpqiGqQDCtegoV58N0cmxAjfGFE3GX0gyuOkyWacpfm+ZP/ivr1pPl3+qZnKk6NJVDdToQIbLbTZ2h0iuuaAadSMJZpEGLlONs67jj1KYyR23kd3NguIX7p82qOm9n9eXe/tJv2gNV6VL4VIt7L5sau8tb5PSsS35n+ihNs+YEEF04=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is NOT the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120141", 
		"question": "25y2fJT0wxj+8oFgQQrz0fi/JWfRDXFRonOKVa1xdDH0XbPKLuP/3Z5+KV2FzUtp+3nUqrH58kBPhqZf4I2eZCcHPoov29iA0fC30H5WMtRAicBN26UgQ8t/8wLtZNjaLvBnwGnALkuwTje5DXE294fSKbCPmyFFmSANXzV4YA==", 
		"answer": "27a9ZoXh0BXj7YAkEGGK+HuBn9yyAC4po0IRUns=", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX2kQnm9oszEhf80fj4J2rECmwW42iKRqs0c3TtQLXDYq3u255+NVWdhF5osnLDrqr+5Ecdjrxe7c6WfiERe4p8zdTJ1OH50GNAP89en4Qy9JYecvpJwjrtQ9zSLPsu2maFZ2vURHm8DX1xkHHChTxQp5Cv8DX7V9U40BAgl5Nx+818OtKb3LqS5ESri0rCyHOUCLRqBVGep8+84kyS4I0+9d6ZsCbetOT1m/bAsMkCdgASvINxd0m9m+gZ6iM3Q8GgYRdYseXcclutMi2lKwse7c7nlmBhw8IgU2844RpIgYYWbcYz1Z3qqCAxM8RwEDf6s0hByZp1URDWebi72Gnq6UYyZjofbYN+/C46rxmZOlN7lGiZDC1dmI98+9RZkwtxPW4AiXjphDaOhCWObIPx5IH/jajkr/li8asuLFeJO1uYWIwIbLzOJmsyzuyNCKpTI5JiGTamOtov8Cq5N56d0zxN0dojIGLp4COXlY3zNnf6oZf+h9t4FbNAINDX4MqjuVPJcmF87iWNYyYtRkubETnm9Znn", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ce,nt,ra,li,zed", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120142", 
		"question": "24GwbdH03hjmt4omElnVxO/2N2KQK2MFonDEEutGdXzsQqKCXuLozIVlPhXJmlposnfCrLXk8ldPhqYb/YaaMB08QbRQ9++26NvI+05+DPkEvIlk4domefVSjA2hddqZNcqxWkVcVyNPPMZYwSB0gQ==", 
		"answer": "25OxboX7k7RBKCyJOeZaPPJs2+fZLDA=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH03hjmt4omElnVxO/2N2KQK2MFonDEEutGdXzsQqKCXuLozIVlPhXJmlposnfCrLXk8ldPhqYb/YaaMAQKeJ9niPaAweG3/XRAIYZ0loF8pNJOJaMUgWr0PZTvKPsuwWyKIkbkbi+4RH9y1CHZnHlEvJr79Cu3Ucw+wQE7mYk4+MY4OcWM2qeB7Un4rwiG1XrWW/1nHlmUvNql7k2I4JY39cyJtSDe5+fwlP+T49EIawdXvIlxbFa1lOgN8TkoUNq9fBtO4qTkaVGtMCSiKU4c8Mbm0jR9ycI8TWU98gsGj4JEZcl915Ttpjc0f95vFiezrEpTh5t6HwSZd7S9xHGk9F0tem8sbcp5vT8ypBuZLBRulWeVTyVUh8Bq8NRZnApqaWZBiH/2hyzLlG2OaNPi4o35gajkr/lq/7M1JleFdVDRQIQSYvPTM2Z8zuiJCbUcMpFjVy32Ldo86Cz3KYKd2ipPXHikj6v7dc2OZ/Ne+l54aQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Fif,th", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120143", 
		"question": "24GwbdHZ0Bfr44RgYh/g0eS/PGXEEW0VtnyGVuNgeHSjV6jMbeju3dd+IRy2smREzUn5nJqw80YdhqZcqZqXdSsRPphnx8Kdl/DyymRTNoRmZiCSBjFw8JjcYFP9RX9F", 
		"answer": "24e3ZJ363x6qx4khXA2wY07pdZcDB4US42jBlsPqLg==", 
		"explanation": "24e3ZJ363x6qx4khXF7lxO6/IWPVQ3YUsXLDR7BxdDHlW7WCeuX7ib1wKV2djBtL82TSuuLjt3UGibxTqaiWZidDR45u2pC52+X5hHVUIc9KncBm7J8WbrRTxDK/YJTJNfJrjlqIIgXkYiuwREw2pj7ahnVYr8OL+Sa1aJh30hA0moJ7+c04fMOX3OiV5EigjwSO2TuQWK12HlWavY6p70yMtIc89cmYozvV87Ttkv2T4NIKbE9B/49yc1e5mq0H7CssWMe6KDtfseXZbFHpYDysZwsT6t7x0zRowoM5SWg2/RNPlpoWds8z1ZDlsjU5McoqEDC1rUtNzpc8XBiYcLSs2Wfq8xU+e35rdYVhtS4s4R+OIVtsk3+VST8d1IFn8t8OnApkPWlPjjbhhjWek3GCeZ33+MD9lqj+pbxn96dlsXjvnDbqtHWxfLJO6qu9OA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ro,ll,in,g Pl,ans", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120144", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+zxhj5t5EoV171yvzzdWTWQyU2om2KUKo0WHD3VaiFLuz6xodlIljJj0I75n7D44L/4VYdgaVe55rffyRDV4VrwdHWldO5w1wbLmb7Mlkopyn4PCU=", 
		"answer": "25OxboX7kT/j4YBgaxvz173POWreQZyJ48P1TzyDveEXTVRfvWE=", 
		"explanation": "25K5epjx2FnC9pEhXVmy0vzsdWrUDHIFpnvDU7A0cTHkW6bOLunr255/IBydhV471H/At62w0VoZiuhi7I+NMBIPf4Uv2NWb3uvzhEVJNoZFno9i8JMQcrRPyn3qU9XJKfxnjkaBM0T/IHm8FzB11DLThGhEqY/78ii6WJolxRw8kIhq7s04fMOX3OiD5Ey2wRXC2nSSXa4kHlrZpcG+7lGIucI9p8yJuDHa4P32lLjn+NtLcgRTscZ2bU+umKwc+y88Ecn0ehNF9uGQblKtLS2iNBsP/Nij131kw4ZpXH108RJWjZRTcMl90djgtSExO9trGye7pEFEh5NuUAKGZ/253myk8lA7YHkia40ttSM2rgKZaF1wn3qJTSBYgJknvt0Yhw9qc2gAnTbziziFiWOGf5Lt/8Dvke3g4K1s5aI1LVLAPFLbWpgPbKXFZ2N33OyXArZRNpFzVQp9/C3LqI0+JFTfZw1+oOw=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "First Five Year Plan", 
		"option_b": "Second Five Year Plan", 
		"option_c": "Fifth Five Year Plan", 
		"option_d": "Sixth Five Year Plan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120145", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQr+9pElXxv80b38OnnCBmEFr2bDVqZnc2PqVqLRLuzwiZ58N12KmRt09DbSq6CwpgpY3OhU4ILfczAKbYJ8l5C12bW37WUBP8NA2pR9pIkKbuRM2S7tZtHNJfB7y33AIUriJza0CDBxjCHZmGhfpoT7+yavXdU501UOmNU4ysQzPtaTmaea5A2olA+B2WjRXbNgFEaOsMC8q0Lcs4o5p93NtTfY+P33n7jv/o1LRwtdsYlyalj8kLoG7z4wEdu4ZwVO9aTRYkbiMzvjKg8T4Ivt12BgyYw6HVU6oF9vjIdfY4Bx05bhujskOskqEyG1rgRJyZduWhaFcbn432HooFAnZXU5cZkvrxrKsIaW5oYxdix8N7ANNQ==", 
		"answer": "yvwnKJ+ujOLGzJfJDbSUHkw=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdGiiE65t4opXl7x1/TsPHiQD2cV42uMErBgcXblWKbWZ+LwiZZ/IxyMjlR1/XvPoOX0+EQBm71J586WfmIOf4V2iNOGwurj1nhEIIZAj4Uy8JVfdP1HxDi/NNvSLL5+3GeDIlawUzG4RH99mHHVmHVFoZD7+iH7BYNgk1U6l4M46sQzPtaTmbqW+EiqhRORz3KeRq4oUVeWu9q64kGJtIs2so2ZvnLatPf2l/ra/t8fawdc/4l5I0iolq8H+SQsEc23ZxxE/O3TIVP/Lz+3L04c98+j3n1uzsIgU2849QtPjY0Wac58wZakvSFwA495ATK9pUhB051zUSvUNImw1Sj36FQtZTo5bJlo/CQ74QCVJBRuiGKfST8RkIl47MUJgQFnPWpDk3jvjzaOkyWYc4Hv75f1ge284LVm86cuJ0bAIVOYVYUdab/FKWB32amSA+ZRMpFmECvoOpUs8y3xYJ+a2TUMxNAvITfm+i7Zh8PwNHW2vIv0i9piVpvDZEgZH3WJL8vnly5xKwY=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": 1, 
		"option_b": 2, 
		"option_c": 3, 
		"option_d": 4, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120146", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+zxhj5t5EoV17G0vjxIXKQM20YrWvDYrF7d2PiWarHLuv324RlZ1CImFV4+nPC46fpt0cHiuh85piaYiwOe4V7iN+Pl835wHhAbITMjG0jefQK9yqX3Nc5MqFS", 
		"answer": "yOzvPR+D/K1Sx4qpguxQzXSYAYQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHHxhzk45xgYhH7y+m/BXnfBHAQrnKGErR1YzHvVbLMbeX7zdd4KRyjmFdisief9PCww1sKz5xM7ICLaWIzcYJh3JC5xevw1nBMPsMEm4l/4Z5faPsAzTmpZtHIM75vjnyBKUL1Jza7RHRxgjTahWxbrY2v9Cv7V9I2zBk3mIB9/oR8Ndmc1b2X4UO/xhaNyn6DXKQoUVGUpcKn8k6ZrpZ09ciJpDHa4P32lLST8dAPIhtdvI9+bxurkqQP+Tg9Efy8bVJI/unAc1HlJSawLhgYudvx2XN7x49pTmYh8xdSwpdZIsV93pnqvzdwK8VvVSKvokhJ0408UBHWeLS+1Sji70d/XHQvbIsqr202qBuVMlFwiSuIRD5egYdjvsQYhwNmaWpE3H/uiyuCgXGGapbwq4Hygajgr7Vq8bpnJESBJknKU55efraAM5LSbvGfzGgyty2JNw==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": 1972, 
		"option_b": 1975, 
		"option_c": 1980, 
		"option_d": 1985, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120147", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iOSB0qTD03RPJ98Eqo976o5fTOZPyy+sedneYOlv3S6DKEvzYjCrAXQ0gD6Wg3FGuoyt8GevXN930QAzmo5s9IgzOpeT0K6WpA29lRaH33KQRLF9UVKWp46840bcsI03p42xvw7VxvH4iffdsJY5K1ISlpI/blSynrwG6i88Ecm6fBsG4evGZEb5OWiiKQpd697x13gpwoc/WGU75BJDjJcWccN705Xhr3BlFAAVls3Za7o6ckn4vM4m", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHHxhzk45xgYhH7y+m/BXnfBHAQrnKGEqV7c2TwUaOCYeO+xJh/LkiGn1J19TbVoK31+lYcz65U+86PfzQGbJ92iNGF2+HhzXBVOslK2oF84NoNaeZBwH2pccLeLPF+w2uOMwXkaHm0CWBmmyfTymhercOq4Ca3Xc4ugBo01otx6818CN+ambiB50qqhwvFzzuURa1sEEeQpo6n5QORr4wxocKfuDzctPX3nrjW5t8HdwlGtolxI0m5kaQM+z49VYi1KBFE/OnZdVnoLjzjMwFd687ww3h91c8tT2Ai8REGhoZAZ8x8xpXhsiZwHdQqASG7oE9JyZM8Sx+TNK2q32/25UYsNXUtJZpiqigntRbcKVhyn32VTThYm44r/94d1RZ2b25M3HLllDqHj3WCeZ33q5P/je39paovsrcvLAGQJ1PfRIwRJbLJKmJ2iv2UTaNSIIp1EmLjO9Mr/y3wNpPU1jQd3NwtKnnz9T6QncO1OGu+85/8j8djBr4COtSF4MansV/TI9pFmr2E11KGmJY2Met39Q0=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is NOT the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120148", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+zxhj5t5EoV17fwPD9MHmQDGRRk36RXqp1fXTtQOfuYe7/xddQNVmIzX9+5HPKrLX98l0bz5tY4YuSdWJLU7tD6fS6nqTxzWNSJ4ZNlJRg654Kf/FEk39LY56O+k7ntUJCF/gukjf7", 
		"answer": "yOzhO21TkGkCsnhgkZqlc/Ww1P4=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHe4TXL08UzURb3yPi/ImrDQ24QtnGAWqZwMHjtFIPHbejzy5JjZw3Q1Ag7xn7D44j1+lEKnbsb5ojfQCMRcoJuxdWHw6Tby3JAP4ZliIVzpL4aavFMwy2gcdrPYM1txmuNIgW4SgmRJVQ91DDfh3lS6Je0tSK2RNUgxQdyu7drrdwzfNab3bqW+174igmB3XfRQbNiA1WKody96FeJsod4u8iItSGbwPz82uvQ+NsGZ0hTs4pwYFqokqxJ/j82Vdv0fB0L3NTDIVLiMmixIg0S9Mbm2HBgyIVpWWwi8RNJko5TbNQzxorrtjczK94qHD36t0xFzoY8XBiYZ6mxxH3h7lY2cGlnJY9jvS85qAGbaEB2n2bcWCMRl49l6sIQlxF3eC9Ukzb0ijrLiWifbpz17o35i/ywr78j/qwkKE3ANlPVW5gSbKfJInQwi8JWXqBG4ZMAWPNuXgnsqA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": 1990, 
		"option_b": 1993, 
		"option_c": 1995, 
		"option_d": 1998, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120149", 
		"question": "25iIRLDX4lnr/ogzEgr9he/6NmTdDmcfpz+UXbF/YzHhVbTHaq3xx9d9KF+IgVdisnDDr7Gw81YZiqRU+YOafjZDcI5qzMPLFI4Su3wbs/Tbbfe3mI3Tqw==", 
		"answer": "25iIRLDX4ltlO1hJlRZol1eyiXyOeEXB", 
		"explanation": "25iIRLDX4lnr+4kvRQ2y6M3sdX/fQ3AUoHCOX6Z6dDH0W7XJfa343Jt3LlCFhFV8snrJoKT8+0pPia1X/c6WfiQRf5h72sWKw/HlwTFPNsNAicBf1LY+WMcAyy+sesDIYNNe3S6UL0CwZiypDH9mnSXPymhZ6Iq/8CmvXdwugBQ8ksdr+M87OcSLmbiB50e9hRKRnG+ZSakkFV2LsM2851rcsocrpcKDtXLP+7Ttkv2T+dANcAlBq5RqYE+pha1J6i8pRMGmbR9O//DDIVvrYDyrIgcPudnmxWRsxZYgS2x09xBIkZdfdtV22JvtuSFwC8VjBnO+pkdFyYBuXhufbri8kGn08EcwdHkjJY9jrzgnpBzcPFx/jiuQQy9QmMBl+9UdhkRib2oAnXLkkDqYk2CLPJLt78Dojenk4L1m5KYrJlGNMFLMFogaY7zSM3Qyy/ueTaVQPIxiGzumPNkn+zf8JNaD1i0FkNovInry+iONi43lK2y1oZvth9FlVmfShkLCldc7gvchlwsUfr8=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "MP,LA,DS,SD", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "120150", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iOCI2ef/xWhAJ9UEkoFk4dobeflBwjmocJTII+xv3n6JKUKwaD/9KUBYtRXlykBYlI2J8CaoW9R3iCd7zMdM5c0lfMCe17zTxX2UpyKxnH2ERrl3UUCW9cytq0KQrI07tNmItXLf/eb8mezf6Z4fbUhesIV+bxu+mKwA/Tl6ecPGmC58WP7kocgiR85iJw==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "24W5ZpL70ADr45ZgWh/kwL3wJXvfEGcV41KzfoJQQz2jUKLPb+P6wJl2Z0iBjE8730bqgoHDt1UagaxIqYyaMCYKbI5s3NyQl/Tly2dIN8NA2pR9pJYQf/VMjD+icN3eM75owXzAMEribCr9N395kXHmi3JVoIKi9DOyFOg2ylU7mJRs5NwpKN6Q17vT4Eyug0aD2G2eS7xwFFDZs8G6q0LcrY0qsI2JuCDe9+C5m/Tf/90KdgFdscZwZRuRp4Qo3Bl4V926bAEL5euQbVvuISTjIAEL/Nnt33puhoAmWWAx51MGg5FRd8l90djwtDMkf9liHCD6olRQ1Zt9XB/WY7Kt3Gyk5Vs3dHQoYMp5riw7sh+dOlFwmXLQDC1Sl49+8MQYlw1vdHtZ0DbhjDvLhWOJeZD34pb5xf3kqbVq6KIzIE6OdVPeFp8ZdrzVNWR32amdArQcP5BkFi6mOdA4+TX2MJuR0S1NwMsvJXLk4DnbRvxjPY+qH9LLCKryA9c4Tg==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Introduction to Central Planning", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is NOT the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130101", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRtHqRV+NgeHSjW6XIa+7qwIF0NByGixt253rSquj88kUKg+hL5Y+RfisNectmxpCg2eD+xS59PZcEro8y9IgQcftUyX2pcdfeLup8z2KJPUTkbjazREx6xnHihTxQqYCy+S6vVc4ygAU3mZd06I8vfMeey7ya60SohxKL03XRdLM3UWCW9d28+UaSp5YwsMPNvT3Y9fi5mPfX+dsYIgtdsZVrak+pg6EG9is0XdGIZkYLxeuQaFr5JS+xJhoYucXiwn1myIMlHWg68F9KjYBXboBjxJHrrjskNsh5V6K0jiejVFSWASJWcuOn7bM=", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9FiCReDHSYbT1Rhi+bjtXhU5A==", 
		"explanation": "25iUWNHy2BTv88U0XV7i1/LyOn/VQ2YUoHqNRrF1fHj5VbPLYeOyiYd0KEyFiBxosmbHsbH59FofjrxS5oDTMCMNestmxsSM0Pb20HQBPcdQk4985ZZfffpEjDGid9XXYO58x2GSLlH5Yir9DX40hD3XhHJfpoT7xjOpUdQw1B03mI526ogwM9Se1eiR50mxgxXC33qcTf1oEECcp46+4kLco402ptmEpSfP/fv3m/ST8dMObAxfuohrcBnlzcPfrjF19vjhxIzeQQ1n", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 3", 
		"option_b": "2 and 4", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 4", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130102", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iP2c2/D+iX1EJcNI2pB+5ZQRdfpHjDusfdjeJL56wS6GJkb5azCpBWRx1DXTiXlYvJG6+S6hUd530BkzmIlx4898Ndnf8KaX4Uz4jwiLyHKQRLF9LVrZicCa7kKPr4x4/f/E63L3+/f4lrjR/9oCZxsSs4d8aF6416sG9jksWNyhfBtE/+XcIUf5ITy2NE4c98+j0H1nx4wqVGg4tA9JlYZEcYIxJESFV0PBiMRKyrHHofuM", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "25iUWNH32B2q+Yo0Eg3nxv76MG+QCmwYt3aCXq9tMHDwFKvNbezyiZV+I1WMnht383XNpqGw9FwBnLxS/ZuLeS0Nf4cvxdGH0+XjwTFAPcIEnIlh55sTPPVV2DKje9nCYOphjmuGIUDzczCrAXxt1CHXmGhfq4qr9DO+FNM5gAU+l4l25MY7fsYrdANDWV85Jx42U4HyoHw=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is NOT the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130103", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCNQbd9ZGT3UefWZui+6pJ/M06MwFd+5HPK47X89l0cz6FVqaeRdCsCOZgvxcWFw+26yHRXNsoEioxz6pQWcvMAyi+sedHML+xlkS68KRSwQTCrATBNkTDEykxaqY2oySnpFO4gxRsmj8dI4sEyKJevy6eU+ky1ugjRnFahZJxAImiX4Y6b/0KIpcIZu8OYsD6bxPj4lOuRGbMHZ+qHBXHLJ/MEoXk6sQ==", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "25a9ZoXh1FTm8pMlXl7iyfzxJivZDWEdtnuGEoV9ZnSjbaLDfK3OxZZ/NBDJuUx+/GLf45X//l0bz5hJ5omNcS9Df4VriP25+8XT9zPOJzCoteHV20X3tRhElVeH", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130104", 
		"question": "24asaYX2nBXv4YAsEg7+xPPxPGXXQ2sC42qNVqZmZHDoUamCeuXsxoJ2LxyehVJ4+jbPrbbk/kcam6FU54+TMC8GfYNuxtma2ru12Gm/4Qzx4wPEj5coK8NkOQ==", 
		"answer": "24asaYX2kSnm9osuWxD1hd/wNHnUECB/S84XHrLg3xGuYL4v7s6j", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX2wln/+YElQArzzvi/JWfRDWwYrXjDRqtmf2TkXOfxeuzqzNdBK12Hg1J19TbkrKTi80BPh61a7YubMCAaPp9nzZCq3+3ywjFsOshNiZR39oldYRfmhSOiN7Y/CGpMYvGX/Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Planning Commission", 
		"option_b": "State Planning Boards", 
		"option_c": "Zilla Parishads", 
		"option_d": "Village Panchayats", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130105", 
		"question": "25SsKIb72Brit4QkXxf8zO7rJ2rECnQU43OGRKZ4MHjwFKPLffnswJRlZ0yFjFV1+3jB46z9518Kgq1V/YubMCsNPqJhzNmIiKavKx3jObHs7MjSHkBL+MRl", 
		"answer": "24Gwep7m1hGqx4QuURbz3PzrJivZDSIDtm2CXuN1YnTiR+fDYOm+5IJ/Ll+AnVp3+2LPpra/1Fwdn6dJ6JqWfywQPoJhiMWb1eX5hHBTNsdX2AYhofQoQYi/ba9tp24BvFE=", 
		"explanation": "25Gxe4Xh2Br+t5UsUxDhhfztMCvZDnIdpnKGXLdxdDH3XLXNe+r2iadwKV+BjEJ65mWGqquw5UYdjqQb6JyacTFDf4VriP2c2e30zWFAP89Qk4Vhq7kQbuRP3jy5fdvVM75nwC6VNUfxaXm8FnV1h3PGHbLT+Y7N6DoATckd07Gq", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "State governments", 
		"option_b": "Through Panchayats in rural areas and Municipalities/Corporations in urban areas", 
		"option_c": "Blocks", 
		"option_d": "Town Area Committees", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130106", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iPSAxPDlzXJVc/ZIm4587ZQYPNdPwTCkYMDeJe0u2WuSIgX2aCuwAXQ0lTfCj24W/9Cp8WeaWd85xBg3mJM40cYAMuWa2Luc5g3wtE/YnE+eCK12FESYp8vo71GdppZ4scSepSDS9+C5nv3F9dIEcgVXsZI/c1e9mbtJ+jN4Use6ex1H+ODRdV3jJ2ivKA0c9Yvz2nVn1cD+Z2vIIhkJyPXl42q8LuYL", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "25GIS4Kzxhz48sUtUxD2xOn6MSvSGiIFq3rDBfBmdDHCWaLMauD7x4MxM1PJjlR14XnKqqHx41ZPn6lV6oaeaSMXPptjyd6al+350H4BN89XjpJ7545fbPhBwi7vKc4D7EArLFM9fuVN/hJfxg==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is NOT the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130107", 
		"question": "24qHV67M7ibVyLpgQRvg0/i/NHiQF2oU43GMVqJ4MHDkUanBZ+jtiZF+NRyLgVR4+TvKprP1+xMfg6lV54eRd2IKcMtGxtSA1qZ03E0clTwhAqnPTquXIb8i", 
		"answer": "25Gxe4Xh2Br+t7UsUxD8zPP4dUnfAnAVsD2+zRAoZVs/hoCQr9V68+YT", 
		"explanation": "25e0Z5L4kQnm9osuWxD1hfTsdX7eB2cDt36IV600ZX/nUbWCeuX7iZZ0IFWazVR9slLPsLHi/lAbz5hX6ICReSwEPqlgycKNxKb7Y9vZGBN3eSX0HOneUWhc", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Di,st,ric,t Pl,an,nin,g Bo,ar,ds", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130108", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQFWMDqn6NRrA0f3ejWKjBb+GzxZJnIlDJnVd6/HjPraKw/l1PpqZf4I/fZysXdst7wNWAxaTxy3JUIIZFiIVz98AjcshO4DS+YJTyYMln2mbAC0zjc3mULTKU82iEQrv91fpB35qLDk4a", 
		"answer": "24OxZJ3y1hyq+4A2VxKy1fH+O2XZDWVRrn6XUatxYzzRQbXDYq3uxodkK12dhFR14TqGi6z8+xMOna1aqZ6TcSwNd4VoiN2Iw+f/wWIMA8lUj4xz8JMQcucAxTPtfN3XLOcuz2CEZ0H5YT+0B2V4gHHCj25EqYq15mv7YMg+whQ+1oZq6Ml8LNue16aa5kr4iweW33OUW/BQA12btMLo+0yMtY45ocSCvyGZ1KbJFMooTmefDCTcKp4nfg==", 
		"explanation": "24OxZJ3y1hyn+4A2VxKy1fH+O2XZDWVRpXCAR7BxYzHsWufQe///xddhKEycgVp49zqGq6z8+xMOna1aqZ6TcSwNd4VoiN+Hl+z+yH1Yc9JBiJJz7ZQMPPVOyH25Zt3ZIfIuz3yFJgXgazizCnl6k3HCi25RrZeotTOpXdg2zFU1hIht/dt+7yGiJhyKZPiDiIZbHopP4w==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Tribal area planning matches,Tribal populations", 
		"option_b": "Village level planning matches,Rural populations", 
		"option_c": "Hill area planning matches,Populations in hilly and difficult terrains", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "match", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130109", 
		"question": "24qHV67M7ibVyMUwXh/8y/TxMivWDGEEsHqQEqx6MGHsRLLOb/n3xpliZ1CAm1J19TbPreX0/lUJhqtO5ZrfZCcRbIpmxsPLWNfOJpx8OWTr0HwtnrkUhg==", 
		"answer": "252xZJ2z0Avv9sfuwaY53iM/RyRqXMlk/HLg", 
		"explanation": "252xZJ2z0Avv9sUwXh/8y/TxMivDE2cSqnmKUaJ4fGijQKbQaejq2td1IkqMgVRr/3PIt+X5+RMHhqRX8M6efiZDeoJpztmKwujjhGVEIdRFk45hpu4x83xII/FokGrVtGM1IDY=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Hil,l a,rea", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130110", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRrl+ogpRgr3wL3tMGjfDm8UrXuGVuNwdXLmWrPQb+H305ZlLlOHzVp19jbDrrX/4FYdgq1V/c6QdmIzf4VswNGQ1vD+hENAOYZNlJNm7Y4KaP1Pwi7yNmNJJUrxQHyhG2E+vBAbMFo=", 
		"answer": "25e5ZIby3w349oxgfxv60fy/FmTdDmsFt3qGEFoFCyRXfA6zxa3d1ESNcf8=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHR0BX99os0QB/7hdD6PX/RQ0EernKKRrdxdTHqWueTN7ipiYV0JFOEgF519nPC46H19FYBm7pa5YeFcTYKcYUvyd6Nl+H61H5WNtRJn45mpJUZPMRy5S7tYNubMOxhw2GUIgX3dTiuF2J7myXFymxaqY21/Cm8Fs27fX3rnSQjHbQl6mPyTmY=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ashok Mehta Committee", 
		"option_b": "Balwantrai Mehta Committee", 
		"option_c": "L M Singhvi Committee", 
		"option_d": "G V K Rao Committee", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130111", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+zxhj5t5EoV16llu/7dUjfDXEFqmuWRqp7fnDvFIbPa+P6xJJ/MxyZn1Rt+3LPraKw9FwBnLxS/ZuLeS0Nf4cv28SIw/HkhGVOc/ZFlIN65YMeaOcA3Dy+Z9Hff7z4dTkEcmnQy7Ej6gxy6uzx", 
		"answer": "yOzhOkFx/+hPTcZoNeAZTHEpBvo=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdGkggvut6YvXA3mzOnqIWLfDWMd416OV61wfXTtQOfVb/6+2ZZiNFmNzVJ1sief+vew41xPn7pU/4ebdWIAcYV83NmdwvD+y39AP4ZXjoFm8YlfffpEjDCsetDaNPsu2mHAF0T+ZDG8HXFgh3M6eApqR+10sF+axT8x7E0B", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": 1985, 
		"option_b": 1990, 
		"option_c": 1992, 
		"option_d": 1995, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130112", 
		"question": "2523f9H33hz5t4MpXB/8xvT+OSvRFnYerXCOS+N8dX3zFLTWfOjwzoN5IlLJgVR483qGoar07hMfg6lV54eRd31DQoU+iPGF2+vg1zFNPMVFlsBm5YIeaP1Pwn2ReoabEvtq222FNAX0Yim4CnRxmjLTynNY6JCv9DO+FN0lwRsmhcdE45t8Gdme26SW+w29ngOByW+YR7MkHlLZucGr6k/csI45u96xv2abxOb2l/fH9c1LYwtRsJNxd1q+nqQA7DMEX/+8YRFDsevWIUDlJWilKAIR9tzq2HMpx5AsHWo75g1DgZcWcdRywp3puTwkLJIoZmX53jmvKoCU1XSiQpmhgg==", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "25Oxe5Ly3Vnr4pEvXBH/3L3rPXnfFmUZ43OMUaJ4MGXiTKbWZ+LwiZZ/IxybiF9u8XPC46H151YBi61V6ovffyxDbZ9u3NXJ0Pb2ymVSc8NJio9l4YgMPPhPzzyhNNbUJPdr3S6GKFewYzy+AX5ghjDag2ZTrMOr+Sa1WtM5x1c/bC2SqXNvNcQhufYtr1Np", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130113", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q440lEkmh1/m/NGXUQzVFt3fDcax6Y2XqQLLWZ+LwyJsxBlGMg19293jSsOX48l8fz6xe6ouRZDACcoJ1ycSA2OqohE1PYoZ0iI9k7Z4aeLRDwzO+YN3PNepnwWCBKwX9Zje5BWRx1CXZynBZq4K3tSW0UNMy01UOmNU4wMkyONaL3KzT+ki/kwqDzjuURLhnBV2Wu93o/0zcrI07tMHNsz3f/fHq2sTdo54ubxhdqINtZl/8sLoI9WoLUMq8aQELzeqEIXH+NCmhKwcO8c7nlkd9x5YsHU89+h5IgYYWQc9+25H3rzs/Md5WGwSyqkdIh5t6HwOecf2+32To70I2e31rZJho/C46sx2ZK0A+iX+dWClckY5/7Y9bF2zmPrOdfE+HvtJMiRdSag==", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHy3Bzk84glXArhhf7wO3jECnYEt3aMXKJ4fGijUarSYfr725J1Z1CGjlp3snTJp6z15B9PgqlV7Y+LdSZDe4dqy8SA2OrkhHBPN4ZXjpJ36p0LdPFOyTntU8baLb5dz2yIJlaykdi/l1VCs2Z23P04A0kADA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130114", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kT/j+YQuURuy5vLyOGLDEGserT+RV6B7fXzmWqPDeuTxx4QxNEibiFV85n7DraD0t0Abjrxe+s6ZeTEAf4dj0ZCP2Pa3xnRVJ8NW2oR3558RaOZBwDS3cdCbMPJvwGCJKUKvJwWzVTAtgDmWrHVYqY248GeYW9c6yQYhn4h2rfQybpfOiLybqGuxiAeM337Ra7JpHF2Kpsen5QOgrtF45J6ZuXL9/fr4lPvWsP0EbwVbrJV2bFX8q6ZduHtsRcD0ThtF8OrTZBTOLyWuLh0O8MTt6npezosqVSk78l9SioYWZM9/2pfztTw3f8x4EHO5rFZSwpdoHwSCdam93W3q9EZgN9G4C9Bz+KieRmL1Flnt7Qc=", 
		"answer": "2+b4aZ/3kU2oTH6dJ7jRLB/nSQexbLE+Sg==", 
		"explanation": "2+TrfJmz0Bfut9R0Rhay4/TxNGXTBiIyrHKOW7BneX7tR+fLYO7szJZiIljJnk965nPV5OXj/1IdiuhS586cdSwXbIpjiMSIz+HkhHBPN4ZJm5J54Y5ffvtS3jK6fdrcM75owXzAJUDkczyvRHZ9hzLXhjxQrYe+5ya3Xck6gvqSKPw1UWKBQHMyCHJI0Lc=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "3 and 4", 
		"option_c": "2 and 4", 
		"option_d": "1 and 3", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130115", 
		"question": "25Oxe5Ly3Vnr4pEvXBH/3L3rOivcDGEQrz+BXad9dWKjXbSCbf/33Z5yJlDJi1RpsnPApaDz41oZiuhf7I2afjYRf4dm0tGd3uv5hEZJOsVM2o90pI4XebRGwzGhe8PSLvkuz3yFZ0b/dSu4B2Q0lTPZn2gWvIuy5meoQNsjxRg3mJMnrwiHTydBMpo6y3prXPSplZg=", 
		"answer": "24GKXbSxHm4A89/yf9ZfF9Op1Z8h7g==", 
		"explanation": "25m3a5D/kRvl84wlQV7gwOzqPHnVQ2QYsHyCXuN1ZWXsWqjPd63/x5MxLlKNiEt+/HLDrbGw8VoBjqZY7J3fdi0RPo5pztWKw+3hwTFFNsVBlJRg5ZYWZvFEjC2hddrVKfBpjO75bFt/cvT49GKqurizeQ4=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "TRUE", 
		"option_b": "FALSE", 
		"option_c": "Partially True", 
		"option_d": "Partially False", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130116", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz3Rzut5EvEhv8zfzxNm7UQ3Aer3qQEqV7YjHFXanDYO77ibR+KlGAnkhy/XiGtazjulJCmaFIqb6TcSwNd4VoiPOG2un+12JIPMgEnJJ96dpOJa0Q32LtSNqKYNttwWCPKkzzJyu4An9mmSKWmHlHvYqp8CP7U8gywQE3hMdr+ckoOZeP2LqH4U6xlgeW1XSfCIFqQxS6us+k4leVr4x4pcKBuCbS9+e5m+yT5NYOIitXsZJtZhuAmftJ2yU2Qty9fAdf+OveYFitLSmtIw8J/Nij2XIpyo0qXGV05BNHjI1fbMcz6paw/AA1PMJnGDa0p0VUzptyTFeZcv3pgHzsoHM2e3slZo8tnyI4rAaPO11xlFeSeyRYl4gr8dZZgQxmPWlPkHrvlTaFhyWObpaj6I/ul+3ztPlw5qIzLEyFO0jLCc9SNb1i7LiUeA5u3IFVNjBH", 
		"answer": "25S0ZNH811n+/4BgUxz90/i9nRQLEAOvQrYd8yxhqAOnaw==", 
		"explanation": "25O5a4X8wwqq+4wrV17gwPvwJ2bDTyISrH6PW7d9f3+jRKjOZ/n3yoQ9Z1+Gg0hv+2LTt6z/+VIDz6Va54qeZCcQPophzJDYh/D/hFdic9RBmY9/6Z8RePVUxTKjZ5TINe5+wXyUIkGwdC28EHU0kjjFiX1a6Ia25SisUcg6xRsm1ohu6Np8DNue16aa5kr4pQmP0XKCW7RrHxb5OyzUpQssCecQ91A0GFFo", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 4", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130117", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+zxhj5t5EoV17UzO78NGeQMWcCs3CNQap2eX3qQL6Cb+P6ibVkI1uMmRtW83jHpKD98l0bz+B926yyOWIifZ8v2NGaxOHzmzOEVc/cKaWUch7zELh6wcN4", 
		"answer": "y+XoO74dOYtXXT2MI4ls8uyRdyc=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHV2Arp9olgYBvh1fLxJmLSCm4Yt2bDU61wMFP2UKDHeq3TyJlwIFmEiFVvsj7gkYfdvhMujLwb/o+MMDICbZhqzJCA2aTjzHQBKsNFiMAgtMpMPOBPjDi+YNXZLPd9xi6GLlbzZjX9AHlnlzjGhnVYrcO6+yP7RMgixBA8gsd17MY9O9KS3KaHqEK+xhaX3neYS/1iGFqYu82t+AOoqId4tM6Z8TPS+fH92uzcsNsFcR1AusZ2bU+5heUO/SQ9Q8mgYR1F8OiQZEX4KTy6ZwcTuc3qxXdoysIkXGc18xpLh41CIsF90tjoszw3ctlvBz76rkVD1Zt5XBiYe7Cx0yj39FQ9fHYicZMvGmgNQPzgeYcloMI7Sa5D2A==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": 2000, 
		"option_b": 2003, 
		"option_c": 2005, 
		"option_d": 2010, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130118", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kT/j+YQuURuy5vLyOGLDEGserT+KXKBmdXDwUaOCffn/3ZJiYByahVpp9zbJpeXz8l0bnalXqZqeaCcQIcl6IC2AiNHQa0wjxD9SdSEC", 
		"answer": "2+TrfJmz9xDk9osjV17RyvDyPHjDCm0f4Y0IE8iO0ap9LBWfsMsA09s=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdGigg3it4QuVl6jken3dU3ZDWMfoHrDcax5fXjwR67NYP6+2ZtwPlmNzVo74n/QrLHx+xMdgKReqYeRMCcNdophy9mH0KTjzHQBNc9XmYF+pJsKaPtOwzC0NNvdYO16z3qFNAXyfnm0CnNmkTDFg3JR6Jez8C6pFMk/wQc31oh+rcs5MsON2KTT/EyggxXC6HOYW/1pFFWKoNytq0KVrYc89dmC8TfW5Pvun+qT48oKdg1B/4dxZxu1mrgb9zw9Edy8bRtZseXSaFjkNDHjMwFd+sr302Yp0o1pUWY39RMGhoZAZ8x8xpXhsiZwMchvESD4wALngeC6evKBJ4pqL+LZkw==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "10th Finance Commission", 
		"option_b": "11th Finance Commission", 
		"option_c": "13th Finance Commission", 
		"option_d": "14th Finance Commission", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130119", 
		"question": "24GwbdHD3Rjk+YwuVV7RyvDyPHjDCm0f436NVuNSeX/iWqTHLs7xxJp4NE+AglU75XPUpuXj8kdPmrgb/ICbdTBDaYNmy9jJ9Ov512VIJ9NQk4985ZZfbOZP2jS+fdvVM6EseCNqpWXnN9uxqkRzqbkcAA==", 
		"answer": "25SqfJjw3RyqpdNyEh/8wb2tbTuSdCXgHF834Iyy1+QdZy5D6A==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH2wg3r9YkpQRb/wPPrdWTWQ3YZpj+zXqJ6fnjtU+fhYeDzwIRiLlOHzVp19jbgqqvx+VAKz4tU5IOWYzEKcYUv39Gal+L2x3hNOtJFjoV2pJgGPOBIyX29ZtvNKe1nwWCTZ0r2JxivEHl3mDTFyi4A+sO6+yP7BoJngBo01pNw6IgVMtOW2KbTy0K2lRKLyG6FQbJqUWCRsN2tq0CTrY8xpt6EvjzItOT1m+HW9J4PaxtGtoh8dxuumKQM62oxX4iyZwBG5OjRdV3jJ2inIhgY9cTz23Fn0sI5UWg6519HjIcWY8x/2ZvlqDs+OI1sHD27rUdJxpg8TRKFe6iq0233oEEwNWk/ZJ5or2F1swqPOFF9jmKKSSBI1p8g4tDUXFwZ9Hci2opP0Xk=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Article 245 and 250", 
		"option_b": "Article 262 and 280", 
		"option_c": "Article 302 and 303", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130120", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kSnm9otgQBvxyvrxPHHVByIFq3rDXKZxdDH3W+fDYuT5x9dhK12Hg1J19TbRqrH4t1YMgKZU5IecMDAGeIR9xcPWlfAkSiGv0JDgRm+BbGCN1dE=", 
		"answer": "25Cxb5nn2VnM/pMlEif3xO+/BWfRDSBSqaH5tqbgHLcx7CDKMEhS", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHW2B7i441gdBfkwL3GMGrCQ1IdonHDGvItKSOuDfCLLv/7yph2KVWTiF875n7D46z951wdm6lV6ovffyRDf4dmz96A2eO31H1APchNlIcy85MLdLRFzzKje9nSI758y2iPNUjjJw21DWM0hD3XhDxXoY6+8WevW5o+zgE3kZV5+c18OdSQ16ee4U74ig+A2WmQRLR+EECQusDo5kads5cqsN7NuDzP+7Ttkv2T4NIKbAZbsYE/c0mzlK0a62osXoi1axpC9PLVIVzkJyCmNU4a68T0wnwlhocvW2A3/RpIgZoaIsF90tjnsz8gOtljATqspkpF1Ic+4iyWc1HJ9rBtBbQp1Mrjkg==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Sixth Five Year Plan", 
		"option_b": "Eighth Five Year Plan", 
		"option_c": "Ninth Five Year Plan", 
		"option_d": "Tenth Five Year Plan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130121", 
		"question": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UGWwj3hcT6NHmQM24QrT/LAPMkIjyzA+6CZ+Pq25h1Ml+MiRts+n/Fq+X+8kRPjrtL7I2LY30/cNov7t+Kwve3y38BPslKk5R99psdcPEA2Dy/c9HPM75SwDzAFFHxczzwCHVikT2Wnn1Er4av5meHWol38hAhg4tsoMcuNdKRzamH4UK2xjqMiDujTbtrA1mcsY6u4k2droExtMHNoibJ9eD8neGRauUirlxuw5aFrpLdRi48cw==", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UGWwj3hcT6NHmQM24QrT+KXLdmf3X2V6LGLv7735JjJlDJg15ssnfVs6Dz40BPm6cb7ICXcSwAe8t/xNGH2e35wzFENcBBmZR78p8ReedTjAmlccfeYPdgzWKVI0D0Jzj9An93gSKWhXIWpYy1/DO0Rts1zBBygoZq6s0oL5vfyryS/Ej1igOU2XfRXLx2FlGNpoLo6k2Y4IN4p8iepD7Pufvrk/3d5NsPIglCr5RwYli015wB/Tk9Ecu8aRxM9PeQYF3gJSzjMwFd/MXww2Zsho8mT2x09RxFjZZYdsFx2p2kvTw0f8hsEzq5qkFO09RsUxaYerS21yjz6UE3NW4qa41kviEw4QCJPFdxl26PDuy+5YjhYj6typzzavrFMGc=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130122", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kSnm9otgUxf/wPm/IWSQB20EoXOGErNxYjHgVbfLeuy+wJlyKFGMzVJ1sneGp6Dz9lcK0Oo+BoBQf2L+c62Cmr81nWc0", 
		"answer": "24G9ZoX7kT/j4YBgaxvz173POWreQTYk82R7BkFveEaQjNEQaS0=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UQXh/8hbWtZTuCTjJG6j+QV7c0cX+jVarAZ/n3xoJiZ0iIn1x+5jbJpeX0+EYNg6FV7s6PdTBDfYp/wcSIl+35x35MNoZTk5R67ZRffbREyT6scNGbFPZn3S6PJU/1ZC20EnU0gzDFyn1aoYS18CP7Q9MjyFUmnoI4/cQ9MpCMmaeF7V+5lAWK1XWWCLprEFjZusjo6kCUqYcuvMOK8TrS8/z8iLjW89EFbQVbvMZ4cVSrg6BJ+SQ8EcG5eABE5+3eZhThKT6qKQld6t/i2HBo1IY6Hx3ZAETgl+vo2b5E03aLcZc=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Eighth Five Year Plan", 
		"option_b": "Ninth Five Year Plan", 
		"option_c": "Tenth Five Year Plan", 
		"option_d": "Eleventh Five Year Plan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130123", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut5EoV17GwPPrPSv2CnQU40aGU7E0QH3iWufHY/32yIR4PVnJjFxp+3XTr7Hl5VZPjrsb/YaaMDIRd4ZqiN2Gwe35wzFHPNRHn8B94toLdPEA5TOpfdXVYPttwWCPKlyvJcRDLketRXx96KpCZPaS+C4=", 
		"answer": "2+foOMO+gU6oCFwvluFsMFIopOHExtLJQQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UGWwj3hcT6NHmQM24QrT/LAPMkIjyzA+6CY+zswpJ1Z13JnlJ8/H/Aqqbx+UdPnKBS75rfcjtDbI5sx9eH3v7+ynYBMsFWk4Nn6I4KbvEAzS7tYNzeYO58x2OFZ0Hibi+0Cnc0kj7EiXkWp4X74S++FPM5xBwzmMd97scyM9qGmZyb4V74gwuS1HqCQa4kEF2UsMro/0zcqIMqu8ieonLP/PG5ivfH9dAfawle/4l5I0+0kugI/zgxUt24fAdZ8OiQclHuNCexZxoSudjzw2Ypw4EmU2Y5/RwGhZFZddR7mtjlsD41KcRrATb6s0tWwoZoRlvWdbO8kG3q6FQxdn9rY4ViuG0mpAyJOl1qgykqchuruPfodFlO/KGqTzpX", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "1997-2002", 
		"option_b": "2002-07", 
		"option_c": "2007-12", 
		"option_d": "2012-17", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130124", 
		"question": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UQXh/8hfz2OG7UQ3Ye43aNUbFxcWLmFJj9UdLB9qhOGGO2zU90smTHqrb1t0EanalXqYeRcy0Oe5gvyd6Nl+DyyXBPN4Rmv6JORMZ2ops6EZgdUcil", 
		"answer": "27S/epjwxBX+4pchXl7i1/L7IGjECm0f4ei3A3r5rz+DTqPEtXzUe3k=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UQXh/8hf76O3/VEWcV43aXQeNnZGPiQKLFd63xx9dzKFOamVJ19TbHpLf59EYDm71J6ILfYDAMep5s3NmG2aTDzHhSc8dUipJ95ZkXPONB332oesLSM/dhwGuEZ1H/JyytCHlygHHEn25XpMOy+yS0Wd8kjFU3mI9548s5fMWKy6mfqF2tlAWK3WiYRrokAVuOsNzkq0KSpMIrocSApD7a4PG5nvfe9c0fawsSu4NyYlW41cGiXUrKFpIdQ19uroCNH4c=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "ag,ri,cu,lt,u,ra,l pr,od,uc,ti,on", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130125", 
		"question": "2523f9H33hz5t5UyWxHgzOn2L2LeBCIQpG2KUbZ4ZGTxUefKa+HuiZVjKF2NiEk793XJrar9/lBPiLpU/pqXMCMAfYR9zNmH0KTjyzFVO8MEroV88JJfTPhBwmKReoWbB/tgy3yBM0DjJzywFHx7jTzThGgWlI3ptQ61V8gywQY3hcd+4sc4fMSa2r2B4VmhugjRnEmQQa5hAhSLoNyp5wOVroE3uMie8TPV8LTpj+rQ+N8YawZV/5ZwdF6uq6ZduBoqXsW7fBdYsenRb0HrISu3MhwU98yj0Ht7hoUlUms1+F9DmpNZcNRglIT9l6wV9cigmwLUekKcGg4=", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UQXh/8he/6NmTXDWsLpnvDRqt1ZDHzRq7NfOTqwI14KVvJjFxp+3XTr7Hl5VZPjKdO5YrfdycNe5lu3NXJ2vH70HhHMsVBjoV2pJgacvFGxSm+NNLUMr56xmvAIkb/aTawHTBWjXHQhW9CrZGy+yD7UdcnzBorm4J2+YR8Ndmcy62S+0S2gUaE03SVCK5hEkGLvNqxpwOdroZ4p8yEojvV87Trj+rS/J4CbAtdsoNsLxu9kLoA+z80Rd2mbV9P4+3GZFqtJzqsMBoVucjsw3hthoEmU30m/R1TloYWds8z2Y7hrjM8M41vFjy0rElJxNR5RweXeq6x32ak1F02ZjoqdZp/syw2qU+dJEdx2mqVQSlV1JRkvtYYlg1vdHtBiHOgjz6FlWOOf4f2+Ynygqj2r6sj9a8oK0CMdVnARoIOcaCMZ2V9xfqPBKhbc5loBSfvOttu+SH6KJea2DxN1dgyIX7p8znbHqDeUbfcK380Aw/sSL30gQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130126", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut5EoV17GwPPrPSvgD2Mf43mKQLBgMHjtV6vXaui+zphnIk6HjFV49zbUpqP/5V4cz6FVqZqXdWITcophxtmH0KTn1n5CNtVXxcJNviyXwlTDy4ZhwP713abq", 
		"answer": "2+foOMO+gU6oCFwvluFsMFIopOHExtLJQQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UGWwj3hcT6NHmQM24QrT/LAPMkIjyzA+6CY+zswpJ1Z13JnVJt/WLHr+X9+F4Kgbwb65ffeSwXe4x9ycSA2eO3w35XNtRKm45x4doNefJP3jC+NN3VNPEu2maFZ1X8ZjezDX5z1CHEhX9Tu5D7wS+yR5okyBw0gsdq6MszO9mWw62XqFmwg0aR1XyfQbttElWXtsvo5EXcp403sY2KviTe5vr4lPvWsNcFIgxAtpB2bVz8k60f/SY3QcWxZgYL/vHEYlvgJTvjJgAZuc7txWF7z4wuHWwy8hZFi4ZYdoBmwpHotSgxK8RlG3O1pQRSwodzSgWVca76TAvelPsekZoM5SqS1xwhQA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "1997-2002", 
		"option_b": "2002-07", 
		"option_c": "2007-12", 
		"option_d": "2012-17", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130127", 
		"question": "2523f9H33hz5t4IvXRqywvLpMHneAmwSpj+QR7Nkf2P3FLTNbeTxhJJyKFKGgFJ4snLDtaD8+EMCiqZPqY+ccy0ReoJhz5Cd2KTjzHQBB8NKjogy1JYecqt8wmztUdrTIfBty33AN1DyazC+RGNxhiffiXkWrIa3/DG+RsN3/Btg1q51/dozKtKMmamQ60KtiBKD3nKdQal9UVWXsY68+UKSs5I5p8iDsiubyPqq2srW9MsIZxsSvIltcU6sg6EG9moEX5z0WABE/OvEZEetJS6lLg0U/MX3lmF9z44gR2gg/RBIwoxQItJ2xZfxrjE1LI9s5wWQ0tPRBRjVYShXIbSw", 
		"answer": "25S0ZNH811n+/4BgUxz90/i9nRQLEAOvQrYd8yxhqAOnaw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UQXh/8hfT7MGXECmQYpnvDVax7dDHkW7HHfOP/x5R0Z12azVo78XnUraDi5EcAga0b5ojfYy0Ad4QizdOG2ev6zXIBN8NSn4x99JcacuAA7iTtcdrTIfBtx2CHZ1XlZTW0BzBnkSPAg39T6Ie++S6tUcgujFU7m5dq4t41MtDf2KuQ51i2kgeA1XeYXKQkEFqd9dq66k2PsIMqsMOOqH6b5vH9j/va/tlLYQdArZNvd1KzmeRJ+SQ8EdimZx9E5e3eZhToJi6qJAcY99+jxHF6yZc7Xmx04QtPjopMY9R62Zao/DU/MMkqEjysplZOxpp/WleVZri5xG33oFQxNX8lZIhhtSMy4QqSPl1slWWRSSJF1IZk7JAKgBd3fGZOnXTsh3+KjmHPdZ3g55XvjP714L5x/bQzIQMf6BugKGepnzPWC2qqxRwt", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 4", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130128", 
		"question": "24W3e4WzgECzpsUyVxj91/DseSvWFnAFq3qREqZ3f3/sWa7BLv/7z5hjKk/Jml5p9zbSrOXy8hMDiqwb65ffZyoKfYMvx9bJw+zyhHdOP8pLjYl849oQbvNBwi7yNhdXEWE1cHENyPL4+62AtrM=", 
		"answer": "26asaYX2wlvtAY6kCI7NFGKCG6dLgyFi", 
		"explanation": "25y2KIX71Fnr8ZElQBPz0fW/Om2QF2oU4y7aC/I0dXLsWqjPZ+6+25J3KE6Enhc75n7D45H1+UcHz5hX6IDfYicAcYxhwcqM06TjzHBVc9VQm5R399oIc+FMyH29eNXCYP8u3meWKFHxa3mvC3xx1DjYym9GrYKp/SK6UNM5x1U0g5Vs5c0ufNKc1qac5US7xhSH2nSDRa4kJVyQpo6740qatMI5tsaDviXX8fD+n/yT5NYOIgFfr4ltd1qylK1J9yx4Vc23bRxf4+XcaE7oJGizKAIU+tKj33pg0osoSWAi8QwGg41SItR709jlvyY5KcgqBTKot01DzoR9Sx6Zev231ij39FQrcDosapxoriM4pAGIOxR3lCuYXiVHnY5svtUamgpscGZD3HHyjSifiCcpMBLlh0C63ewzL0qN0Am9", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "centre", 
		"option_b": "states", 
		"option_c": "private sector", 
		"option_d": "World Bank", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130129", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+zxhz48sUzRh/mwLDzMH3VDyIcrHGKRqxmcXPvUefWb//5zINiZ1qAn0hvsn/IqrH59kcKi/cZNbjsQ9c5ACgG6f/d5f/+Og==", 
		"answer": "24G9ZoX7kSnm9otgQhvgzPL7d5EZvSviVAqGJKFYMtAQzsU=", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX2nBXv4YAsEhP9y/TrOnnRAW4U42uCQKRxZGKjQ6LQa633x4NjKFicjl5/snDJseXk/1ZPiaFJ+prfZCsOe8tr3cKA2eO30HlEc/JBlJR6pLwWavEA9TisZpTrLP9gjn6FNUz/Y3n1ViAkxnyG3TUWnIuy5me6RMolzxQxnsd55MU5OJeL1uiW5kW5iAWHnG+ZTf1hF1Kcttqh/UaSpZEr9cKL8SLX9fr3k/bUsNwSIhtXq5J2bVz8hLgM+yM+WMv0aRxPsenVYEf4MimhKwtd7crx0XF91cIoSSkg/BoGkZdXdsUz2p3yuT58f8xmHDS0qkpHh5B5SRKae6211WbwoFA5c3U5cZktqyQhqU+TPUB9lWaZX26YTbvUfXGoniPJtM9Y7zAy", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Eighth Plan Period", 
		"option_b": "Ninth Plan Period", 
		"option_c": "Tenth Plan period", 
		"option_d": "Eleventh Plan Period", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130130", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+zxhj5t5EoV170zO/sISviBnEEr2vDdLF1fXT0W7XJLsnxyoJ8IlKdzRNJ1FKP46z+40EAi71Y7IrAMvSD7T6CjXD4NOc9o5Dv8tg=", 
		"answer": "y+XpOFIUCEV+4/cxtbqXNvjpBRY=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH12Av548USVw3nyem/E3nRDmcGrG2IEod7c2TuUanWLqXM77M4Z0uInhty/GLUrKHl9FYLz6FVqZqXdWIae4p9iILZhrS3xWIBI8dWjsB94toLdPEA6TGoYtHVNPYu6GeWIgXJYjivREB4lT+WvnRT6LGd0We6XdcyxFUmmcd948A9MtSamamQ60KtiBKD3nKdQal9XRSNp8+m+FOdsoc2ttTB8TPV8LTpn+rV/8wGYwZRusZ+cEi5hLsE/SQsEcG6KBVE5+HCb1noLjzjIwsN+Nn323Fn0pFpX3B05xpSlopYZYB+05n3qSAxPcFvVSe7sUNF04c8XhmSNLC33mHw70c2e31rap95vyI4pBzeJ8usHA3jof3wnaEd/4r28g==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": 2005, 
		"option_b": 2008, 
		"option_c": 2010, 
		"option_d": 2012, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130131", 
		"question": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UQXh/8hfz7OnvEBmZRp3aFVKZmdX/3XabOLun735J9KEyEiFVvsmXSsaTk8lQGirsb64+MdSZDcYUv39iA1Oy3wnBCJ5kGnY63xCqfOHeHsCfor6SEkA==", 
		"answer": "24asaYX2wlni9pMlEhr7w/v6J2LeBCIBrGuGXLd9cX2jVanGLu7xx4RlNV2Ag09osGor1aDNwWcIpUnFSnUbsog=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UQXh/8gu6/NG/fE3YYrHHDXaU0dHjlUqLQa+PqwJZ9Z1iMm153/WbLpqvkt0AbnalP7ImWdTFDaYp8iNSb3vLyyjFDKoZQkoUy9p8cc/NOxSmke9qbNPZv2i6TM0TkYir9FH9nhzTFmTxAqZGi/Cm8FMo41BA8go554Yg9MtPf2qed+1mqhw+MyGjRfLVtAhSYpd665EKfqMI5vMCItXLP+7Ttm/Hf/8xLZg1Euopwc1a5mbxJ6CY5X9v0fB0L5ezVIUf9JSuqIQceucXm03B6hoMnWSk3/B5KjoZYZcVglp7lvzc0f89zVTa7oEwA1IB9SxLaNK2q32Xr9Fwxcjomapho/CQ7ogOJO11onyudQigRgIF5+dUNkAAjen1Pi2LowLOqyr/LuYChOxLvsugnN6U=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Political party in power", 
		"option_b": "Varying literacy rates", 
		"option_c": "States have differing potential and constraints", 
		"option_d": "Availability of natural resources", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130132", 
		"question": "2523f9H33hz5t5EoV172zPv5MHnVDXYYonPDVqZidX3sRKrHYPm+2oNjJkiMikI78HPIpqP54xMcm6lP7J3ATCxSPqprzMKMxPfy1zFSJ8dQn81h9J8cdfJJz32kZ8fOJe0u8mDSZ2T8azaqFzB3gSLChXFfsoa/tTe0WNM02RgznY526vQyb5e80amd5ki0jxyHzzuDTa5rBEaasN3o6UKPpYZ4usPNvzfe8Oe5pvaHsO4ZbQVdq4NsI1izmrgM7CMsWN6xKBRO9eHCYFjkMyXh37K1IgZz9ZekBI1xPjwclQ==", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH32B/s8pclXAr7xPG/MW7GBm4es3KGXLc0Y2XxVbPHafS+y4V4KVuazVZu/mLPs6n1t1EKga1d4JqMMDYMPph7ycSMxKTV3TFAN8JWn5Nh7ZQYPOdUzSmoOcfLJf1nyGeDZ0zjdCy4Fzw0kT/XiHBfpoT79jKoQNU6yQ83ksdo4sQ1P86S2KOa5kr0xgeM2DuSQLxqH1GVvNSh5UTcsocrutifsjfItPb4if3XsNEFIgRdvIdzI1W5kqwatGosWcGnKBNb4fbfYFflYC6sNBoY69ij1HVlx4wqWG109RFCwpFTZcl82JnosCtwK8xjGTyopkAAw5FqWhuZZLC93nykwVE7fG4iaoRssCEs7U+VPBRuiGSRQzhUh8Bj+9EVgQx6PWxPkWblljafiXOKPJXm74XuhOT5s7Qj864oJ0bAJkjZQogPJafPZ2ZxwuCeG6McPI9zHi/nMZUp7jbuNJ7U0CwZ09YtKmSlBT1sQCE3mDpbjJqh+z4T/g==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130133", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iOSB0qTH5zFMPMhNjo9g4Z5ff/FO2C+seJTWKfBn3XqSLkDjIHmtC3x9lyiWg3JfvIq64S6tUcl3xAAgn4l/rfw5MsOXmZif6UP4ugi+0kmUSa5rHxTRh4fyq3eT4IM0vMqD8T/S+v3qjurKsN8IdgFdsZU/dFKon+gH+T4xXsa1ZFJb/eXeb13jJ2ikKA8R6olmLqQF/WWvAkpTZtMLjDsU", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UQXh/8hfvwNn7DBmZRrHHDU699d3/qWqCCbejw3YVwKxyEhFVy4WLUqqDjsBMfgKRS6pffeSwKaoJu3Nmf0ve303hVO4ZKm5R765QecLRQwDyjet3VJ75pwW+MNAXyfnmwC359gD7Eg3JR6Jez8C6pFMolzxIgk5Rrrfw0NcTf2LiD+kK5hQ7C3XKcTbkkBVvZsMC7/lGZ4JYwtNnNvDvV/eftiOGT8d0fawdcrMZoZkm516EHuDkhX8v0fxtf+aTEaVGtIjqsJgoY64vn02Jsyo05UGw64F9HhYZYZsEz2Y3wsDs+OskqFyr6t0xFh4RwXhnUR9/k+HObuD+pou+gvbhbtw==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is NOT the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130134", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut5Y0VxvgzPP4dWjfDm8Yt2uGV7A0Y2XiRrOCb+H3zpl4KVvJq1Jt9zb/pqTit2MDjqZIqZmWZCpDe4hgxt+E3ue31nRHPNRJid8wmueX9PJSn8LF7As6XJJUJw==", 
		"answer": "25uxZoX7kSnm9otgQhvgzPL7dwZz0uePoUmuYSVW00tDMWQ=", 
		"explanation": "24asbZTh2Bftt4YvXxP70en6MHiQFGcDpj+GQbd1cn3qR6/Haq3qxtdwK1WOgxtd+2DD45z19kFPv6Ra553fZysXdstqy9+H2On+xzFTNsBLiI1hpIkLfeZUxTOqNNLJL/Mu2maFZ2v5aS21REB4lT+WmnlEoYy/tW/qDYNgjUdixtUxrfw0OcSamauc5UCxkhKH2WjRWLFlCFGd9c/o6FGVtIs7tMHNoz3X8bTwlLja/soOZRpTq49xZBu5lKcH9ycxUoi4YRBO4+XcaE7sNCGsKU4Q/Mrww2Zs1cIoU2105wtUg5dTZclwlojovTw+NsNtVSe140VDz515SRLWZ6irxGnt7lQ9eX9rZIRp/C80rQ6SK1F62myOQztFnMJYonnKmweESWZfqkG7Tdbh", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Eighth Plan Period", 
		"option_b": "Ninth Plan period", 
		"option_c": "Tenth Plan Period", 
		"option_d": "Eleventh Plan Period", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130135", 
		"question": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UGWwj3hcT6NHmQM24QrT+LU7A0cnTmWufBb+HyzJMxJhy2smREzUn5nJqw518Ogeovqo983/n8k8JE4PAcbdxF", 
		"answer": "26e9bp7h3Fn6+4QuEKPl9ztTLfw/SFc1Kup68qM=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UGWwj3hcT6NHmQM24QrT+GU7F6dXWjQK/HLuDxx556Ik7Jgl078zb64bf18VwdguhL5Y+RTGBDep5qiMSGl+3j1zFEPtZMm5N799oQcrRJwim/e9DOI/dgyS6TM1flZC2oFnF41DLei3JRrZD79Cm/FMo4zBwxj8dq6M4zLtqMmbqS/EW9lEaW1HqfCLtrEkGKvMCvq1CTrIc0rI2Cv3LJ8ef2j+rQ9Z4KbgRdvIdralSy15wB8Tl4UNikeh1K8uyQYF3gJSzjMwFd9MTn02Znz5gsHXk49RFIi41RItBh15vwtTE1LI1rGzf6okhJwJo8Sx+Tef2v2XzsoFEme3smbIktuS46rwCRIVc+mWSSSCVFnY9l7ZKaLM/qFqyuaVDILmh0swti", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "re,fo,rm p,l,an", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130136", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q440lEir3y+n3dU3ZFWdRmnqCQONEfHDtFLPQd63qxtdjIlqGn1Y74nrHrav5+VRQs6YKqauSYCoCbYJ1zdTJ2uv5zWVOIcdGloUy8JsNe/FU332ReoabBvFt232FIwX/aXmyEWR3mzzTmTxZvoaptSiuQNY22QZyqokrrekwNdCR3KzT60i2khSD0DucQbNtAkCLvMu7q3+S9MILsNnNpCKb5+D8n+ra/tlLYQdfso9rd165hOgG9moqVM67eh9Ys3UF3n7IULXL8gnJuhcuATQ=", 
		"answer": "25S0ZNH811n+/4BgUxz90/i9nRQLEAOvQrYd8yxhqAOnaw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UQXh/8hejxMW7CF20eqD+CEqB7fWHxUa/HYP7335IxJkyZn1R68X6Gt6qw5VYJgLpW4ICYMDYLe8t/xNGH2e35wzFRIclHn5NhpLMLPPFN3DWsZ93BJfouw2GOLlH/dTi/CHU0gDDEjXlCu8O9+jX7Rt8k1Rkmhcp3/8E5MsOa3eiD5Ey2iA+M2zfRTrJnBEecsY6n5QOTtZY7usCIonLU4vHr2vfG5NIKexse/4dzalyykqxJ+y82Rdq1ZFJG+OrZckD/KS2wZxoSuc/mwHFlyZIkWGcgtBhJg49FLoBy2JykuSEkPs9mHCCypkAA1IB5WgWferr402fp7VwrYX8udsp5s20xswaKLRRulWeVTzURhoVt8cIUhkRXdWZT3Hv1jiuChmSMeYfm78D9lfjir7hg+uMmIEyFMRzMWc0Za7vBKWR3ivmXDKhSOpFgVyfgO9At6DDvJZiRzCpN0dckb3bk9yWMnNn0O2y2uobgzG7T/pqIFLpWuyvhGPdxcdw=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130137", 
		"question": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UQXh/8hfTxPH/ZAnYUpz+QRqJgdTzvUbHHYq3zxpl4M1ObjFl39zbSorf38kccz7xUqZ6Nfy8Mao4v39iA1Oy3y3NLNsVQk5Z3u6YRLbRjwzC9ccDSNPd4yy6GIkH1dTixDWN51A3Y2Dx0p5ev+ir2Qcp30BkzmIlx4898ANnMmZmG6UGxkh/C33SfXK9rHRSlu5roykCfr5c2ocyPuD7S4O27HWpP6aTteZNurzqamYJgVQ==", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kU2ou//Q2AbZiGVbdoMovrUDhg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UQXh/8hfTxIXnfB3cSpnvDQbd1ZHSuWKLUa+G+xJh/LkiGn1p5/nOGt6Ti8FYbnOhM4JqXMDYLe8tr3dGFl/Ti1mFOIMMElYYy4ZQefvhJwjrtdtvPNPFjg3uQZ1X8ZjezDX5z1DDYjjxTpou6+ySyWt13wRYxmZJ2+ck+NduWzbHTylT4lQOWyHKfT/13AVGavMih6AOIoZA/sNme8TPPtODxn7jA5N8fZ0heupB6bxf8g6AMuDo0UMb0aRtG9OCQdVutJSWzKBkY64vwwnV9w5FpSWZ04B5PjoxEItR705H2/DY1KchmGiO3pkpUh4doTRaCcbqx1Xuk9102eX9rZIZ+s20lswCRJ0B3lGzcSz5UlZRu7JAYlgdsaGFUnXTpjjafmSWOcpej/5L9i/vgoatm/KA+aUiOdV3bXoQZc7rOICdmwuaICOZbPJ5rBGBGxj8Qi41Sl7sUaZqX7TKI", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 3", 
		"option_b": "2 and 4", 
		"option_c": "3 and 4", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130138", 
		"question": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UQXh/8hfjyJWPREGsCpnvDRqtxMH/mUaOCaOLsiZF9IkSAj1J3+2Lf46z+t0MDjqZV4ICYMAEMc4ZqxsTJ2Oq30HlEc9VQm5R36Z8RaLbccP73/2Jh2YC0jlM28a77", 
		"answer": "24GKXbSxHm4A89/yf9ZfF9Op1Z8h7g==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UQXh/8he/6NmTXDWsLpnvDRqtxMHjtQLXLbezqzNdwKVjJn1pr+3LKuuXz/1IBiKFV7s6RcTYWbI4vx9bJ0uf4yn5MOsUI2pN955MecLgAzTOpNMDeI/ZgwWKPIEzzZjX9CHF6kCLVi2xTu8OS+2epUcknzxshk8s45Nx8Ndmb3K2XqEi1lg6Dz3KLTbkkBVyc9cCt6EaPs4ssrI2LviCb8vj8gvHR/NtLcgRTsYh2bVz8lrgZ6iU5UsCxe1J/+eGQcVjsLmiiLgMY/Yv32TRtw5IoT3108g1Jj8NEa8d60tSkszw1ct5jDzb3pU1U1Nl9UxvWZ6mq0Xzh51w6Zjoqa44tvSk6sRvcKVB/in+VWikRmYVq7cULkBcjaWdBiDbjjSqHhCWdeYDz5I74xe32prxg5qoxLE2ZdUjXFogRYKHHLml1iuqTDKpQNpFgEjGmPNsqvDbpMJmGyywD2c0pKmSnwCKQgY30KXWovJP6hpRzGr4COtTBqdu4vFXEeC7gKniBdYvgVkj9Tnf9kxpsuh0p0WER7GjNG51y8CMZjT6xR0AknTf0ZXGojLsc+IedcJsj0PCs3D4cl/d5i5L42l0oSES6gXZEvMSIRkhHjVHAEcERzQcpTLcIBpXE/36ClHjTTm9NXde2AKyRzC9Jzur/iSF7sIJOU4CLNBDZg9Iv3A79QelxUCfZrYjtNbwlBmUiuqF+3+qpo4qverOhIm0rYRmyGftR9tVDbRFyHQLYCydKILmgUt0MROxKxHTElAIISHkJFVbN9aYBUwPqo8qIb2SeZqcZHFPha7ILFMf2SQfKO+eg2j/HC7qSgQWbn8v3S51338Rl1OD6XtS7", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "TRUE", 
		"option_b": "FALSE", 
		"option_c": "Partially True", 
		"option_d": "Partially False", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130139", 
		"question": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UQXh/8hfvwNn7DBmZRrHHDXbZgc37uUbSCfOzqwZJjZ0iBjFU7+GPVt+X/4kcDjrFIqZqQMDIRcYZg3NXJwOz+x3kBPMROn4Nm7YwaI7aioSdhmntSRr/mEAbH01XQ", 
		"answer": "24e9e4T/xQqn+JcpVxDmxOn2OmWSmJQkPUBvUyp78Bp2oZTeJA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UQXh/8hejxMW7CFGcftz+CErB9d3/qUq7Bb+PqiYR5LlqdzVJ1sn/SsOXx50MdgKlY4cLfYDAKcZlm3NmT3urwhH5UJ8VLl4VhpJUJeeYA2C+scN3PKfFgz2LALkvgci3wC2J9kT/Cj3gWp5av+SaiR5oV2VU3m4Vq7Ms1MtDf2OiB7V6tihKRkXSDQbhqBVGd9d28+UKIpYUh+Y2ZuTeb5Pj4lLjS+dMOZkhGsMZ6bUipha1J7CI5RYigYBcL8OjcblfsNCGsKU4S/4vx02dm05AqWHp04A1HjJBaY9R20tjtsiY/f8BvFD2zrUNG0pg8XhmSNLS1wGnn9FMqeTokcJ5usyAwsk+oIF1t2mqMXD5elYNjvtkXgwtva2pE3GXlliuCjmLPf5/m6pK8hOb04LRm87AyO0CCOVmYQowOYrbUNCdmwuiPTadYN41iBDHjOZUl+SC5M5mX1jZA1dovIXjq/SnZkcX0NWm/vZX8nZRfAP8QJN7I5t+ytBzGIS7uM3jTY83yUAv5SnLskxt2slgqzmEC7XHXHZt88D5NnGfwT0tnhzTpYnvhmbAc64GGdosn2vvrnSEAnfdxmZL0lBk5UQG3gm9Ot4qLTlAPylvXEt5H1gg6BLETVILZ82PWmHPCTnAUP83+AKaJxiBB1OSxiHRzu4NOXIKaI1nLmNEszRSlEr1uXHPlp5Ptff8aBHcl/rdjw+Om996zcLOlL3E/bhb3UOJJ8pZFKDZzGBidETZObqunQpQRT6Bb3TXYkhRdS2taSFXe8q0GSQW+o8vGLmvXbrQYTgrtI7YLG8/2TUKPIfmsiDXPALqfgU6oWkogXSnRYaQf5Anjao3gIR2wiiQk+M/hclBYR4wCMjPydmK1rLeaSwk8PyggPo9LdVfYTh4wlTKDLvduma4BZBE7RLvrWUUaghhCnirXAkEFs0MQS7ekQkYzI6dCYE8ejTq6A6VfSB3EgTMIglPcyy/8O/VdNEQmdXCAz0Xu24Zumr/4l4+NA8D7bbIdkoEKLrMbQpXEX1gVjvr+6u/zUW03Ai1jJv2IUfTUok76DojksMzd11lY2v4HMB8vLTzLh57N+TVjbWeZfb/wcVjUZbVnfSg70Bk=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Political consensus", 
		"option_b": "Funds utilization", 
		"option_c": "Results-orientation", 
		"option_d": "Public accountability", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130140", 
		"question": "24GwbdHHxhzm8ZEoEjj70/i/DG7RESIhr36NErBxZDHtVbPLYeP/xdd8KFKAmVRp83TKpuXk9kEIirxIqY+cYi0Qbctnx8fJ2uX53TFDIclFnsBz9p8eb6sCcCiJMhl0wp37Kf4G6Lj6YQ==", 
		"answer": "yOTzEUiiDlspif57GmI9j3Lw", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHHxhzm8ZEoEi7+xPO/On7ED2sfpnvDXKJgeX7tVauCY+LwwIN+NV2LgV475nfUpKDk5BMOjLpU+p3fIXNDfJlgydTJ1vbyxWIBOshHlpV27ZQYPPNSwyq5fJibMPF4y3yUPgmwYj2oB3FgnT7YxjxTvID5iJzzAwAcr9Bal/38RrnmrA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": 11, 
		"option_b": 10, 
		"option_c": 8, 
		"option_d": 12, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130141", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxRj48IA0EhH0hfv2O2reAGsQrz+KXKB4ZWLqW6mCeeztiZ5/JFCciV5/sn/I45Hn8l8Jm6Ab2YKefmIOcYVm3N+b1ub7wTFVMtRDn5Rhu9hV6oBCPA2HV8WjNFPUzqS7", 
		"answer": "24WqZ4f61RDk8MUhUR331u6/IWSQAWMfqHaNVeNyf2OjDfeHLsTwzZ5wKRyBgk5o937Jr6HjtTV7Hk6eIqegCsEiXt8QuBM=", 
		"explanation": "24WqZ4f61RDk8MUiUxD5zPP4dWrTAGcCsD+XXeMtIDSjXKjXfej2xpt1NByejEg78zbytKD88UcHz5hX6IDffS0Nd59g2tGL2+G30HBTNMNQ2oZ99toZdfpBwj6kddibKfBtwnuTLkr+JduEbxZmsXZsjCPTXulyA64=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Providing access to banking for 85% Indian households", 
		"option_b": "Providing access to banking for 90% Indian households", 
		"option_c": "Providing access to banking for 95% Indian households", 
		"option_d": "Providing access to banking for 75% Indian households", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130142", 
		"question": "24GwbdHHxhzm8ZEoEi7+xPO/IWrCBGcFpnvDU600dXLsWqjPZ+6+zoV+MEiBzUl65nOGrKOw/1wYz6Va55ffYCcRfY5h3NGO0qbl7yyEwXT302YkfOsf/RMO", 
		"answer": "2+34eJTh0hzk48fwO3E0kwErjaggffub3yeG", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHHxhzm8ZEoEjj70/i/DG7RESIhr36NErd1YnbmQKLGLuzwiZZnIk6Iil4783jItqT8t1YMgKZU5IecMCURcZx7wJCb1vDyhH5Hc54B2EPsWcGVH5vmo5opOVl4Wmg=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "8 percent", 
		"option_b": "75 percent", 
		"option_c": "85 percent", 
		"option_d": "7 percent", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130143", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrv9JEvQF7lxO6/IWrCBGcFpnvDRqw0d2PsQ+fDeq2vmdIxN1mbzVp1/GPL46Hl5VoBiOhP4YvfRDUGco17wJCv3vLyhEhEMtQEqoxz6toPeeZJwznyNsYX8P7VQO2AQYO2pf7hRxY=", 
		"answer": "25i5ZoT10Br+4pcpXBmw7dn9Fe49uf83PduYbOiHrA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHHxhzm8ZEoEi7+xPO/Jm7EQ2NRt36RVaZgMHziWrLEb+7q3IV4KVvJikl05WLO47fx41ZPgK4buN7aMDIGbMt2zdGblQU2LbDOXxU4YL27ZGOVdVE=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Agriculture", 
		"option_b": "Manufacturing", 
		"option_c": "Services", 
		"option_d": "Infrastructure", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130144", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17/yvP2IWTCAmAdpj+XU7FzdWWjUqjQLv3x35JjM0XJn15/53XSqqr+t0YBi61JqZqXdWI3aY5jzsSBl8L+0nQBCsNFiMBC6JsRI8hOnX34NMTeMv1rwHqBIECwdza0CmRn1A3Y2DwH+MOr8DW4UdQjwRI31pd35MYoL5ej1/vTuRj4lgOQ336fXLxjFBSJusem/1DcnIxs9Z/d8SLe5vf8lOzS99tLcgdbsZJsIRfKFjHKN++BeZQIokKUbA4=", 
		"answer": "25q2ZIizg1uwV+m/y6r0/hG+btiKc2Mw", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHHxhzm8ZEoEi7+xPO/NGLdBmZRt3DDQKZwZXLmFLfNeOjs3Y4xNV2dhFQ78G+G8vWw51YdjK1V/Y+YdWITcYJh3MPJ1Ov61HBTNsIEjo8y9Igaav1P2S7tccfPKfNv2muTZdBdmf/UF1OMD+knN8GL44I=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "Only 3", 
		"option_c": "Only 2", 
		"option_d": "Only 1", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130145", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwhLj+4lgVhvkwPHwJWbVDXZRt36RVaZgMGbiR+fNe/nywJl0IxyAgxtv+nOGl7L1+1Ubh+h94JiaMBsGf5kv+NyI2bvLyiABENRBm5R3pM9PPPlJwDGke9qbLvt5jmCPKQj2ZiuwRHp7liKWtnIE6KC+5zOyUsN30x47motrrcc6fILPmaWa5EGxiQjCzH6eWLFhUWiX5o6c+UKVrsJp9c6fviDetO32j+zbsN8FbB1Ts4pmI2eyw+gs9jktQ830ZRtF+OnFbBT+KyGvKx1d/8TxlnVlysI6XmE7+xMGhZFXZtVywp33/km1I0W0rjpI0lHqMqXtu3I=", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHHxhzm8ZEoEi7+xPO/NGLdBmZRt3DDUbFxcWXmFPKSLuD3xZt4KFLJg15ssnjJrej29kECz6JU653fcSwHPohq2sSA0f23xX8BNtdRk5Zz6J8RaLRO2TCvccabKfAu3WWJK0njJYSCrFKnbHXQdjfums+/OM4=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 3", 
		"option_b": "2 and 4", 
		"option_c": "1 and 2", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130146", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz3Bzr+cU5Vx/g1r3wMyvDAGoerHOKXKQ0dHjnFLPKa63K3pJ9IUiBzWt383iGt6Ti8FYbz6pCqdzPIXVcPBYusbCFFB3rMj8lhommgCs=", 
		"answer": "zgkQ1meMHQg2MoWuRaRjLDQ=", 
		"explanation": "25y2a4P20Arj+YJgXxvzy73mMGrCECIepT+QUat7f33qWqCCeuK+ntdmJk/JjBtP5XPKpbH4t2MDjqYb7IqKcyMXd4RhiN2G2e3jy2NAMcpB2pRz9p0aaLYsnSheTpV2yY+Ci1aWAd+w", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": 5, 
		"option_b": 6, 
		"option_c": 7, 
		"option_d": 8, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130147", 
		"question": "24GwbdHHxhzm8ZEoEi7+xPO/NGLdBmZRt3DDV618cX/gUefDbe772oQxM1PJhVJ8+nPU46D04lAOm6FU586daWIAbI5u3NmH0KTI+05+DPl7pcBz4J4WaP1PwjyhNMfeIep9jGz+rgDd7pZU8zWY0jdYOmA=", 
		"answer": "2+f4ZZj/3RDl+cf+5hMiirJO2BKbHs2aeEJc", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH+3hfj44oyUxz+wL3rNHnXBnZRtH6QEqZ6eHDtV67Maa3/ypR0NE/JmVQ7+n/Bq6Dit1YLmqta/YeQfmIBZ8ts2tWIw+35wzETc8tNlox765RfffBExSmke9raLL59y2+UNAfF3mKJJZOM/P01PYl2HC+9", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 million", 
		"option_b": "15 million", 
		"option_c": "2 million", 
		"option_d": "25 million", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130148", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17by/v+O3+QLm0Dt36PW7dtMEPiQKKCeuzszpJlZ0mHiV5psmLOpuXE4FYDibxTqaiWZidDR45u2pC52+X5mzP89hWWROqdzzZUCKfyhUnU", 
		"answer": "2+ftKIH2w1m7p9VwEhL70/i/N2LCF2oC4XPH8nsqopljSiVHC8IBgvQ=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa/Cuq44QyVRvmher+JivEDCIDpnuWUaY0eWWjQKiCPLi+y44xM1SMzV519jbJpeXE4FYDibxTqb6TcSxBLRJLZwFA+cnNuKhkJm6NDA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "20 per 1000 live births", 
		"option_b": "25 per 1000 live births", 
		"option_c": "30 per 1000 live births", 
		"option_d": "35 per 1000 live births", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130149", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz5Rb+9olgdBvg0fTzPH/JQ1AQt3rDVqpwMGXrUef2eejyz4N5Z2yFjFU783/L47H/t1IMh6Fe/4vfcjtDLNs+n4/LoPvLgt6t8MI9T9Ykwr9FNw==", 
		"answer": "y+S0x0hgF7emTb72sBQxySdS", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH9yuq+oouWwr91/z9OW6QF2MDpHqXErR1YzHxUaPXbeTwztd4MxydghspozbEuuXk/1ZPiqZfqYGZMDYLe8tb39WF0fD/hEFNMsgEioVg7ZUbPlDaxF4v5Y+mN9uvw3EQfgw=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": 18, 
		"option_b": 2, 
		"option_c": 21, 
		"option_d": 22, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130150", 
		"question": "24GwbdHHxhzm8ZEoEi7+xPO/IWrCBGcFpnvDW613YnTiR67Maa33x4F0NEiEiFVvsnfV46Sw51YdjK1V/Y+YdWIMeMtI7ODJw+u303lAJ4YB2IufdsmW/517DLaJUqQQZSI=", 
		"answer": "2+z9KiRk51n79e8QXl0XnUPWyDw=", 
		"explanation": "25y2a4P20Arj+YJgWxDkwO7rOG7eFyIFrD/aF+N7djHEcJeCeeztiZYxE0uMgV1v+jb2r6T+t1oBibpa+pqNZSEXa5lqiMSIxePy0DO1QiE7NrUMrjEKEvqMcCl7", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "7%", 
		"option_b": "8%", 
		"option_c": "9%", 
		"option_d": "10%", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130151", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV1771+/2MmrECm0f43uGRKZ4f2HuUanWLvn/25B0Mxycg19+4DbSq6Cww0QKg65P4c65eTQGPrJqycLJ5+j2yi4Ds1ws8rtgPbT3eRdv0TFgTQ==", 
		"answer": "2+TrKJz63RXj+ItgWhvx0fztMHiSa71bVXfRLK3hHxFHGcxpxg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH6wwvj8IQ0WxH8hen+J2zVFyIGomzDV618cX/gXanFLursxoRiZ1Wbn1J882LDp+Xx5VYOz65J5oPfKXJDaoQvmYDal+n+yH1IPMgEkoVx8JsNeecChtuvxjqD04p4oltvO+XcZw==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "10 million hectares", 
		"option_b": "12 million hectares", 
		"option_c": "13 million hectares", 
		"option_d": "15 million hectares", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130152", 
		"question": "24GwbdHHxhzm8ZEoEi7+xPO/NGLdBmZRt3DDQrF7ZnjnUefHYuj93YV4JFWdlBt68XXDsLaw41xPsJdk1rHfZisPcopozcPLzkgJ0k+4mZJjh4khev3uUg==", 
		"answer": "252tZpXh1B2q54AyURv80b3wMync0TvMnSszR27ZtXRVTY6V", 
		"explanation": "24WqZ4f61RDk8MUlXhvx0e/2NmLEGiIFrD+CXq80ZnjvWKbFa/6+3pZiZ13JgFR1+2LJsaTy+1ZPm6lJ7ouLMiqX7WYRKgEKe3zk9nuFu8w=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Hu,nd,red pe,rc,en,t of", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130153", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17g0O/+OSvCDGMV43yMXK1xc2XqQq7Wd63qyIV2IkjJhFU75n7D45Hn8l8Jm6Abz4eJdWI6e4p9iOCF1uqohvsG+iWY11neWpRzXx1l+AQ=", 
		"answer": "25a3Zp/20g2q9oksEgj7yfH+Mm7DQ3UYt3fDU694PWbmVbPKa/++25hwI0/Lt0ZVqowW30xRGTMvNxmPIQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHhxAvr+8UyXR/21r3rNHnXBnZRtH6QEqB7fn/mV7PLYOq+yJt9Z0qAgVd69XPV47L541tPjqRXpJmacTYLe5kv2t+I0/e1EKKORRPMqM1udHRbQtWwPg==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Connect 50% of villages with all-weather roads", 
		"option_b": "Connect 75% of villages with all-weather roads", 
		"option_c": "Connect 90% of villages with all-weather roads", 
		"option_d": "Connect all villages with all-weather roads", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130154", 
		"question": "24GwbdHHxhzm8ZEoEi7+xPO/NGLdBmZRt3DDW613YnTiR6KCeuX7iZBjIlmHzVh05HPU46fpt2wwsJcb5IeTfCsMcMtnzdOd1vby1zFAPchRm4x+/dhkg2aHQer3PBXbA4ep+IlA", 
		"answer": "27q2bdN9mL4f9vyXuoLqKeHFUMZc", 
		"explanation": "25y2a4P20Arj+YJgVQz3wPO/NmTGBnBRoWbDA+N5eX3vXajMLuX7yoNwNVmazV5t92Tf47z19kFPmKlIqZqXdWICeI1g2tWaw+XjzX5Pc9JFiId38NiY7+PEPTV2UOiXJkqlGOj2", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "on,e,tw,o", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130155", 
		"question": "2523f9H+xBrit5clXBvlxP/zMCvVDWcDpGbDUaJkcXLqQL6Cb+n6wIN4KFLJmlposmLHsaL141YLz6FVqZqXdWI3aY5jzsSBl8L+0nQBCsNFiMBC6JsRI7ZeiU9MPIyx7/00gC5A16vq", 
		"answer": "2+boJMGjgVnHwMedq31JOFDDqkG901W4rCwz", 
		"explanation": "25S8bJj91lm5p8lwAk6y6Mq/J27eBnUQoXOGEqZ6dWPkTefBb/3/yp5lPhyejEg78zbLrKv541wdjqpX7M6LcTAEe58twidKnTY5VtSU59Dwwp8mEA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "20,000 MW", 
		"option_b": "25,000 MW", 
		"option_c": "30,000 MW", 
		"option_d": "35,000 MW", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130156", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhj5t5EoV17G0vjzM3/YQ1IdonHDRqJmd3T3FKHNfK3awIV0JEjJr15193DPt+XE5VIBnK5e+53AMuOn2l+J+eq43ASsIYGGcg0=", 
		"answer": "25i5Yp7hkQr/9ZYpVhf31r3rPXnfFmUZ41uhZuNhY3jtU+fjb+n2yIUzWFb2uxCUBSaTp9JA+0vxfg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHX8y2q44QyVRvmher+JivUBm4YtXqRW61zMHziXqjQLv7ry4R4I1WMnhtv+mTJtqL4t1cGna1Y/c6ccTELPp99yd6a0eHl1zFUIM9KncBT5Z4XfeYCzxoLx1UodykB7fANLKep+g==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "10% DBT", 
		"option_b": "25% DBT", 
		"option_c": "50% DBT", 
		"option_d": "Major subsidies through DBT using Aadhar", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "130157", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwgD544AtEhr7wb3rPW6QN3UUr3mXWuNEfHDtFLfQYf3x2pIxM1PJmEh+snDJseXU/kEKjLwby4uRdSQKastb2tGHxOLy1mIecYT6YewEO7rjFXoPLPKnWwI=", 
		"answer": "25S5bJny0Auq54khRhj91/C9sNQvWAUmvXmzj/syrGEfnA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHX8y2q44QyVRvmhfTxI2TcFWcV42qQW61zMGXrUefjb+n2yJZjZ0yFjE99/WTL46P/5RMLhrpe6prfcyMQdst72tGHxOLy1mIDwiL+qi3X/lfII77TlSjFXQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Multi-Level Planning to Health", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Jan Dhan Accounts", 
		"option_b": "RUPAY Cards", 
		"option_c": "Aadhaar platform", 
		"option_d": "Mobile payments", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140101", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz0Avvt5YvXxuyxu/2IWLTCnEcsD+OU6dxMHDkVa7Mffm+3Z90Z0yMn0hr93XSqrP1t1YDiqVe55rfeSxDV4VrwdGHl/T7xX9POshDxbx8tdozffdLjDKrNNHNIfJ7z3qJKEuwaD/9FGJxgjjZn28WuI+6+zT7aNRlgDQwhYJ27s18M9Hf1aed7wCsgxSPnHyeSbF3UWiX5o6M6led4IY9s8SOuDfV9/38ibjv/opLSwVCvoVrI1S6164M/C8qUMS9ex93/9PYaFflYCelZxoV/IvwwnV9w48sU30ntB5Uh8NVbdJh05vw43AsPMXYZkcefE1fEXIPOC1X", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "24a9fpTh0BWq9JcpRhfxzO7yJivYAnQU432GV600fHT1UavHaq3/zpZ4KU+dzU9z9zbWprfj51YMm6FN7M6afCcOe4V7iNmHl835wHhAPYZUloF86pMRe64AnX2BddfQYPFojmuWJknlZi20C340mzeWmm5Tvoq04DT7RNY2zgZyxMdZ79s5MtSamaeVqEG3iAHPyH6DRf1jHlWVpo77q2edtIN4sciLuDHS8fr6k/3AsIpLSwVCvoVrI1S6164M/C8qUMS9ex8LxezVclGtIzqqMwcM7M7wlnxgwYolVG484F9SioYWbMV20tjisyBwMsJ4EHO5rElQ1ZF0WhmFfau9kGnq5BUsYWgqcY9qtS51sQOdJlp3lGzcXD5Ql5Ri/dUK1RBrfHsAnXLkkDqYkyWbdJbw7sD/iubzpatt4eEkDsTxFF9si/RfBiWYQE4h", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140102", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q440lEir3y+n3dU3ZFWdRmnqCQONEfHDtFLPQd63qxtdwI1ibiEhosmLOpuXg8kEcn61Y/YeJdWITcophxtmH0KT01nhVOsVNiY0t2JROPMdF2H2ge9rSNPF8z2yMIgXkZiu6AWRn1A3Y2Dx5vZe3/Cm+UJo20AUgmYZ75Yg6M8Xf/KSW/ki2kg7C7HeQRv1YHwfZk8Gr/lCZpMI3u42CpCbY+/n8ibjc5tsZIgdHq4p+ekj8q6ZduA81QcC1extR9OCQc1HrLzquNDITzsPq1XwpyYRpSWExtAxSg5dTb8V9woukvSA1f85lByG/oFAfhXDutttQjQPvDUwcjVYnwtU=", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UGWwj3hcT6NHmQM24QrT+GX6F1YnrmUOfNYK3/iZ1+Mk6HiEI75nmGt6Tz/F8Kz7xT7M6cYisXd4hm293J1uP2zX9SJ4ZUn5Jh9J8caP1WyX29eNXVLvdgyS6UL1f/cj61RHE0mSTannUbuJG0+yC+UJo20AUgmYZ75ZJ8bZes3LzT5UK2jxKNznqTRLgkBVWLssu8+APO4K0tocGEvzfftPXpiurc8d0DIg5drcZab16qkqYd8GoIXcm6KEEL1+vTdEfoJGisKU4S7N/g2Xls1cImS2wmtBBTlo9Xe9MzgtjBsSI4Pt5jDza+41ZFwZtuUgTWVqT42Wbn70cvemgqcYNju20hqQqPLRRtjnmdWClWnYV4spANnQEjSWpOiH6gsjOKjiWOdZ7m78Doiqj1rrFi/KAiaVWIMBzdUIsZZqfJMWJ8z/qITadSN990AzDnKdAp9Tq5IZqd2DcA1dc0b3jhtDqVk8P7MGu985v3h8B/FasJINTWqyJYe2IT67I7185S12Uipj8=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140103", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+zxhj5t5EoV17cxOn2OmXRDyIit36XW7BgeXLiWOfhYeDzwIRiLlOHzUh+5jbTs+Xk+BMGgrhJ5piaMCYCaoovzt+bl/T7xX9POshDxcJxsvummX9lIURw+f4QG/+3", 
		"answer": "y+XoOMp7iQiBXf+VzwaosmE7ASs=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH2wg3r9YkpQRb/wPPrdWTWQ3YZpj+tU7d9f3/iWOfxeuzqwIRlLl+IgRtY/XvLqrbj/lwBz6FVqZqXdWIae4p9iILZh7S3yXBTOMNA2oEy9JMJc+BBwH2+YNHLYPdgjm+EI1f1dCq0Cnc0kDDCizxSrYWy9i6+Wtk+xQZygo95+YgrOcWamamX/kiqlQOOxTuQTrthEkCQu8no/0uZ4JI9p96dtDHP/eL82ujf8dAFawZV/5ZtbFi5hLtJ8SR4eMawYRMLxezVIXfiLSWqNB0U9sWjxnho34ctHWh09w1TgYpXboBh2ZTh/Ds+f8RnBSG1tU1OwNRoVxLWZai53GHw+RU+e35rd49htSw3qAOVPE0+lW3cXzhQgIl46tkalAgjeW5UnTqgg3+Ij3eBeYHw/4/ygKj/pvlm9KUiKlWJI1mYRoEda73JKWAwUL/OBpIKAh4TRewDK9HPXw==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": 1990, 
		"option_b": 1995, 
		"option_c": 2000, 
		"option_d": 2005, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140104", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwxzs+JctQV7zzPD6MSvEDCIQp3vDV7V1fGTiQK7NYK3qxtdlL1nJnVd6/HjPraKw50EAjK1I+tHdoT7g9YK8QMOKRtBXtu0W0w==", 
		"answer": "24StaYPn1Avm7sUyVwj7wOq/NGXUQ3IUsXmMQK51fnLmFKXXaur73Z5/IB5I+V69DfuBb5+vyrOANx8K", 
		"explanation": "25T4e5Th2Bz5t4omEgz3w/LtOHiQFGcDpj+KXLdmf3X2V6LGLvnxiZV+K0+diEk75n7D46Dm9l8ajrxS5oDfcy0OboRhzd6dl/P+0HlIPYZQkoUy9JYecvpJwjrtZMbUI/t93TTAdgXEZiH9FnVymyPbmTwE6Key5i61Qt8k1Bg3mJM4vogNKdaNza2B5FT4lAOU1X6GCLxqFRSJsNyu5FGRoYw7sI2PpDbc8eDwlP+TpJ4taxtRvoo/YFSyhKcF8S45RcG7ZlJ/+eHDZBT/JS6sNQMOucjs2nhsxZYgS2w47V9Hi45TZoBn2djhsjoxMc5vVSeypgRTxIZpSx6Ybf231ij07FQxe3MlYspksiQhqA6IIUJ7iSudQigRnY177N8PkER3dWpJjjblhDmCg2yKcpD6q4Hygaj/ta1g/a4iOgO0RpcvS67T31XbHxdDvM4Z", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Tax reforms", 
		"option_b": "Disinvestment", 
		"option_c": "Quarterly review and performance budgeting", 
		"option_d": "Fiscal consolidation", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140105", 
		"question": "2523f9H32B2q9oY0Rx/+hfzzOWTTAnYYrHHDXaU0YH3iWufEe+P62tdlKByamVpv92WGp6z28VYdz65J5oPfZCoGcZlq3NmK1ui3xX1NPMVFjol96sUjcqUA5TOreMHeLv1rjmGGZ1X/azCpDXN1mHHQi39Cp5GotSi1FNs01AAzmsd54cQzP9aL0KedqHG21Ean33SfR7BtElWVudfo6UKfq5U5p8nNoiba4PHq2urW89sCdAFcuMZybEm5164c9i4rEfS6O1Jq/ejfYlX5KSetZwkI8M/m0jRr38IoUWAz+hJDjJcWdcln3tjHuTwkLcxmVSOoqktSzoB1WgSqeoqw2WvsoFo5NW4jYMp+qCwhpAKZJkBt2mqOSWxSm5J5+9MNykZScjyNpd4KRQ+bvt155dxU", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUqol5tyMTgvamx+yDS5tdxxbQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHy0g3/9olgUxL+yv7+IWLfDSIepT+TXqJ6MHf2WqPRLvnxiYRlJkiMnht09GLDreX0/kUKna9e7c6ZYi0OPp9nzZCd3+H41nRVOsVFlsB09psSeeNP3jbtcMHeYOphjmqZKUT9bjr9AnF3gD7EmSYW+cOS+yG3Qd85wxBymYE4/ccwNcOW2qmfqEu5hRKNzmjRR7MkEFeNoM+kq0KQrI07tNmEvjybprTcmffd/9MCYQles58/YVq/nL8I6i54Qty1fBdYsfbVYlHkNiGtIE4Q9tnmlnJ8yIY6HTp01RNKjYBXdsl82NjjqTs0OskqFyr6okhJwJpxWhmCNKqxxGCkw1AxYWgqacp9riQ6swaIIVFt2l+UST9U1JJu/9xUggtxcWsAn3nukTaPhXeOaJrs5ZO8jObksrZn56AiLQGDOlHIWogEbKfJInQy3uGaGeZVPZlrAifoPtAqvCv8M5mBzToIkN0pPGP1/SiMhsT6NyW4tov2gNA2ALcFdsXN7MSltUjOYiLtYXSXY8r4FUj5Qmz50BpsuR9lzCQG7W7XGIR6+zkMkj6/XFBnnSrlfz7mMLXp0b0LU7+4BYDSiXSB", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140106", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzwg349pElVRf31r3oMHnVQ2MVrG+XV6c0ZH6jVaPGfOjt2tdjIluAglV6/jbPrqfx+1IBjK0b4IDfdCcVe4dg2N2M2fCo+H8Qc/ZWk49g7Y4WZvEAzjyuf8PaMvou3GuHLkr+dHm7C2I0tzTYnm5XpMOy+zG+R846xRsmhcdE45p8GN6Z362B7UOsjweW2TuVTathHVuJuMum/wOPtJA5ociKuDfItPb4if3XsNEFIhtGvpJ6I1W5kqwauBY2AoidZhFO//DZd133JWizNQcL+N/mln1n0Ic6SWQx+gsGi40WbsF00ZHqu3IiOspjGj2p43hOk9RMTRiAfbm9kGHq41AxYXM9YJktuiIn4RyIKUB7iSzcSiVCl4FnvsIckwtxcHx8kkHoizyDwGqJPIfr7sD9h+fmpfli4KZnKk6SJ1nbQs0PcbLUImp3xP2IUuSOCdPMdMR3OErn10LvcNMK", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "24asbYHgkRXj/IBgQgz7yu/2IWLKCmwW432CUahjcWPnFLXHaeTxx4Q9Z1iAi11+4HPIt6zx41YLz7tP+4+LdSUKe5gvyd6Nl+Xj0GNAMNJNlIcy9IgWavVUyX2kesLeM+pjy2CUZ1HxdT64EHVw1CPTjXVZpoK3tSOyR8o20hwmn4Jrr+oFKpPvDVY/L1/mCfR6MlU=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140107", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iOCF1ur5zX9Gc89K2ql84JMePPxB332vcdHVYPF4y3yMPgXzYjepFnF4nSvTjjxqpr+1xyK6R9U5gF0A3904zs0yKMWe1aGJ6VmxiQjC1XWSWrhlAlGd9c+u/0aO4Kw9vd+Y9iGb8PH4jvCR11qEkLRi/sx4aY4BtT6K3Q==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyM68dSwXbIpjwcqIw+34yjFONYZUloF86pMRe7RJwj6/cdXIJfouz2iUIlewSTy1FmUzh3HSj3Ffu4b79DT7W8onzwY3ksds4og0NcTf3KWD4EyrjxXC03XRS7JrAVGLtNqh/Ubcpoc8sN+MvTvI+bbQ7rTQbR73wbWwDBr+gAUI", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is NOT the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140108", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iOSB0qSgl2NFc8dKnsAlsI4XPPVNyTOpedHVNO0u3nyPKkrkYj39AHV3kT/CmH1aoZm+8WerWNs5zhw8kbt2rfQyDtKeyqedqAWKz1zC6HOUUf1hHESWosu67kfcrI07tMHNtj3N8eb3l/3d5M1LYQdcrJJ2d06onqcH+SY0SIpf3cqSNAx8SlldOlGUze6N", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyM69aWITbIR5wdSA2eO3x35PINJNjpVm7ZURffgAwTyjcNXPJb56wS6QJkvzbzikBWRn1DDYjjxbvY2y9i6rVdY+1Bw3hcs4+cA5fNaS3KaX5Ui2khXC2XWQSrFhFRSdsM2t5VeOoY4xr8iJ8TXJ9efqiPfc5M1LcgRTsYh2bVz+GKE2lZMH9qg28nuehTwYTA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is NOT the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140109", 
		"question": "25C5ep361Auq54khXA2yw/L8IHjVByIerT+8bZxLT07ca5iCa+DuxZhoKlmHmRt4/XvWorf18xMbgOhI7IKZPScObodg0d2M2fC184v9soLKjJEro/N95RNEpQ==", 
		"answer": "26K5b5Sxq9dNfQJQMWT7oe6ezQXohw==", 
		"explanation": "25C5ep361Auq54khXA2y1e/2OnnZF2sLpnvDRaJzdTHmWbfOYfTzzJllZ1WHzVJ19mPVt7f58kBPnalP4YuNMDYLf4Uv29WF0anyyWFNPN9Jn45mpi68rplOB1f+0zRTgyxfVwE=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "wa,ge", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140110", 
		"question": "24e9bp7h3Aqq8pchEg7+xPPxPGXXQ3EZqnmXV6c0dXzzXKbRZ/6+3ZgxGGO2smREzUn546P/5RMKgrhX5peSdSwXPoxqxtWb1vD+y38D38eerBK4j/xaGA9dDGR5Fw==", 
		"answer": "26a9ZJe+1BT6+4o5Xxv80b+QD7NPNJWKMYMRd4YKkbVa", 
		"explanation": "24e9bp7h3Fnv5YRgQhLzy/P2O2yQBW0StmyGVuN7fjHzRqjPYfn3x5AxNFmFixZ+/2bKrLz98l0bz71V5YeUdWIGf5ljwdWbl/P2w3QBNstUlo9r6Z8RaLRB3C2/e9XYKLyj/9r1jupC2hJfKfn3WyHy", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "sel,f-e,mpl,oy,me,nt", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140111", 
		"question": "24GwbdHM7ibVyMUhXxv8wfj7dX/YBiI4rXuWQbdmeXTwFO/ma/v7xZhhKlmHmRs9skTDpLD89kcGgKYSqa+cZG5DL9I6mZCM2eX1yHhPNIZUiIlk5Y4WZvVUxTKjNNvdYM5d+33CzIdcSBqFEn8yl+H7VjYR1A==", 
		"answer": "25u9f9Ha3x3/5JEyWx/+hc3wOWLTGiJA+ibSECkV5Xv2MzTrzQPYZRr4GEM=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHd1A6q3oskRw3m1/T+OSvgDG4YoGbDXaU0ISi6BefDY+jwzZJ1Z0iBiBtS1jD044Tz4xMAiegKsNvOMDYMPo5hydKF0qTn1nhXMtJNgIFm7ZURPPtGjA2eQceZxj6qzAprJ0Ic2BS5cI2d+g==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Ne,w In,du,st,ri,al P,oli,cy 1,9,91", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140112", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz3Rzut5EvEhvqxvjsJmLGBiIWrGmGQK15dX/3FKTNYPnsxpsxJlKNzV90/3/Ioqvz8hMAiehr2ruMMCsNPp9nzZCg2eD+xX8BNsVLlI9//doQavFSjCmkedGEYkDcIHWShmJHbm95RUF/HtQ=", 
		"answer": "24W0aZ/92Bftt5UyWxHgzOn2MHiQAmwV43aNVrZnZGPqVauCfuLywJR4Ik/LIn1tJia9B/SQVGNBo3yZFA==", 
		"explanation": "24W0aZ/92Bftt4AtQhbz1vTsdWTeQ1IilmzDVrF9ZnTtFKXbLsD/wZZ9JlKGj1JosnvJp6D8t1IBi+hS54qKYzYRd4pjiMCG2+30zXRSc8pBnsBm69oaZPdF3y6kYtGbJ/F4y3yOKkD+c3m+C35ghj7ayDjUhamFdd+nEUINkLTAT3s=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Socialist ideology", 
		"option_b": "Lack of private capital", 
		"option_c": "Planning priorities and industrial policies", 
		"option_d": "Risk averse bureaucracy", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140113", 
		"question": "25S/epjwxBX+4pclEgnz1r3wI27CEGoQp3CUV6c0dGTmFLPNLujmypJiNFWfiBt9/XXTsOX/+RMwsJdk1rGgTx1Dd4Uv4d6N3uX5hGFNMshKk451plXcULSaPCi1Dure2Eq7Cmk=", 
		"answer": "27y2bITgxQvj9okpSB/mzPLxd7F+HW8HR/I4Myfqts7w/us=", 
		"explanation": "25Cga5TgwhD88sUwQBf91/TrPHHRF2serT+MVON9fnX2R7PQZ+zywI1wM1WGgxt393KGoqLi/lAag7xO+4vfcicKcIwvx8aMxff/xXVOJMNA2ol8pJ8ebvhZjC2hddrVKfBpjL9M3NjgoVmh6L+aV3AOHPo=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "in,du,st,ri,al,iz,at,ion", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140114", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQAG0fsHqSR6Z6c3TwFKjELuP7zpt0JEjJgl0783HUqqbl+0cana0b+oucZC0RPpxm3NjJw+zyhGFNMshKk451pJ0QffhTjDSgZNXYNPtqlC68KXn+SzCuEDAl1Hn1hXJFrZKu8Cm4Ucl+/BsT1qF34sx8NdmM3KuG+kSsn0a+0lnRZLJzUUaMp8+kq0qSo401sN7NsDzftPD8l/nd9J43bCsSkodtaF6o164I8SYtQ82IZi5F3e3DdRS/YGCEKA8R6ovq22RoxZYsWSAI+hYGpZFZddR7lqTqtTtwGtx/HCej43hOzp11HySTeLv1wm3o6VQxdn9pPskp/9jWNjInq7fVwZx5YA==", 
		"answer": "25T4JdH62BCq1cVtEhf7hd6/eCvZQQTJhnIUaR87FNNWfmyxTmM=", 
		"explanation": "25u9b5320g2q+INgUxngzP7qOX/FEWdRr3qHErd7MH72QKTNY+jtiZt4LFnJi1R09jbPrbb19EYdhrxCpc6TfzVDbJ59ydzJ0+H6xX9Fc8dKnsB/5YgUeeAAyjykeMHJJb5nw36FI0z+YHmtCHF6mjjYjTxRp4K35mVS4nCikLpEf3DKKa4CU5/w", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "A - i B - ii C - iii", 
		"option_b": "A - ii B - iii <C - i", 
		"option_c": "A - iii B - ii C - i", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140115", 
		"question": "24a9fIX63x6q4pVgWxD20O7rJ2LVECIYrT+BU6B/Z3DxUOfQa+r3xpliZ0uAmVN052KGoqH15kYOm60b4ICZYiNDeo55zdyGx+nyymUBP8NA2pR9vtjFtcUSOO8Q/Xkj859zlMeX", 
		"answer": "24C2bJThnAz+/okpSB/mzPLxdWTWQ2sfp2qQRrF9dWKkFLfNeujw3Z5wKx4MxCxtxvdI+11bgTLvXDhl", 
		"explanation": "25CrfJDx3RD5/4wuVV77y/nqJn/CCmcC43aNEqF1c3r0VbXGLv/7zp5+KU/JmlJv+nnTt+X5+VUdjuhf7JiafC0Tc45h3JCF0uC30H4BJshAn5I/8Y4WcP1azSmke9qbL/gu3mGUIkvkbjixRrT+YWi/0mJA5U7g9WNQKbA=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Rise in regional disparities", 
		"option_b": "Under-utilization of industries' potential", 
		"option_c": "Industrialization of backward regions", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140116", 
		"question": "25m5a5qz3h+q5I4pXhL3wb3zNGnfFnBRqnHDUKJ3e2biRqOCfOj5wJh/NByejEg78zbFrKvj8kIaiqZY7M6QdmIFf55j3MnJ3urz0WJVIc9FlsB+65keaP1Pwn29e9jSI+cu7WGNKkD+c3t8kzrplCkNLGc35hj4GPvQ", 
		"answer": "24GKXbSxHm4A89/yf9ZfF9Op1Z8h7g==", 
		"explanation": "25m5a5qz3h+q5I4pXhL3wb3zNGnfFnBRom2MQaY0eX+jVqbBZfr/25MxNVmOhFR1sn/Ip7Dj40EGirsb7ZuaMDYMPoduy9vJ2OK3zGRMMsgEmYFi7Y4ecLREySuoeNvLLftg2ixPCgnTYPfcMK05INb0Vl2i", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "TRUE", 
		"option_b": "FALSE", 
		"option_c": "Partially True", 
		"option_d": "Partially False", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140117", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRbst5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRsXqQR69gdXWjUrXNY6370ZR0NE+Am1479XnQprf++lYBm+hY5oCLYi0PPoRpiNaA2eX5x3RSc9JL2oZn6p5fbPhBwi7yNOjVcb5N3GGXI0z+YHmyEWQ0mzeWmm5fvoKv8GeyWswy0wE/k4lsrfQybpe30K+bqFm5nkaHynqCQbJqUWiX5o6b50yL4JY9tsWDvj7U8/36m/ST4MwEZRpXrJU/X1Xo14AA/yJ4WMayZBNf+OveXVraKCGgL04S/4v33nEp1ZYoSWw58RFSkcNXcMUz1Zf2rjczK5Io0B7aBD2BF5A+jIPI1accUQ==", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "25K3fpTh3xTv+ZFnQV70zPP+O2jZAm5Rp3COW611fnLmFKvHaq3qxtd+MkiKglZ+4TbKqq71t1AdgL9f4ICYMC0WastgzpCZxe3hxWVEc9VBmZR99tZfaPVYjDi7dcfSL/Auz2CEZ1b8aC79EHV3nD/ZhnNRscO68SirQNM4zlcA/jQM0XDtgBNhDUsDtJvs", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140118", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjp48UlXw790vjtMG+QEHYQt3qQErd7MHPsRrXNea3pwIN5KEmdzXh+/GLUpuLjt1Ifn7pU/4+TMDYMPo1mxtGH1OG312VAJ8MEioxz6oldLAq8IUnRSWv6KwaZ/TaTag==", 
		"answer": "25Oxe5Ly3VnY8pYwXRDhzP/2OWLEGiIQrXvDcLZwd3T3FIrDYOz5zJp0KUjJrFhvsHQRMOOuKzQGynQrHcL0J9o=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHV4zvHt6QjRl79w72tZTuDQ2Mdr3CUV6c0Y2XiQKLRLvnxiZV+NU6Gmhts+2LOrLDkt3AKgbxJ7MmMMCMTbplg3tGFl+L41jFHOshFlIN76p1fb+BB2DjtZNjaLu0sxfxHmkENdCyqQMVv8ZoMaA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Planning Commission Act", 
		"option_b": "Fiscal Responsibility and Budget Management Act", 
		"option_c": "Financial Management Act", 
		"option_d": "Finance Commission Act", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140119", 
		"question": "25G9ZZ7wwxj+/oZgbSHN+sLAClTvQ24Upz+XXeNkf33qQK7Bb+G+wJllIk6PiEl+/HXD46z+t1YOnaRCqZ6TcSwNd4VoihLY1RJi/F/PjKKSmf9ZxW8=", 
		"answer": "27y1ZZDnxAvj45xioS7tDCOblcQ4+WRRygO0qQ==", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJjylgqq84AtXR3gxOn2NivZDm8Qt2qRW7dtMHjtFKLDfOHniY50Jk6azVd+9jbSrOXg+F8Gm6FY6ILfeSwXe5lpzcKM2efyhHhPc9ZIm4587ZQYPoAsD3yfsNk1qNvb9X+zNL8=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "im,ma,tu,ri,ty", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140120", 
		"question": "24qHV67M7iaq+INgRhb3he3zNGXeCmwW42+RXaBxY2KjV6bXfej6iZN4NEiGn09y/XjV46n5/FZPna1c4IGRcS5Dd4ZtydyI2efy1zPvEdvW2FBKzztblV6yhEe/", 
		"answer": "24W3ZJjn2Brj5IQ0WxH8h64gOv7qLTzEBFPSibzBr/k=", 
		"explanation": "24W3ZJjn2Brj7YQ0WxH8hfL5dXvcAmwfqnGEEq9xdDH3W+fGZ/7qxoVlLlOHnhty/GXSpqT0t1wJz7pe7ZuceSwEPplqz9mG2eX7hHRCPMhLl4lxpJ4Wb+RB3jS5fdHIYiPwI77MSpnvRCwH/5Ghhd8=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Po,li,ti,ci,sa,ti,on", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140121", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+z1RDut5EoV171yuv6J2XdBmwF436HXbNgMHCjV6jMfe73xoJiZ0yGgVJ46zbSrLLx5Vccz6FV6oKKYysVe8to2t+ew+yoht/5alfRONAnBMKZFezloeE=", 
		"answer": "2+foOMG+gUioFgljgzs6rimV7ZCPYMRyZA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH03g/v5YstVxDmhfz7OnvEBmZRoj+AXa1nc3jsQbSCZ+P9xYJiLkqMzVxp/WHSq+Xg+F8GjLEb4IDfInJTLsY/mZCL1vfywDFOPYZF2pJ38pMaa7RPyn2od9vVL/NnzS6SIkP/dTSuRqNpJjKD51755jbt9u/G+Wk=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1999-00", 
		"option_b": "1991-92", 
		"option_c": "1993-94", 
		"option_d": "2000-01", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140122", 
		"question": "25y2a53mwhD88sUnQBHl0fW/ImrDQ2NRqHqaEqV7c2TwFK7MLvr2wJR5Z3qAm147y3PHseXA+1IB0OrDiZZaJ5Ds6tIdq+D0mwkZ", 
		"answer": "25C0bYf23w3it7UsUxCwKSxBjagxrE24KwHiT7Sygw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHW3Rz88os0Wl7CyfzxdSOCUzJG7i7RG+Nyf3L2R6LGLuLwiZ5/JFCcnlJt9zbBsarn41tPjrsb6IDffyAJe4h7wcaMlZzUhlTL4FvQXSlxDqm6Cog=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Ninth Plan", 
		"option_b": "Tenth Plan", 
		"option_c": "Eleventh Plan", 
		"option_d": "Twelfth Plan", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140123", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQrp/4AtVw2yxPTydX/fQ3IDrGmKVqY0cnDwXaSCb+D7x55lLlmazU90smLHsaL14xMfgLhO5Y+LeS0NIctTxoHJ8unnyH5YPsNKjsB14ZQabvVUxTKjNMTJL/l8z2OTZ3n+NXmbC39w1CLTiWlEoZeitTepW90lwRgh1rt2vogUM8KM0KaUqEy2gkaR3XWYXLxwGFuX9d2r40aRpZF4icPZ8QHQ/fj12vzW5tsHbRhfuohrI1KynrwA+T4xR82nKkXSgBR/HqkGI/TeCCBeylw=", 
		"answer": "2+f0KMKz0Bfut9Fi1LB3cmVPXGWtbxH1/PCLYw==", 
		"explanation": "25K3fpTh3xTv+ZFgQR36wPD6JivfDSIXrHCHHuN8f2TwXanFIq3tyJl4M12dhFR1snPSoOXx/l5Pm6cb+ZyQZisHe8ttycOA1KT2yXRPOtJNn5My8JVfeP1TzTm7ddrPIflryi6TIkbkbjazFzJuTjkkodJS9F+sHKU7zLTK", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "2, 3 and 4", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140124", 
		"question": "24awZ4PnnA3v5YhgQhH+zP7mdW3fESIYrXyPR7B9ZnSjU7XNefn2iYV0K1WMnhtz93fQqqnpt1wBz5dk1rGgTx1B6ZIlhv+xkLPHwkxkO58hJw==", 
		"answer": "26ataoL61RDv5McT2ZjLA4q+IFPtgvmFgYFW", 
		"explanation": "24awZ4PnnA3v5YhgWxDxyejsPGTeQ3Ier3aAS+NhY3TwFLTXbP73zZ50NByLmE87+nfV46P55FAOg+hI/J2LcSsNf4lmxNmdzqT+12JUNtUGr0Cl29BWUKriuQ7hPl300w==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "su,bs,id,ies", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140125", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1Rbv5MU0WhuyyfLxMibEBnAc43aNUa9hY3j1UefFfOLp3Z8xN1OFhFhisnDJoLDjt1wB0Ohn59/fVS8TcoR2xdWHw6TwwX9EIcdQk498pKYRLrRwwyuoZsDCYP9iwmuWLkTkbjazREx6x3HzjmlVqZey+in7VdQzgAY5n4t0rcw5KtKT1rie7UOsxjqMiDuiXb93GFCQsN3o6k2Y4Is2tsiDpTvN8ee72tEScEIiImQAAkuUMjCUmg==", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "25m3Zpa+xRz4+sUwXRL7xuS/M2TTFnEUsD+MXONndX3lGbXHYuT/x5R0Z0iBn1Ru9X6Gpqjg+1wWgq1V/cLfYC0Ve5l70ZCI2+jy0nhAJ89LlMBz6p5fefBVzzy5fdvVb+1lx2KMNAdgTOPxqB8k2TtGhr9+xLGq", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140126", 
		"question": "24azYZ3/kR3v4YAsXQ7/wPPrdWLeCnYYomuKRKZnMGbmRqKCYuzrx5R5IljJmVQ74mTJrqrk8hMwsJdk1rGgT2AmvSzFmbVIJAvWsPIZnkOv", 
		"answer": "26a9ZJe+wxzm/oQuURuwnl1r1WAyihEab7IsHa35qg==", 
		"explanation": "24azYZ3/kR3v4YAsXQ7/wPPrdW7BFmsBsD+TV6xkfHSjUqjQLv77xZE8IlGZgVRi/3PIt+Xx+VdPnK1X78ONdS4Kf4VszZJdKhg9Wj8wN21hb1dLqxEf", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "sel,f-re,li,an,ce", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140127", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV170yvHzOnzZDWVRoHCHV7A0cX/nFKbMffr729dwJF+Gn19y/HHKuv/M+XIcnK1J/YeQfmJLX8I1iOKMxOvi1nJEc8tLmIl+7YAeaP1Pwn2kesLULOhr3S6DL0T+aTyxDX5z1CPTmXNDuoC+5mevW8020hEh1pd07MYyOdPf3a2F7UG3lguH0m/RT7JlHUelu46U5XGZoZE3u43Fg3uBtN3t2v3d89EGcglBrINsI1yzga0b9ic9X9z0ehdd9OrFZBitMzimKQoU98yj13pthosnS2wn4BJDjJcWcs9/35vtuSFyBtQ/M2iJMhVQThmTYC8cYA==", 
		"answer": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyMzhe6ddeFdnLLMGFYjfRT4E", 
		"explanation": "25e3fJmz8Fnr+YFgYF7z1/i/IXnFBiIQrXvDYON9YzH3XKKCbeLs25JyMxyMlUt383jHt6z/+RMJgLobyM6tdTEMa5lszZCE2Ob+yHhbMtJNlY4y8Ykab7RGxS6uddibMPFix22JIlawczb9AHlmkTLCym5Tu4yu5yS+R5ojzwIzhINrrdgwPdmR3KzT7EiugwqNzHaURqkkHlaTsM284lWZs8B9uunINcN22i3hKO8w0oSM", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Both A and R are true and R is the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_b": "Both A and R are true but R is NOT the correct explanation for A", 
		"option_c": "A is true but R is false", 
		"option_d": "A is false but R is true", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140128", 
		"question": "24W0aZ/92Bftt6YvXxP71u72OmWQFGMC422GQbN7fmLqVqvHLuvx29djIk+GmEl49zbLrKf5+1oVjrxS5oDfdi0RPrRQ9++26NvI+05+DIZ4lNEyx58RaOZFiy7tZNjaLr59zWaFKkDjJwWzVjBHgDDCjzxGpIK15meHWol38Ac7gIZs6IgvOdSL1rrT+kipkw+Q2XaURql3UWiX4Y6Y/kGQqYF4osiBtzPJ8bTqiv3d9NcFZUoNKDZtlYkMipBiLE2BvLBp", 
		"answer": "2+T4aZ/3kUuocWEOEhwNBe0zN4qxEabNUg==", 
		"explanation": "24W0aZ/92Bftt6YvXxP71u72OmWQDm0TqnOKSKZwMGPmR6jXfO772td3KE7Jrl515mTD5Law9l0Lz7tP6JqaY2VDWIJ5zZCw0uXlhEFNMsgEiYN64Zcab7bkU7IQ7/hSUqdmxqguu7d3", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "1 and 3", 
		"option_b": "1 and 4", 
		"option_c": "1 and 2", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140129", 
		"question": "25Oxe5Ly3Vnp+IszXRL7wfzrPGTeQ3UQsD+KXKpgeXD3UaOCeuK+25J1Ml+MzVx05HPUraj1+UdPsJdk1rGgT2ICcI8vzd6I1ejyhGFTOtBFjoUy958caPtSjC+oZ9vOMv1rjmOPJUz8biO8EHl7mnMV7v3Q3xjeVnVQgH1YlcC5", 
		"answer": "27G9bpjw2A2o837ta8V8FqTOrR16cut68g==", 
		"explanation": "25Oxe5Ly3Vnp+IszXRL7wfzrPGTeQ3AUp2qAV6c0d371UbXMY+jw3dd1IlqAjlJvsmLJ46T8+1wYz7hJ4JieZCdDbY5s3N+bl+X0x3RSIIZQlcB07ZQecvdF33+bb7D0uRwdkRvZSx75AEiY", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "de,fi,cit", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140130", 
		"question": "25OKSryz8Br+u8VyAk6hhfz2OG7UQ3Ye42+RXbV9dHSjR7PDeujtiZBjIl2diEk782PSrKv/+kpPhqYb1rGgTx08QbQtVelTud5FqmPMYTdITrZE+A==", 
		"answer": "27e3eoP8xhDk8MeFFXJXlW4AgljG0l6JKpx/", 
		"explanation": "25OKSryz8Br+t4AtQhHlwO/6MSvDF2MFpmzDRqw0cn7xRqjVLvr33Z9+MkjJrl515mTD5Law9kMfnadN6ILfdi0RPph7ycSMl/T7xX9ScVfl55WdhENiJMsq7ywUT/s=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "bor,ro,wi,ng", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140131", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEg7gzPD+J3KQAmsc43CFEoR7f3XwFKbMaq3NzIVnLl+MzW966jaOhJbEvgxNoY1OASXr+kEuYIP+zZxY6g==", 
		"answer": "27C2YJD90hyq5JEhRhvhgr3tMH3VDXcU43yCQqJ3eWX6FncfiBLOBODNoEyN63PzO2c=", 
		"explanation": "25KLXNHy2BT5t5EvEhv8zfzxNm6QEHYQt3qQFeN9fmXmRqnDYq3szIF0KUmMzVh64nfFqrHpt1UAnehJ7J2QZTAAe8tix9KA2+3txWVIPMgG3mJiyw8TZv3VSGgl/BuU7Q==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "reduce inflation", 
		"option_b": "simplify taxation", 
		"option_c": "increase exports", 
		"option_d": "enhance states' revenue capacity", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140132", 
		"question": "25i5fJL7kQ3i8sUmXRL+yur2O2yQF2cDrmzDQKZ4cWXmUOfWYa35xoF0NVKEiFVvsnDPraT+9FYcz79S/YbfZCoGd5kvwd2Z2+30xWVIPMhXwMBO6qYRUP1T2H38NOjVAb5cy3iFKVD1Jz24Anl3nSXqhF4Wjoqo9ia3FN4yxhwxn5M40cYffOeN0KWS+lT4ggOE1XiYXP1YH2iXmce7/wPOnIwx9eSDpTfJ8eft2ujS6dMObBxB/4RqcV+5meg19iMxEeq7egBE5u3eZketJTCgIgsZudnmwHFn04dpYWc9/RYGsIZRd8xyxNj3rDc+O8RkEnO/u0dFwpBvHwWTYri2xW2mALJYkm+S9OcTZ593WOutqw==", 
		"answer": "25T4JdH62BCq1cVtEhf7hd6/eCvZQQTJhnIUaR87FNNWfmyxTmM=", 
		"explanation": "2569cdH+1A34/oYzEhL7zvi/J27GBmwEpj+HV6V9c3j3GOfEZ/79yJsxI1mPhFhy5jbHraGw50EGgqlJ8M6bdSQKfYJ7iNiIweG312FEMM9Ck4My7ZcPcP1DzSmke9rIYPhh3C6HKFP1dTewAX5g1DffhH1Yq4aot+CmusHlQmMB8XHKAgDEt00=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "A - ii B - iii C - i", 
		"option_b": "A - i B - iiC - iii", 
		"option_c": "A - iii B - ii C - i", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140133", 
		"question": "25y2fpTgxRTv+ZFgXxH2wPHsdXnVBWcD42uMEpxLT07ca5j9LvjtzJMxM1PJgFR5+3rPuaCw5VYcgL1J6ouMMCQMbMt/xNGH2eHzhHVEJcNIlZB/4ZQLPp7pqruarTqaSpKZhAwVzxE=", 
		"answer": "27i9aZ/gkRjk88U0XRH+1r/BPHbPbbOQV21smenWz+WV", 
		"explanation": "25y2fpTgxRTv+ZFgXxH2wPHsdW/VDW0Fpj+XWqY0fXTiWrSCb+P6iYN+KFCazU5o93KGt6qw+lwNhqRS84vfYicQcZ59y9Wal+L41jFRP8dKlIV2pJ4aavFMwy2gcdrPYjcAA1JJTuK/19vEqC4fwKM=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "mea,ns a,nd to,o,ls", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140134", 
		"question": "24KwZ9Hk0Aqq440lEhPzzPO/PGXGBnEFrG3DW600ZHnmFKLBYePxxI4xI0mbhFV8smLOpuXA/1IciuhyqYeRZicQaoZqxsTJ2uvzwX0Be5cdz9E/ssNWI7ZrmEtWGpht7Nie89hyDs+y", 
		"answer": "25K3fpTh3xTv+ZFi8buaUinsYea2nDjLTFTzKg==", 
		"explanation": "24WwaYL2kTCq8YosXhHlwPm/NCvDF2MFpjKPV6c0fX7nUauCeeTqwdd2KEqMn1V293jS46Tjt0cHiuhL+4eScTAaPoJh3tWaw+vlhm5i8FOSKMM/bvNQkHG1BkU=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Private sector", 
		"option_b": "Foreign investors", 
		"option_c": "Government", 
		"option_d": "All were equal investors", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140135", 
		"question": "24WwaYL2kTCq5YAzXQvgxvi/OGTSCm4YuX6XW6x6MGPmWK7Haq32zJZnLlCQzVR1smHOqqb4t1wJz7xT7M6Zfy4PcZxmxtfWlbbue5K2vylcZQuETiMq910=", 
		"answer": "26G5cJTgkRjk88UkVxj7xvTrdW3ZDWMfoHaNVeH5lwMrs1egCx5SZeqs4RVd", 
		"explanation": "24WwaYL2kTCq5YAsWxv2hfD+P2TCD3tRrHHDRqJsMGPmQqLMe+jtiZZ/IxyNiF1y8X/S46P5+VIBjKFV7s6Lf2IFa4VriMCF1urkhiRtPvdCXAF1BY8lyn9j2+U=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "foreign aid", 
		"option_b": "taxes and deficit financing", 
		"option_c": "PSU profits", 
		"option_d": "private profits", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140136", 
		"question": "24KwaYWzxhz48sUzXRP3hf7wO3jVEncUrXyGQeN7djH3XKKCXuX/2pIxDhyAg01+4WLLpqvkt14Ai61Xts6jfnNDV4Vr3cOdxe32yHhbMtJNlY4y5o8LPP1Oyi+sNNPaMO0u8mDSZ2H/ajCzBX53kXHZjDxGvYG3/CT7R9801Bog1rt2vogQPdDf262H/0i9iEaEyXWVCLNhFFCK9c+m7wORr4AxucSXsCbS+/q5pvaHsPYCZQAStoh5b1qonqcHxCQPWcG3YFJE96TEaVGtISqsMQtd+Nnmlndm1JAsXn105wtHloZbZ85nxcKmrfeveMegvjGIwGlzPcxKOw==", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "24WwaYL2kTCq+4AkEgr9hfLqIWjfDmcC43OKWaY0eX/nQbTWfOT/xZ5rJkiAglU783vPp7bkt1oBibpaqYmeYDFPPrtc/ZCN2On+ynBPMMMEm452pJwKcvBJwjrteNXcYj41dsqIwulrpA2P0q47GlE=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140137", 
		"question": "25+3YZ/nkQrv9JEvQF7/yvn6OSvRD24etHqHErNmeWfiQKKCfuzs3Z5yLkyImVJ0/DbPreXn/1oMh+ha+4ueY2IHa5lmxtfJw+zyhEFJMtVB2qlbu9hOFMVh06X2NCR761hp3YZp", 
		"answer": "25SqbZDgkRb68otgRhGy1e/2I2rEBiICpnyXXbE2C7rLCiktOEvIBKD+FlDN6A==", 
		"explanation": "24WwaYL2kTDDt4QsXhHlwPm/JXnZFWMFpj+TU7FgeXLqRKbWZ+LwiZ5/Z1WHiU5o5mTPpraw9l8diqlf8M6QYCcNPp9giMCb3vL20HQBIMNHjo9gps05YWqcD4Oiuqg5z1C9qIY=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Areas open to private sector", 
		"option_b": "Areas open to government sector", 
		"option_c": "Both of the above", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140138", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRjp48UyVxnnyfzrMG+QBW0DpnaEXON3f33vVaXNfOzqwJh/Z12HiRtd1l+Gp7Di/l0Iz5hT6J2aMAsqV8tgzpCA2fLy12VMNshQ2o194J8TI7ZiEzLsPJ2ioq+TC8UkCLJc", 
		"answer": "25OdWrCxkvFR8aJ6BXF1kwufYBWAhw==", 
		"explanation": "24WwaYL2kTDD3sUhXhL90vj7dWfZDmsFpnvDVKxmdXjkWufBYeHyyJV+NV2dhFR1snTTt+XW03pPmKlIqZyaYzYRd4h7zdTJwurzwWMBFeN2u8L/4fIYEgB8JoMue0pOvQMH", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "FEMA", 
		"option_b": "IDRA", 
		"option_c": "FERA", 
		"option_d": "FIIA", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140139", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz3Bjg+JdgXhf/zOn+IWLfDSIVqnvDdIZGUTHzWKbBa63xx9d3KE6MhFx1snXJr6nx9VwdjrxS5oDfdDcRd4VoiOCB1vfyhFhoGpkG6pSa3mYhX8BJRtkqLOa5Bg==", 
		"answer": "25mxZZjn1B2q44pgQRvx0fLtJivfE2cf42uMErNmeWfiQKKCfej93ZhjZXjjVF+SWJ7pL3V+/XjdL8Q=", 
		"explanation": "25OdWrCzwxz545cpUQr3wb35OnnVCmUf42uKV+5hYGKjQKiCfej93ZhjNByIgUl+83Lf46rg8l1Pm6cb+ZyWZiMXe8tGxtSA1uq3x35MI8dKk4Vhpj9Mxjb1+zD9R+XVVlqr/n4=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Limited to sectors open to private sector", 
		"option_b": "Limited to sectors open to government sector", 
		"option_c": "Both of the above", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "140140", 
		"question": "24WwaYL2kTDD3sUpXAj31unyMGXEQ28ep3qPEqd9dDHtW7OCb+HyxoAxDlKNhFo75nmGoaD+8lUGm+hd+4GSKmI/cNov7t+b0u3wyjFCMtZNjoF+pKYRLrRtwzmoZtqbNPttxmCPK0r3fnmBCiM0uTDYi3tTuoq6+We+TMoy0gE7hYI40cZofPKc1qac5US9lUaN2juCS7xoFGiXgsah6Evcr4R4ocWI8TPZ++L82vnB9Z4IbRpAuoVrORlpYBeV/ZtNqGmcwOvOi9uY", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "24e9e4Xh2Br+/pMlEi76xO76dUL5KiIcrHuGXuNkYnT1UanWa+m+3ZZhN1WHiht09DbArLf1/lQBz6ta+YeLcS5PPp9qy9iH2Oj4w2gBMshA2oVq9J8NaP1TyX+SylkMvswAwh8pR7EtqkoH", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> A Critical Evaluation to Phase-IV (1991 onward)", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150101", 
		"question": "25a9ZoXh0BWq5IAjRhHghe78PW7dBnFRom2GEpxLT07ca5j9Luvrx5N0IxyLlBtv+nOGgKD+40EKzfos91W13//xg+CqSpbqICc=", 
		"answer": "27OtZJ3qk9J3fNTN4py41RYB7sXxTfs=", 
		"explanation": "25a9ZoXh0BWq5IAjRhHghe78PW7dBnFRom2GEqVhfH36FKHXYOn7zddzPhydhV47x3jPrKuw8FwZirpV5IuRZGC9fYM2xSRIz7rjTTBkTZ00", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "ful,ly", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150102", 
		"question": "25a9ZoXh0BXm7sUzQhH81vLtMG+QEGEZpnKGQeN9fmfsWLHHLtLB9qhOGGO2zV1u/HLPraKw8UEAguh47ICLYidDf4VriMOd1vDy1zNiKKiqeVVnEBZ0f891bGrV", 
		"answer": "26awaYP21VtlVYP8PjyzW8BTT2owl0Gd", 
		"explanation": "25aLW9H63w/l+5MlEg36xO/6MSvWFmwVqnGEEqFxZGbmUamCTejw3YV0Z12HiRto5nfSprayHn+Wy98U9pVjeHWwoC5USg==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "sh,ar,ed", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150103", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kQ3z54BgXRiy1v73MGbVECIXr3CUEqVhfnXwFLPKfOLrzp8xNEiImV478GPCpKDk5AxNd5AjxrZsdT/RD62eXwLZpg==", 
		"answer": "25a9ZoXh0BXm7sUzQhH81vLtMG+QEGEZpnKGQeGgC8V5Md26OqWVOfXpo4N9", 
		"explanation": "25aLW9H1xBfu5MUmXhHlhen3J2TFBGpRsGuCRqY0cmTnU6LWfa3rx5t4LFnJiVJp93XS44b1+UcdjqQb+oucZC0RPphswNWE0qTx0X9FIIRCe1EXJTS8eWwtkOmxK9kN", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Centrally sponsored schemes", 
		"option_b": "Central and State sponsored schemes", 
		"option_c": "PSU sponsored schemes", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150104", 
		"question": "25a3ZoL61Rz4t5EoV17h0fzrMGbVDXZL41yGXLdmcX3vTefRfuLw2phjIljJnlhz93vDsOXx/l5Pm6cb7ICcfzcRf4xqiMOd1vDy1zFVPIZUiIl99pMLde5FjDaobZTVIepnwWCBKwX2aDqoFzB1hjTXmT6rtoTuKoXooQaBGChUd+vz", 
		"answer": "24GKXbSxHm4A89/yf9ZfF9Op1Z8h7g==", 
		"explanation": "25aLW9H23xrl4pchVRuy1un+IW7DQ3Ye42+RW6xmeWXqTqKCZejniZlwM1WGg1p3snLDtaD8+EMCiqZPqYiQczcQPop9zdGalYGE7AWkwwyXn1LPAFqf1BQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "TRUE", 
		"option_b": "FALSE", 
		"option_c": "Partially True", 
		"option_d": "Partially False", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150105", 
		"question": "25u3epzy3VnJ8os0QB/+hdzsJmLDF2MfoHrDRqw0Y2XiQKLRLuTtiZN0M1mbgFJ193KGoaTj8ldPgKYb/YaaMB08QbRQ9++2ldO7t3Z5xYVznoE0BMET/Mg=", 
		"answer": "25K5bJb63VTH4o4oVwz4wPi/M2TCDncdoj3fDT5mR6T4BY1f04qmL/Xz", 
		"explanation": "25u3epzy3VnJ8os0QB/+hdzsJmLDF2MfoHrDW7A0cX3vW6TDeuj6iYN+Z0+djE9+4TbEorb18xMAgehP4YvfVyMHeYJjhf2c3Ozy1ntENoZClZJ/8ZYePgSBmsdT5gf9zdHBdGrcYnc=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Ga,dg,il-M,ukh,er,je,e fo,rm,ula", 
		"option_b": "", 
		"option_c": "", 
		"option_d": "", 
		"quiz_type": "fillup", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150106", 
		"question": "25S8bJjn2Bbk9olgcRv80e/+OSvxEHEYsGuCXKBxMHjwFLfQYfv3zZJ1Z1qGnxts+n/Fq+Xk7kMKz6ddqZ6NfygGfZ98l5KkYo693o7qGvwE+3Lvn0S0", 
		"answer": "25CgfJTh3xjm+5xgUxf2wPm9VkjY1pIpXloYXGbUlqzTZA==", 
		"explanation": "25S8bJjn2Bbk9olgcRv80e/+OSvxEHEYsGuCXKBxMHf2WqPRLsjm3ZJjKV2FgUI703/CpqGwx0EAha1Y/Z3drKXlkDpWW7xqHzD8fttRpA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "CSS", 
		"option_b": "CPSU", 
		"option_c": "Externally aided", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150107", 
		"question": "24aobZL60BWq1IAuRgzzyb3eJnjZEHYQrXyGEqpnMHbqQqLMLvnxiYB5Ll+BzVh65nPBrLfpt1wJz7tP6JqaY31BnXbuLLZcycd/iilcvEiDgw==", 
		"answer": "24aobZL60BWq9IQ0Vxn91+S9rak8Jn99NXLHqx0sfdeZLQ==", 
		"explanation": "24aobZL60BWq1IAuRgzzyb3eJnjZEHYQrXyGEqpnMGHxW7HLauj6iYN+Z2+ZiFhy83qGgKTk8lQAnbEb2pqeZCcQPL2Tp48xKBDxtgZhcdn9hIQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "general category", 
		"option_b": "Special category", 
		"option_c": "large", 
		"option_d": "small", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150108", 
		"question": "25iIRLDX4lns4oskQV7i1/LpPG/VByIFrD+QRqJgdWKjVbXHLuy+z5hjKhyGixts+nfS47Hp51ZPgK4b6J2MeTEXf4VszY/LaJIzMFEYFXGA3/ZAD9bnIQ==", 
		"answer": "25a9ZoXh0BWq9pYzWw3mxPP8MCmEw0ay1n6HbGOUee2Bu87d", 
		"explanation": "25iIRLDX4lns4oskQV7xyvPsIWLEFnYU41yGXLdmcX2jVbTRZ/7qyJlyIhyPgkk79nPQpqn/514KgbwZ7HQP/yazCl/sZAcuVfkZnA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Central assistance", 
		"option_b": "State Assistance", 
		"option_c": "Private Assistance", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150109", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz1BX58sUhQBuy9/jsIXnFAHYEsXqHEoBHQzHnXbHLauj6iZZhJk6dzV1p/XuGrLXk/lwBjqQb+o2XdS8GbdQtpmlkHLZyTb+2OI/jtE9oIw==", 
		"answer": "27a3epSx2VaBK0N2N39w9Udi4ElASQ==", 
		"explanation": "25aLW9Hywxyq9YwmRwzxxOn6MSvZDXYe43yMQKY0cX/nFKjSeuTxx5Z9Z0+KhV5292WGoqPk8kFPna1I/ZyKczYWbIJhz5IyNGfSqu/71ONSukmWxfeK", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "general", 
		"option_b": "core", 
		"option_c": "supplementary", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150110", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEhjny/n2O2yQE2MFt3qRXONkYn7zW7THaq34xoUxJFObiBtYwUWZ4Q+kcC//qEPHBFFxhgt68gI=", 
		"answer": "2+PoMsWjkR/l5cUnVxD31/zzdXjEAnYUsD2FhVn+l23RWfkMuS5t88CL", 
		"explanation": "25a3epSz8irZt40hRBuyk62lYTuQBXcfp3aNVeN2dWX0UaLMLs77x4NjIhyIg1879XPIprfx+xMMjrxe7oGNaWIQaop7zcPLqd4iDlany8mIM8XGzDNZhQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "50:50 for general states", 
		"option_b": "60:40 for general states", 
		"option_c": "40:60 for general states", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150111", 
		"question": "25y2KIX71Fnp+Is0VwbmhfL5dWTAF2serX6PEoBHQzHxUbTWfPj93YJjLlKOwRts+nfS46j19FsOgaFI5M6afTIMaY5925Caw+XjwWIBJM9QksB07YkcffgAyjGobN3ZKfJn2nfAM0qwZjWxC3N1gDSWjGlYrJD79yKvQ98yzlUhlY994M0vY5Vw6l4eu/QHf0t48I7GSTzE", 
		"answer": "24W3eoXy0xDm/pE5EhH0hf/qMWzVF2MDuj+CXq97c3D3XajMfa84chxzEt9ochughSlsRxm+", 
		"explanation": "24asaYX2wlnr5YBgVxD2yur6MSvHCnYZ42uLV+NkYnTxW6DDeuTozNdlKBydn1p14XDDseXy4lcIirxa+5ffcS4PcYhu3NmG2fe3xnRVJMNBlMBk5YgWc+FTjC6ufNHWJe0u22CEIlewaCmpDX96lT2WqU9l6JG+5jOpQdkj1Qc7mIA4+cAuM8KY0eiH4Ej4hQmM336BXP1rFxSJuty86kGVrIssrI25uTvItP33lPfF8coCdA0SvpZvcVS9lKBJ/SQwUMa3bQEL5ezVaEatJiGtJgAe8MrvlnV80o0nUmQttB5IhsNFdtJywp3jtTFwPsFmGjC7t01PydR/XgeXdrS02Xz9oiEIqQoznIkKuKJuR12xaM4=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Fiscal reallocation", 
		"option_b": "Budgetary decentralization", 
		"option_c": "Fiscal autonomy", 
		"option_d": "Portability of budgetary allocations", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150112", 
		"question": "24KwbZ+zxhj5t5EoV17by/n6JW7eB2cftz+mRKJ4ZXD3XajMLsL4z55yIhzBpH5UuzbVprGw4kNQzSZNO2oAVd2O2nY1Ypb/rws=", 
		"answer": "y+XpPOKdtkBJHQ8TJFBnyOqOTQY=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa9Daq4IQzEhvh0fz9OWLDC2cV432aErd8dTHkW7HHfOPzzJllZ1WHzX1+8GTTorfptwFf3vwZazkEeCv8loY5IXVdAjuVFQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": 2012, 
		"option_b": 2013, 
		"option_c": 2014, 
		"option_d": 2015, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150113", 
		"question": "24GwbdHa9Daq4IQzEg330b3qJSvSAnEUpz+MXONxaGHmRq7HYO772td3NVOEzUxz+3XO46r2t0cHiuhd5oKTfzUKcIwvy9+c2fDlzXRSc/pKy8Bf4YIWf/sA8DP/NOHwYMJgnS61FGSwWzfpREd7hj3Syl5XpoiH+xCzXdk/gBo01pNw6Ig9PtiJ3OiS+kj4hQmQzn6SXOcmORCCNku+GD6Fl9enM0FQyQ==", 
		"answer": "2+f4aZ/3kU2ou//Q2AbZiGVbdoMovrUDhg==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa9Daq4IQzEhP9wfjzMG+QDGxRjnqbW6B7N2KjUbHDYvj/3Z5+KRyGi11y8XOGoqv0t0AKm+hO+c6IeTYLPopmzJCPxev6hERqc8dKnsBF64gTeLRizTOmNvGVwRdn1Lf+2auTm7eR6HI=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 3", 
		"option_b": "1 and 4", 
		"option_c": "2 and 4", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150114", 
		"question": "24KwaYWz2Aqq440lEgz9yfi/Om2QF2oU41amffw0TH+yFILUb+HryIN0Z1uGm15p/HvDrbGw50EAiLpa5J3fTCxRPqJi2MKGweG3xXJCPNNKjoFw7ZYWaO0A8DP+NPPOKfprjmuWJknlZi20C340mTTCgnNSp4+08i6+R5oLzkFytJJx4cx8OcGe1b2S/ES3iEaB3WuQSrRoGECQsN2U5XSUqYEw9cKL8SbT8bT4mPfF9Z4KcA0SvIltcV6/g+ga7CssVMWxZgZYq6av8xs5OocvWMdmm5kZkKtV", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHa9Daq8pMhXgvz0fjsdXvCDGUDonKQHuNzZXjnUbSCY+jqwZh1KFCGilJ+4TbHraGw/l4fnadN7J3fcSEAcZ5h3NGL3uj+0GgDZja8hsxQy00fIHdsrGVpBA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150115", 
		"question": "24GwbdHq1Bj4t9R5B0yyyPztPm7UQ2NRsHaEXKpyeXLiWrOCY+TyzIRlKFKMzUxy5n6Gt631t1Ycm6lZ5YeMeC8GcJ8vx9bJw+zyhEFTPMFWm41/4do6avVM2Ty5fdvVYNF8yW+OLlbxczCyCjA8pBT5wzAWv4uy9i/7RNY22RA21oY47topP96e1eiB50G9xg+MnFKfTLRlVkfZssG+7lGSoYw7sI2BsDzf5/f4iv2T8sdLZB1euY9zb1KykOge8CM7WYikfQBb/vfVPhZ7Vg3sGcHOLDg7lrGVQRoN", 
		"answer": "24ahe4X23Bj+/oZgVwjzyej+IWLfDSIepT+TQKxzYnDuR+Uol0dUBvSG6nNufloNRnf5", 
		"explanation": "25y2KMCqhEumt5EoV17C1/L4J2rdDmdRhmmCXrZ1ZHjsWuftfOr/x55iJkiAglU7ukbjjOyw4FIcz65U/ICbdSZPPphmz96I2+35wzFAc81Bg8Bh8J8PPOBP2zy/cJTeNvdqy2CDIgjyZiq4ADBzmyfTmHJXpoC+uWe+Wts1zBw8kcdr9NsoOdqezaGQqEiuhwqX3W+YR7MkHlLZssG+7lGSrYc2oY2doz3c5vX0ibjH/54ObABTsYV6I0+0kqEbuC8+V8G3YRdF8v2QYFrpYC2lIQse7cL103ps1ZFrbV4rK0ByNiBLatU3+1iP6A==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Improved financial management", 
		"option_b": "Systematic evaluation of programs", 
		"option_c": "Effective resource allocation", 
		"option_d": "Administrative decentralization", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150116", 
		"question": "25S0Z5/0whDu8sUlRB/+0PzrPGXXQ3IDrHiRU65nMHfsRufPZ+P32oNjLlmawRtv+nOGk7f/8EEOgqVeqauJcS4Wf59mx97J+PbwxX9IIMdQk498pNIvWdsJjDyhZ9ubNfBqy3yUKEr7JzyrBXxhlSXfhXJF6IW052esXNM0yFUhgpV5+c07NdTf3KaH4Vmh2UTWi35AC3COyuUf/ESyoxjN", 
		"answer": "24W0aZ/92Bftt6YvXxP71u72OmWSBpZYculOxbTphLLzJwd1Bw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHDwxbt5YQtXxuy4Ov+OX7RF2serT+sQKR1fnjwVbPLYeO+gadUCBXJnVd663PC46Sw9EEajKFa5c6Nfy4GPoJhiNWf1ujixWVIPcEEipJ944gececAyjK/NNnSLvd92nyJIlawZje5RGR8kXHmhn1Ypoq18meYW9c6yQYhn4h2oYgoNNKN3KqKqE63iBKQ1XmEXLRqFhSNuo6pq0CTrZIqsMWIvyHS4vG5m+vA9c0Ybw1cq8ZwZRusmKQA+yM9Qoi1ZhYL+OrZdV3sNCG1Ih1d+Mjx2Wd6hpQoT2A74QwGkYZVds9hxdpO2jTr31rWr2XFVQaXGPsc", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Planning Commission", 
		"option_b": "Finance Commission", 
		"option_c": "Economic Commission", 
		"option_d": "Development Commission", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150117", 
		"question": "24GwbdHDwxbt5YQtXxuy4Ov+OX7RF2serT+sQKR1fnjwVbPLYeO+gadUCBXJjF904mLV46Sw+kYDm6EW/YeaYicHPph72sWKw/HlwTFVPIZCj4x07ZYTPP1U332idt7eI+pn2GuTZ23/cHmwBX5t1DzXg3IWu5ep4CSvQcgy01U2mYJrrdw0OZev/IfU+w23lAGD0nKLSaltHlqYuY6u+UKRpZU3p8bNtDzY+/npm+vAr5z52jXSBY2IeC1g7DGtz+Rp", 
		"answer": "yvwnKJ+ujOLGzJfJDbSUHkw=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHDwxbt5YQtXxuy4Ov+OX7RF2serT+sQKR1fnjwVbPLYeO+gadUCBXJi1565mPUpraw9hMMgKVL+4uXdSwQd51qiN+b0OX5zWtAJ89LlIF+pJwNfflF2zK/f5TYL/N+3GeTLkv3Jy21FnVx1DzXg3IWu5ep4CSvQcgy009ynoJ56dkpPcWL3LqApA2qgwGL03WQRP1rF1KQtsu7pwOdroZ4s8SIvTab4frwjuufsNgKYQFetpJ+d1KykOgM/iw9Uty9fhcL9PLRbUHsNCGsKU4N68Tg02d6w5FpXH108BZAhIZEZ85nlpngsTs+Nt5+BzKuqlJFh5h5SRKaZ/+jGwhcNAW50r7jBKq94efz", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": 2, 
		"option_b": 3, 
		"option_c": 4, 
		"option_d": 5, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150118", 
		"question": "24GwbdHDwxbt5YQtXxuy4Ov+OX7RF2serT+sQKR1fnjwVbPLYeO+gadUCBXJiENv93jCsOX540BPna1a6obfZCoRcZ5owJCP3uH7wDFUPc9QicBh7Y4KfeBFyH2kepTNIexnwXuTZ1bkZi24FzBdmnHehWsWpYK17Ge2VdA40lUhgoZs6Nt8PdSN1ruAqGS2gg+DnHqDTf1wGVGKsI6u4kaQpMItu8SZonLX+/f4jv3Xr5y6RiUTiNvWBVBFK93pev17", 
		"answer": "wZOe1a3yQ7jjcD6t65k8Lx8=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHDwxbt5YQtXxuy4Ov+OX7RF2serT+sQKR1fnjwVbPLYeO+gadUCBXJhVposnPVt6Ty+1och61fqYiWdS4HPp5hwcSal+35hCkBIM9DlIl07ZkecuAA3ymsYNHIYP9t3GGTNAXZaT20BTw0hyXEi2hTr4q49Cu3TZonzwY7go5348EyO5eWzbuW5Ev4kgnC33SfTKhnBRSNvcG65FabqMI9o8yBpDPP/fv3ibjS/tpLYQlCq5NtZhu4nr4M6jk9EdqxbxtE/+XcIUToMjuzIg0J8N3mxTYk06+MEkz4czGusKcAB8Yc", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": 5, 
		"option_b": 6, 
		"option_c": 8, 
		"option_d": 10, 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150119", 
		"question": "24GwbdHDwxbt5YQtXxuy4Ov+OX7RF2serT+sQKR1fnjwVbPLYeO+gadUCBXJiFVz83jFpraw/kccz6Za/YeQfjUKeo4v2MKMxOH5x3QBJ85WlZV17NoNefNJwzOseJTeNv9i22+ULkr+Jza7Anl3kSKWonNB6I66+z77R880yFUgk4Bx4sY9MJeaz6mf/UysjwmMnHSXTrRnFEfZscGt+AOIqId4heii8T3L8eb4jv2MsnrVgD68AW1PRF6ySuT2zDk=", 
		"answer": "2+L4a5jn2Bz5tZDZni1sQrBFcajyAW8kK3g=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHDwxbt5YQtXxuy4Ov+OX7RF2serT+sQKR1fnjwVbPLYeO+gadUCBXJi0518WLPrKvjt0cHnadO7obfJ2IRe4xmx96I26Ty0nBNJsdQk498pJUZev1DyS7hNMfLMvtvyi6BJFf/dCr9D3Vt1D3ZiX1CoYy15meyWpoezhE7l8s468k/NduWzamH4UO/xgWN0WuDTbVhH0eQo8vo+1GTp5A5uI2MoiHe5+f0n/bH454KbAwSuINxZkm9g6EH/2ouUMShaRBH9KTZb0fkJyC3NEwl4frw+7tw2VSabKChFH7C", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "7 cities", 
		"option_b": "3 cities", 
		"option_c": "4 cities", 
		"option_d": "8 cities", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150120", 
		"question": "25y2KJD/2B7k+oAuRl7lzOn3dX/YBiIlpnGXWuNEfHDtE7SCfujs2od0JEiAm143snPQoqnl9kcGgKYb/o+MMDIRcZtg29WNl/D4hHNEc89KjoV19psLefAAxTO5e5TMKPdtxi6CNUrxY3m7FnF5kSbZmHcWvIz78CmzVdQ0xVUmnoI46M46NdSe2rHT50v4ggOU2XeeWLBhH0DZvMCh/0qdtIsusN7S85NxtlOj8CxhTQ8Btlpd8jg=", 
		"answer": "26W0aZ+zwhri8oglEJoFJAk0CY6XgPH7BKVJj0k=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bf+/8UQXh/8hfjyJWPREGsLpnvDRqtxMHDuVavFb+D/3Z5+KRyGixt+5HfKtqTk/lwBz6FV/YHfZCoGPptjyd7JxOf/wXxEf4ZQkoVg4ZgGPPFNzjipcN3VJ759132UIkjxczC+RHVilT3Di2hfp4375TW6V84+wxAh1o52+cd8Fdmb0KnU+w28gxCH0HSBRbhqBRSKodyp/0abucIsuo2IvyHO5vG5jvDWsNsNZAFRvoVmI1qyk+gG7T47XsWxe1JE96TGYEbkLz2wZwoY787v2WRkw4w9XGV05A1JiIZVdtMx8O8Ow/dEnXEM4G2U68vhfQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "plan scheme", 
		"option_b": "finance scheme", 
		"option_c": "development scheme", 
		"option_d": "None of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150121", 
		"question": "25T4e4H20hDr+4w6VxqywOv+OX7RF2serT+QUatxfXSjQ6bRLuvx25pkK12diF875nmGpqv49l0MiuhM4YeceGIQbo5swdaA1KT212FEMNIElYYy45UJeeZOwTijYJTUMPt8z3qJKEvjOHv4F/hrzLnNp5quVNTFrKog", 
		"answer": "27CuaZ3m0A3j+ItgUR/ixP/2OWLECmcC4bqrXh0CSvDN7US7C5/H72s=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHwwxzr44wvXF79w73+dW/VB2sSomuGVuNxZnDvQabWZ+LwiYRyL1mEiBt6+3vDp+Xk+BMNgKRI/YuNMCcVf4d6ycSA2Oq3x3BRMsRNlolm7Z8MPOdJyzOkct3eM756xmvAIkjgbziuDWM0mz+Wg3FGuoyt/Cm8FM4/xVU1mZF9/8YxOdmLnrvT60yohwWLyGLRXLIkEluXsdur/wOfr48op8iFtDzI/eL82vnd9J4OZA5XvJJ2dV78kr4I9D85RcG7ZgEL/uKQd1X/KSe2NE4N68TkxHVk1cIoU2105BBKi4BfZ9MxLR0KByJ4KgnuSDVo1VqTwA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "accountability", 
		"option_b": "transparency", 
		"option_c": "funds allocation", 
		"option_d": "evaluation capabilities", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150122", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRLv7sUpXA3mzOnqIWLfDSIGomzDQbZ3c3TmUKLGLu/niYN5IhyPgkl282LPrKuw+FVPoYFvwM6+cTsMectmxpDbh7WiiDFJNtRFloR76p1ffbRQzS+scN3cLb59xmeGMwX5aXmUCnR9lXbFymxaqY21/Cm8FNs5xFU1mZF9/8Y9MtSamaSS5kmrhQeS2STTd/pMJcdlvShJLpwStDUrOw==", 
		"answer": "24W0aZ/92Bftt6YvXxP71u72OmWSBpZYculOxbTphLLzJwd1Bw==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdH2wg3r9YkpQRb/wPPrdWTWQ0w4l1bDc6Jtf3ajXamCPL2vnNd8Jk6CiF875n7D47f1518OjK1W7ICLMC0FPp9nzZCMxffj03lIP8MEqoxz6pQWcvMA7zKged3IM/dhwCLANEz3aTC7HXl6k3HXynhTuIKp4TKpUZox0ho/1pNw6IgoLtab0Lya50O5ikaS0HqfRrRqFhSYpd665EKfqMIsuo2M8T/U5vG5mfff/N8JbRpTq49pZhu9maxJ/DM2UMW9a1JG/uDVbRTiJmikKBgY68Xi2HdshAHRsfhF8wqAFMg4prsiWn4=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Finance Commission", 
		"option_b": "NDC", 
		"option_c": "Planning Commission", 
		"option_d": "Administrative Commission", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150123", 
		"question": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJsEh+y0e/+O3jWDHAcomuKRKY0eX/wQK7We/n3xpk9Z12FhFx14TbPt7aw8VwMmrsb/oeLeGIXdo4vy9iI2eP+ynYBPcNBnpMy65xfa/xJzzXtccLULOhnwGnAIUTzYi39C3Y0vT/Sg30J6lzny4wAhDF5q2MLw/AFID0=", 
		"answer": "25u9f9Ha3x3j9scB8rkMk+DS8ye/PEm+1Pev", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgWw2ywfj7PGjRF2cV42uMEqB1ZHTxXanFLvnxiYN5IhyNlFV6/3/F46T+8xMKmadX/4eRd2IRe5p6wcKM2uH50GIBPMAEjoh3pI4NffpTyjK/edHfYNBr2S6pKUH5ZnX9AX1knDDFg2ZfpoT7/Cm1W8w21Bw9mMs45MY/MMKM0L6a/FT0xgeM2DuCXa5wEF2XtMyk7gOYpZQ9ucKdvDfV4LZU7XNhFTd/uMPZy+2wPjLl", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Modern India", 
		"option_b": "Developed India", 
		"option_c": "Emerging India", 
		"option_d": "New India", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150124", 
		"question": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgWh/hhf/6MGWQAWcCt3CUV6c0Z3j3XOfDLun32oN4KV+dhE1+smTJr6C8t1EKhqZcqYqaYyERd4lqzJCIxKTjzHQBD4RGn5NmpJwNdfFOyAHvNNvdYOlmx22IZ0bicjq0BXw0kT/Cg2hfrZD74i6vXNM5gDw8ko55qtt8O9iJ3Lqd6UO7g0aRyGmES6lxA1HG90JzDDI0bHJOy5covfmZjvE=", 
		"answer": "24asaYX2wlt7KDFTyZpCQ+VyiJ0LBJjx", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJnQV7/xPP7NH/VQ2sftXCPRKZnMHDgQK7Maa3/2tdlL1nJsRl592XS46Pi/lYBi5QZqZqQMBEXf59q25CIw6TjzHQBEMNKjpJ3qNoLdPFSyT+0NNLUM+pr3GeOIAXzaDatAWJ1gDjZhDAWq4y3+Sa5W8g21Bw9mMs47MY4fNKZ362Q/ESug0aS03eYS6QkEluWp8qh5UKIqY029c+IpSXe8fq5jvDWsN0ObBxAvoo/YlW417sd+T49Ec+7fhdZ/+nVb0D+YnK88ssd40ACANrt28A2fis=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Central Government", 
		"option_b": "States", 
		"option_c": "Bureaucracy", 
		"option_d": "Corporate Entities", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150125", 
		"question": "24KwZ9H73hXu5MU0Whuywfi/M2rTF21Rs3CQW7d9f3+jW6GCTeX/wIV8JlLJhFU73F/yiuXR9koAiOQb+YKeaSsNectuiMCAwevjxX0BIclIn8B76toYaf1ExTOqNMDTJb5nwH2ULlHlczCyCjdn1CffmXVZpsO6+yP7R84lwQE3kY57rcw1LtKczaGc5hL6gljOQowrz4ob12Gh/WRxFw==", 
		"answer": "24WqYZz2kTTj+YwzRhvgh3V1OK4NfvHPiCsddrwc43c=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHDwxDn8sUNWxD71un6JyvfAGEEs3aGQeNgeHSjUKKCaOz93ZgxNVOFiBt09Dblq6T55V4OgehS586xWRYqPqpu0d+Om6TkzXZPOsBdk451pI4XebRMyTypccbIKPd+iX3AJkbkbi+4RHl6gj7anHlbrY2vtS61FMk/wQU7mIA47MY4fMSL3K2B4UO/xhKK2TuYRq5wGECMocen5QSP4IM/sMOJsHDWiybGV9p2PL7RlH840/OB", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "President", 
		"option_b": "Prime Minister", 
		"option_c": "Finance Minister", 
		"option_d": "Chief Justice", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150126", 
		"question": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgVxDkzO72OmXDQ3YZpj+XQKJ6Y3fsRqrDeuTxx9d+IRygg19y8zbPrbH/t1JPhKZU/oKadCUGM4Jh3NWHxO3hwTFAPcIEk45864weaP1WyX2+e9fSJep3gi6UL0DiYjukRGBmmyHThnBfpoT7/DP7QNUgwQc2hcdv5cE/NJeb0LqW61mxiQjdnmlAjN6VZct6MFSaX8PLJFE=", 
		"answer": "2762Z4b/1B3t8sUlURH8yvDmd0fU+49HkkwM0xloJCZlduo=", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJnQV7kzO72OmWQCnFRoHqNRqZmdXWjW6mCfv/x2ZJ9K1WHihtS/HLPouXk+EQOnaxIqYyacy0Od4VoiNHJ3Or4031EN8FB14Jz958bPPFDwzOiec2bIfBqjn2PJEz1cyDxRHZ7hyXTmHVYr8Oy+ym0QtsjyRo82sdq6Ns5PcWc0eTT6UO8xhKH33OfR7FrFl2atMLo6keKoYw7sMCIvybItokwMOUmpFA6TXBbDp94t/8=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "industrialized economy", 
		"option_b": "agrarian economy", 
		"option_c": "service-based economy", 
		"option_d": "knowledge economy", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150127", 
		"question": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgQgz9yPLrMHiQAiIXsX6OV7R7YnqjQK/Deq37x5R+Mk6Iil5osnXJrLX15VIbhr5eqY+RdGIAcYZ/zcSAw+3hwTFFKshFl4lx99odeeBXyTijNMDTJb5ty2CUNUT8JzizADBngDDCjzxRp5W+5ym2UdQj01UGno5rrc4uPdqazqeB4w2xlUaJ0nSGRv1lAg7bZG4lTEO4TpZagWFTjqJwkw==", 
		"answer": "27O9bJTh0BXj5IhiUy2WoHxCJC+hiIFmvxuNEA==", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJnQV7z1e3tOmrTCyIFrD+FXbBgdWPqWqCCbeLyxZZzKE6ImVJ0/DbHraGw9FwCn61P4JqWfyxDfI5739WM2aTjzHQBMMNKjpJz6NoecvAA3ymsYNGbJ/F4y3yOKkD+cyr9DWM0hjTQj25ErYf74Sj7Vcl3wxo9hoJq7Nw1KtLf362X7V+5ig+R0TfRTbB0GVWKvNSh5UTcs4o5p8iJ8TXU4vHrlPnd89tLYwZW/4VwbEm4nqYI7C88EcyxaxtY+OveLFnsKyGtIExqj4bmbr6+gtneTdd1fMkL", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "funding", 
		"option_b": "planning", 
		"option_c": "evaluation", 
		"option_d": "federalism", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150128", 
		"question": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgWhH+we6/IWPVQ20XpXaAW6J4MHXmR67FYOzqwJh/Z1OPzVl++3jB46Sw5EMKjKFa5YeFdSZDe4V7wcSQl9P/xWUBJ8NWl8Bw4YkLPPBF3z6/fdbeM756xmvAMkv5diy4RGJ7mDSWhXoWhqqP3GeaVcM4x1U7mMdR48w1PZCMma+c/kiqiAeM337RRLxqFUeatN6ttAGZBAcIYLVIZP8LA986rRL2", 
		"answer": "24GwYZ/4kS3r+Y5iAZDhJF/71auxRphm96ftbg==", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgVAv8xun2OmXDQ2MC437DVqZweXLiQKLGLurx35JjKVGMg087xn7Pra6ww1IBhOQb6I2LeTQGcpIvzd6O1uPywDFIPYZWn5N35YgcdLgA3DKhfdfCYPhh3GOVK0TkbjazSDB1mjWWgXJZv4++8SC+FN4+0wY3m4527Nw1M9nTmauc5lmqjwSXyHKfT/1wHhSQu8in+U6ZpMI8sM6EojvU+rn0m/Pa/tlJPL29BrbluoupnNy1QZaVAQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "1", 
		"option_a": "Action Unit", 
		"option_b": "Research Foundation", 
		"option_c": "Strategy Center", 
		"option_d": "Think Tank", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150129", 
		"question": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJnQV7i1/TyNHnJQ2QeoGqQEqBxfmXmRrSCb//x3Jl1Z1qIjlJ3+2LHt6z+8BMbh60b4IOPfCcOe4V7ycSA2Oq3y3cBJM5NmYgy55UNebRFwDigcdrPYPFojmmPMUDiaTizB3U41CXej25Tqpr78CmoQcg+zhJyk4F+6MsoNcGambic5ES7n0aHxH6SXaltHlrG9/rmd7Qhu7YWBZnFUPXG3Q4=", 
		"answer": "25y1eJ323Bzk44Q0WxH8hz45W5vj5+H2NK1cSx7PDc0=", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJnQV7i1/TyNHnJQ3Aer3rDW7A0ZH6jUqbBZ+H33ZZlIhydhV474XvJrLH4t1oCn6Re5IuRZCMXd4RhiN+Pl/T4yHhCOsNX1sBi9pUYbvVN33HtddrfYPdgx3qJJlH5cTyuSDBxmiLDmHVYr8Ov/SavFM4/xVU3mJFx/sEzMtKbma+c6UGrxgeQ2TuFWrxqAliYocusq0qStI14tsKDsiDe4PG5m/vH+dEFcUhTsYI/bE6olKcE/Tl6pkhneKd/CvpZ4WyLJa77mQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Innovation", 
		"option_b": "Planning", 
		"option_c": "Implementation", 
		"option_d": "Regulation", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150130", 
		"question": "25y8bZ/n2B/zt5EoV172wPDwMnnRE2oYoD+AWqJ6d3TwFKHDbeTwztdYKViAjBxosmbKoqv+/l0Iz7tS542aMAsNeo5/zd6N0ur0wSt9PZcEqo9i8ZYeaP1Pwn2qZtvMNPYu2mHAKFP1dXnsRHJ9mD3fhXJqptH73Cm4Rt820xA21pJq78kyNc2ezaGc5nG21Uau3WmWTf19HkGNvY645FOJrIMsvMKDjTyPtNj2jf3BsNMEcBxTs49rehuulrwM6xY2ZsC9axoL/uKQdVzoYCmhKBgYucrx0zRqyZA7WGogtAxSg5dTb8V9wou+/vYPWWSueAxDAaP9QG4xaXA=", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJjylgqq54owRxLz0fTwOyvYAnFRpG2MRa00f2fmRueRdqG+3IVzJlKAl1pv+3nI46z+9EEKjrte7c6efiZDZ4R63NjJx+vn0X1AMMMEn5hi5ZQbefAC/tGJHHmTFVKyZVTolamGDA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 4", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150131", 
		"question": "25y2bJjylgqq0JcvQQ2y4fLyMHjECmFRk22MVrZ3ZDGrc4PyJ632yIQxMFWdg15o4XPC47bl9UAbjqZP4I+TMCURcZx7wJCa3ur0wTFIPcJBioV84J8Rf/EMjC64ZtPSLvkuyHyPKgXCdHnsVDwkxGGWiW5Zuob74Sj7UcI0xRA21pBw7Nx8PdqQzKaHqES2xgWQ02mUF/9XYi0yO8i0JO0ibLCUVv4v", 
		"answer": "2+ToONH/0BLit4YyXQz3h/YGCPiMx3fdhKY4XzYtGzI=", 
		"explanation": "25y2bJjylgqq0KEQEhbz1r37MGbfDXEFsX6XV6c0YnTuVbXJb+/yzNd2NVOemVM3snPVoKT89kcGga8b75yQfWIxbcs+mJzZh7S3x2NOIcMEjo8y948NbPVT3325fNGbLfFg22OFKVHxa3m/AX53nDzXmHcWp4X7xzT7BYpngBkznY847tozLtLTmbqW7kG9hRKL0nzRXLVhUVqYocen5QSP4Ic7usOCvDvYtOTrlf/B9c0YIGaYW9yPAhq2qIp2RzoXVtg=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 lakh crore", 
		"option_b": "10 lakh crore", 
		"option_c": "50 lakh crore", 
		"option_d": "100 lakh crore", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150132", 
		"question": "24GwbdHWxxbm4pEpXRCyyvu/IWPVQ3IDqmmCRqY0Y3TgQKjQIq39wZZjJl+diEly6HPC46fpt0AGiKZS74eccSwXPo532NGHxO34yjFAPcIEnYx95psTPPdPwS2oYN3PKehrwGuTNAmwaTy+AWNnnSXXnnlF6Jez8Ge6UNUn1Bw9mMd364gyOcDfyaSS5kOxiAHCz2+DSalhFl2cpo685AOZpoQ9ttmEpzfX7bT4nvzB9c0YIh9atoV3I16xkroO8SQ/Ecu8aR5H9OrXZAuva74sGDIs73RH/QxZOp5y3w==", 
		"answer": "24W3ZJjwyFnr55UyXR/xzfjsd711b3ezUnlgdyhvcLAKcxs=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHnwxjk5IMvQBPz0fTwOyvfBSIFq3rDQrF9ZnD3UefRa+7qxoU9Z1GIn1B+9jbEuuX540BPnL1Z+pqefjYKf4cvz8KGwPD/hHBPN4ZBlIhz6pkaeLRHwDKvddibI/Fj3muULlH5cTyzAWNn2HHei28WuJG0+DevUd531B031ol96Mx8OtiNmaac/ki0xhaN0HKSUf1lAUSLus+r40aP4JYwtNnNsjPVtPf4jv3BsMoEIhxausZ6dVSwgaEH/2o0UMawexFK4eGQblKtJSusKQEQ8Mij13d9z5QgSWAx519HjIcWa853w4vwrjs1LI9S72oh1N27j4tOwbZVLCMS", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Technological advancements", 
		"option_b": "Social equity", 
		"option_c": "Environmental sustainability", 
		"option_d": "Policy approaches", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150133", 
		"question": "24GwbdHxxAvt8oouWxD1hfzsJWLCAnYYrHGQEqxyMHLqQK7Ya+PtiZJ8N1SInlJh9zbSq6Cw81YCjqZfqYiQYmICPox9zdGd0va3wn5CJtUElY4y85IWf/wAxzi0NNXIMPtt2i6PIQX3aC+4Fn51mjLTxjxGuoy25TOyWt13wVUhno5++Yg1MpeL0a3T6V2olAmD33PRXLIkAVuVvM2xq0WTso8tucyZuD3VtPX3nrja/c4HZwVXsZJ+d1KzmfdLhM572cH+BpkP7rzOLeBr4A==", 
		"answer": "25O3a4TgkRbkt4o1Rh39yPjsdWreByIDpmyWXrdnMguqITcpVNxxsCOqleVQ2ec=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHh2Arj+YJgUw3izO/+IWLfDXFRrHnDUapgeWvmWrSCe+P6zIViJFObiBtv+nOGqqjg+EEbjqZY7M6QdmITcopswd6Ol+W3w2NEMtJBiMB36YoXfedJ332iepTPKPsuz22UMkT8JzaoEHN7mTTFyn1YrMOp8DSuWM4kgBo01pd34cE/NdKMmamd7A2xiA+W1XqFQathAhjZu8ur7lCPqZY5ocSDtnLatOfxk/7HsNgZbQUSq5R+Z1KonqcH+SZ4WMakfQYG8+XDZFCtITizNQEc+sPmxTbBDFYAxAcdF+mEwSDLAFAg", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Resource allocation", 
		"option_b": "Administrative efficiency", 
		"option_c": "Focus on outputs", 
		"option_d": "Focus on outcomes and results", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150134", 
		"question": "25i5YJDn3Biq0IQuVhb7gu6/ImLDB20c422GVaJmdHjtU+fWZui+7IF+K0mdhFR1snnA46z+5EcGm71P4IGRY2IKcMt9zcOZ2OrkwTFVPIZHkoF845MRe7RUxTCoZ5TTIe0uzGuFKQXzbi24ADB1h3HXyntDoYey+yD7RMg+zhY7hot9rc4zLpeL0a3T/F+5iBWE02mcSaltHlrZusjo/EuVo4p4vsiU8TvV5+Dwju3H+dEFIgFc/69xZ1K90LtJ/yUuVNq6aRxI9KTWc1XgJT+sNQVCu637XRQcI53TZ+hRlGj7RoY=", 
		"answer": "24W0aZ/92Bftt6YvXxP71u72OmWSBpZYculOxbTphLLzJwd1Bw==", 
		"explanation": "24StZ4X63x6q2oQoUwr/xL3YNGXUC2td42uLV+Nzf2fmRqnPa+PqiZ94IFSFhFxz5nPC47H48hMBiq1fqYiQYmIKcJh7wcScw+34ymIBJ8kEn5Z96IwaPONJ2DXtd9zaLvlnwGnAM0z9YirxRGB1hiXfiWlaqZG37GeyWpojyBBylYh2+c0kKJeQ3+iB7V20hwWL0nzRXLVhUWSVtMCm4k2b4KE3uMCEoiHS+/q5jfHH+J4lSzx7/6d+elS72+gb/Sw0VMugYRxMsfDYZBTpOSaiKgcO9Ivs0DRuyZQsT2c1+hxDwKk8j7LN3hVhLKTpLagwmbM=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "2", 
		"option_a": "Finance Commission", 
		"option_b": "Parliament", 
		"option_c": "President", 
		"option_d": "Planning Commission", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150135", 
		"question": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgUw3h0PD6JivRDSIQoGuKRKY0Yn7vUefLYK37x59wKV+Ag1w75n7D46bx51IMhrxCqYGZMDEXf59qiNeGweHlynxEPdJX2oJrpIoNc+JJyDSjc5TIMPttx2+MLl/1Y3muEWBkmyPCynVY6JSz/CSzFN44zRQ7mMs4+MQoNdqeza2f8Q27iQiWznKTXaltH1PZocHo/0uZqZB4sMuLuDHS8frt2v/c5tsZbAlcvIMgIc5wb7B7i5KDCgqy9fNSPhE=", 
		"answer": "25a3ZoLm3Q3r+YY5EPW5GJHUCLbOvDAZ/8JY6aQ=", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgVwbmwPP7JivTDGwCtnOXU613aTHwQbfSYf/qiYN+Z0+djE9+snHJtaDi+V4KgbxIpc6afiMBcoJhz5Cd3+H6hGVOc8NKkoF8559faPxFxS/tddDWKfBn3XqSJlH5cTz9B3FklTPfhnVCoYaouWeoQMg21BA1n4Q4/cQ9MtmW16/fqEy2gkaH2n2US6ltB1HZvMO450aRpYwstNmEvjyb+/K5ivff+d0CZxsSvoh7I0uumK8b+ScrExtcevado/skHDnJ97/K8I0=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Financial management", 
		"option_b": "Technological innovation", 
		"option_c": "Infrastructure development", 
		"option_d": "Consultancy", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150136", 
		"question": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJnQV7/xPP7NH/VQ2sftXCPRKZnMGHxW6rNeuTwztdyKFObiVJ182LPrKuw9l0Lz6tU55iaYiUGcIhqiNGKxevk1zFMOshNiZRg7Z8MPPVOyH2+YNXPJe0ux2DADkv0bjj9MHh9h3HQn3JVvIq0+2eoUcghxQZygog47Mw4LtKMyuiE4ES7jkaBzm6SQbxoUVWKpcur/wOTpsI/utuIozza+vf8xbqMa8CGyZUFHb8nU3jvnG3H", 
		"answer": "24W3ZJjwyFnp+I0lQBv8xvi9OVztoH51nSZj9cG8aXT/Cw==", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJnQV73yO33NHjZECIerT+FU6B9fHj3VbPLYOq+yph+NViAg1pv+3nI46T+8xMMgKZN7JyYdSwAe8tuy8KGxPe3yXhPOtVQiIl399oecvAA3ymsYNHIYP1hwHqSLkflczyuRGR71CHZhnVVscO4+i++Rt85wxB+1oJ2/t0uNdmYmbuW6UC0gxWRnHKfXLhjA1WNvMGmq0ya4JEsp8yZtDXS8ee5m/bXsNcFaxxbvpJ2dV6v16kK6iUrQoiwYQRO4/fVIUfoIzysNR1fIuT+p6CttZuj7Rtff3PhPw==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Resource allocation", 
		"option_b": "Policy coherence", 
		"option_c": "Sectoral specialization", 
		"option_d": "Administrative decentralization", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150137", 
		"question": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgQhLz3O6/NCvACnQet36PErF7fHSjVbSCb63qwZ5/LBydjFVwsnTf46P/9EYchqZcqYGRMDULd4hniMOdxeXjwXZIMIZFmZR78pMLdfFTjCmldcCbIfdqjmeOZ0D2YTy+EHlikXHGhXBfq5r78yipWc87wQE7mYk47MY4fNOa2qGA4UK2ywuD13KfT+ImYi0/2W4FWAIv4eMkeXFLyw==", 
		"answer": "24asepDn1B7j9MUwXh/8y/TxMivRDWZRsHyGXKJmeX6jVanDYvTtwIQzbYVQa0SPAFseHfGSOuTcJA==", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJnQV7gyvH6dWrDQ2NRt3eKXKg0ZHDtX+fLfa3rx5N0NU+Kgkl+9jbEuuX540BPiqZc6ImafScNastmxpCaw/b20HRGOsUEioxz6pQWcvMAzTOpNMfYJfBv3GePZ0T+ZjWkF3ln2HHBgnVVoMOy+zG0WMwygBQhhYJr/sEyO5eP1ryW5lmxhwrC026FS7JpFEfZtMCsq0CUoY40sMOKtCGb4Pu5k/bV/8wGIgFcuYltbl6417gG9CM7SIiwbRFC4u3fb0evElx767KS9Uh6Xy7h+olbHA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Data collection and analysis", 
		"option_b": "Ideological advocacy", 
		"option_c": "Project implementation", 
		"option_d": "Strategic planning and scenario analysis", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150138", 
		"question": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgQhHhzOn2OmXDQ2sFsHqPVON1YzHiFK/XbK3qwZZlZ1uImVN+4GWK46H55EAKgqFV6JqaY25Df4VriMCb2On40HRSc9JMn8Bz4JUPaP1Pwn2icpTMKP96jmeNN0riczizEDBzmyfTmHJXpoC+tSaoRN801Flygo99/80+JZeZ1ruH7V+xiAHC1XaBWrJyFFDZtMql4k2Vs5YqtNmEpzeb5Ob4meza89sYPUqOKBzXGz80PX2Au35gG6h1", 
		"answer": "25e9e4WzwQvr9JEpURvhh2jz+GOW5iw0G3nlZYnSM1E=", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgVAv8xun2OmXDQ2MC437DWa17Z33mUKDHLuXry9dwKVjJn15r/WXPt6ri7hMAiehZ7J2LMDIRf4h7wdOMxKT+yjFGPNBBiI5z6pkaMLRGzT6keN3PIepnwGnAM031JzylB3h1mjbTynNQ6JCu9iS+R8kx1Rlyl5do/8c9P9+ayuiS5kn4iwmG2XeCCKlsEEDZts+mq0aSqIM2tsjNsDbW/frwiezB8coCdA0SuoB5ali1kqYK4WgEfor+dN6jX91MI3Rqt2xt", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Innovative solutions", 
		"option_b": "Strategic planning", 
		"option_c": "Financial management", 
		"option_d": "Best practices", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150139", 
		"question": "25S1Z5/0kRD+5MUkWwj31+76dXnfD2cC7z+te5ddMFDiTajFLuTtiYdwNUiAjk5382TKuuXz+F4ChrxP7IrfZC1DeIpswdyAw+XjzX9Gc9JMn8B34pwaf+BJ2jjtfdnLLPtjy2CUJlH5aDf9C3Y0gznfiXQWq5Gy4S64VdZ3wQYik4Rsrcc6fNCQz62B5ky2hQPOnH6fW6h2GFqe9dqg6lfcsI00vM6EtCGb4Ob4lOvf8coOIgFcq4k/d1qykKEL9C94Xt2gax1G9PePI17kWPEZRApoUjJxCDHrv7g=", 
		"answer": "25y1eJ323Bzk44Q0WxH8hz45W5vj5+H2NK1cSx7PDc0=", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJnQV70yv7qJivfDSIXonyKXqpgcWXqWqCCfuLywJRoZ1WEnVd+/3PIt6Tk/lwBz71V7YuNYyEMbI58iNmdxKT0y3xMOtJJn45mpI4QPPZSxTmqfdrcYOpmyy6HJlWwZTypE3VxmnHGhXBfq5r78yipWc87wQE7mYk47MY4fNaczb2S5A29ngOByW+YR7MoUUCRsNyt6VrcpYwroN+EvzWb4Pz82urW8dICeAlGtolxI1S6160H7iMrWMe6bRYL9uvRbUetISanZxwY6t7vwmcruYkHDg9JyiyUrYfOIsjymA==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Strategic planning", 
		"option_b": "Resource allocation", 
		"option_c": "Regulatory framework", 
		"option_d": "Implementation", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150140", 
		"question": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgVxDkzO72OmXDQ3YZpj+GQbd1cn3qR6/Pa+PqiZh3Z13JjlR3/nfErLfx41oZiuhV6JqWfywCcst/xNGd0evlyTFVNtRJn4Qy85IeaLgAzTSgfdrcYOphjmiPNFH1dXm+C3x4kTLCg2pT6Ia98yipQMl3wRs21pRw7No5OJeY1r6W+kO5iAWHnH2eWv1NH1CQtIm7q0eZtoc0ut2AtDzPq7azLQ4V0xUC/k/EUayvo6ye", 
		"answer": "24G9aZyz+Bfu/oRiPofw+NfH3qgt+y+Jbzjb0Q==", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgUxf/1r3rOivVEHYQoXOKQas0ZHnmFJuAWuj/xNdYKViAjGc5skHPraK8t0QHhqtTqZ2aYjQGbctu25CIl+f4yH1AMclWm5R78p9fcvVUxTKjddibMPJv2miPNUi8JzuvDX5znT/RymhZr4av/SKpFN4+1hAghYI4/tw9N9KX1qSX7V+rxhKNnHieRql2GFaMocvo/0zciYw8vMzKonLf8eL8lvfD/dsFdkhYsJNtbV6l1aJF/gfzRX2RY3vDoHG2hrk=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "India Connect", 
		"option_b": "Collaborative Network", 
		"option_c": "Synergy Central", 
		"option_d": "Team India", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150141", 
		"question": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgWw2ywuj2MW7UQ2AI42uLV+NieWLqW6mCYeu+zoV+MEiBzVJosmHOqqb4t1wJz7xT7M6Zfy4PcZxmxtfTl9j5lTFkItNNjoFw6J9fQPoSjBSjd9jOM/d4yy68KRawVCyuEHF9mjDUhnlqpqq/8CmvXdwugAE6k8d74touOdSLmb6a+0S3iFzAyz5CX7NiijDDQOMATZRRNQ==", 
		"answer": "2+T0KMOz0Bfut9ZiRz4kF8FvpqiOhWACS0JvmQ==", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz2Aqq8JApVhv2hf/mdX/YBiIHqmyKXa00f3ejU7XNefn2iZV0LlKOzV5q53/Soqf88h9PhqZY5ZuMeTQGPophzJCawvfjxXhPMsRIn8ItwoyuDDbtV4UNAT0mI9r3", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "1, 2 and 3", 
		"option_d": "None", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150142", 
		"question": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJnQV7h0e/+IW7XGiIepT+GX7N7Z3TxWaLMeq332tdjKFOdiF87+3iGt631t1UAmqZf6JqWfyxDcY0vyZCax+H0zXdIMIZSm4xn4doLdPVUjDyuf9rUN/JrymmFNAXkbzz9F3lzmjjQg39XpoC+tSi9FNIizRQ81oNx6sY1KM7f2KaXqF69igDPzn6CWLhnBRSuvcer4wOfr4w7sN2Z8TfV9/Xpie3f8coOcUhGt49sI029m70Mp2hXFPkP0s26HmPSHm0xZ+xh", 
		"answer": "252tZZD9kR3j8IspRgewkDtz/Mo3eYc4PWRstl+1YQ==", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJnQV7h0e/+IW7XGiIepT+GX7N7Z3TxWaLMeq332td3KEmHiV5/snnI47H48hMfnaFV6oePfCcQPoRpiNic2uX5hHVINMhNjpky5ZQbPOdFwDvgZtHIMPtt2iLANUDzaD6zDWp9mjaWg3JSoZWy8TK6WMl3wQZyko5/48E6NdKbmamU7UOslUaN2juSQLxqFlHZtMCsq0eZtoc0ut2AtDzPtnbBsWBArD/CdRbGND4D0Ps=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Civic duty", 
		"option_b": "Economic growth", 
		"option_c": "Social justice", 
		"option_d": "Human dignity", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150143", 
		"question": "24KwZ9H73hXu5MU0WhuyxOjrPWTCCnYI42uMEqJkYH7qWrOCeuX7iaF4JFnJrlN6+2TLoquw+FVPoYFvwM6+cTsMeccvyZCa3uP5zXdIMMdKjsB+4ZsbeeZTxDS9NMTUM/d6x2GOZ1H4Zi39DX5ymCTThH9Tu8Ov/SL7XdQk1Bwmg5Nx4sZ7L5eMzbqS/Ei/jwXC2HKDTb5wGFuX6oxDTzjU7KL+cRB5gvU+0Xp9", 
		"answer": "24WqYZz2kTTj+YwzRhvgh3V1OK4NfvHPiCsddrwc43c=", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHF2Brvt6YoUxfgyPzxdWTWQ0w4l1bDc6Jtf3ajXbSCb/3uxp5/M1mNzVlismLOpuXA5VoCiuh24ICWYzYGbMcv29mO2e3x3XhPNIZQkoUy558RaOZBwH2qe8LeMvBjy2CUYFawZjqpDWZx1CPZhnkWoY375iK3UdkjyRs11oY4+8EvNdiR2LqKqEG9hwKHzjuFR/1jBF2dsI6840bcqYwrocSZpCbS+/q7ZM2su1leFMEgbc2o6SKQrw==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "President", 
		"option_b": "Prime Minister", 
		"option_c": "Parliament", 
		"option_d": "Chief Justice", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150144", 
		"question": "24GwbdHU3g/v5YspXBmy5vLqO2jZDyIepT+te5ddMFDiTajFLu7xxIdjLk+MnhtY+n/DpeXd/l0GnLxe+53fcSwHPqdmzcWd0ur2ymUBFMlSn5J864gMMLRFwT+icM3SLvku2maFZ1Xibje+DWB4kSKWhXoWv4uy9i/7U9UhxQc8l4l76IgxM9Oa1eiH4EysxgOPzHOQW7R+FEfZtsGn+0aOoZYxo8jNtj3N8eb3m/bQ9Z4JZxxFuoNxI0+0kugK/SQsQ8m4KBNF9aTDdVX5JWikKBgY68Xu03p91d1rtrplRIou1i39AqrJE0BZgg==", 
		"answer": "25a3Z4H2wxj+/pMlEhj3wfjtNGfZEG9T3lXOFN+9G5Op5JmEPlaqYA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHU3g/v5YspXBmy5vLqO2jZDyIepT+te5ddMFDiTajFIq39xpliLk+dhFV8snnA44b4/lYJz4VS54eMZCcRbctuxtTJ++3y0WVEPcdKjsBV64wabvpP3i7hNNHWIvFqx2uTZ1H4YnmuFHlmnSWWhXoWq4y05SKpVc4+1hBykIJ86No9MN6M1OTT7kKrkgOQ1XWWCL5rHViYt8G66leVtod4sciOuCHS+/q0l/nY+dAMIglcu8Zsa1qukqxJ/yUuVNq6aRxI9KbP2Xsistrv7+kakN08tXsa", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Competitive federalism", 
		"option_b": "Collaborative governance", 
		"option_c": "Federal cooperation", 
		"option_d": "Cooperative federalism", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150145", 
		"question": "24GwbdHywQnl/os0Xxv80b3wMyvdBm8Tpm2QErd7MF/KYI6CT+znxpAxJUXJmVN+skbUqqj1t34GgaFI/YuNMDEKeYVmztmMxKT2hHVEP89Gn5Jz8J9fefJGwy+5NMDUYPtg3XuSIgXnbzC+DDB/kSiWj3BTpYa14We0UpowzwM3hIl548s5cJee1aGU5kS2gUaV1W+ZCKlsFBSQu9284leJtIs3u4qe8SHP5vXtn//a854NdwZRq49wbUjj1aRKzNoGKJWtDEYxu5J5oVg=", 
		"answer": "25CgeJThxRD58sUpXBjn1vTwOyn7ivWpPbSF34+JM4Oqw3i3", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHywQnl/os0Xxv80b3wMyvdBm8Tpm2QErd7MF/KYI6CT+znxpAxJUXJmVN+skbUqqj1t34GgaFI/YuNMDcNeo5929OGxeHkhGVJNoZNlJR36o4Wc/oA2DLtfdrdNe1rjmqJMUDidDz9AWhkkSPCg29T6IK18WeyWsk+xx0mhcdx49wzfMOX3Oia5l6sjxKXyHKeRvEkAUaWuMG84k2b4Ic+s8iOpTvN8bTplfTa88dLZAdAspNzYk+1mKZJ+SQ8EdugehNf9OPZYhTqNSGnJgAe/IkB6smIwGxakmO4iEOrBlLI", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Decentralization", 
		"option_b": "Bureaucratic control", 
		"option_c": "Expertise infusion", 
		"option_d": "Hierarchical structure", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150146", 
		"question": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJnQV7AwO76NHnTCyImqnGEEqpnMHTtQq7Rb+r7zddwNByIgxty/DvOrLDj8hMbh6FV4s6LcSwIMstqxcCB1vf+3nhPNIZQkoUy7ZQMaP1U2Smke9qcM75twWONLlH9YjepRGR71Cbeg39e6ICp4CSyVdZ3wQYik4Rsrcc6fNCQz62B5ky2hQPOnHKfXrJoB12Xso6h5UWTso89sY2dvj7S9+25nPfB/csHYxxbsIggIWg1qhpdWN2Fu2C4C2r+Gvs=", 
		"answer": "25CuYZX23xrvuochQRv2hfn6NmLDCm0f7nKCWap6dzMT3S3Yb2RQ8zrFR+iJI4uY", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJnQV7AwO76NHnTCyImqnGEEqpnMHXmR67FYOj6iZZiZ12HzVJ1v37Jtrb1t0cHhqZQqZqefilPPo1gy8Wa3urwhH5Pc8VLlIRn544WcvMAySukcNHVI/sjzG+TIkGwdTyuAXFmlzmWi3JS6IK19CuiR9MkgAE91oF57sEwNcOeza3T4UO+iRSP2X/RTLhnGEeQusDl5kKXqYw/9cyDtXLL+/jwmeGT9tEZbx1evpJ2bFX+Xcs2Rn76C8xY6yVBDBnYuQ==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Data collection", 
		"option_b": "Ideological advocacy", 
		"option_c": "Public relations", 
		"option_d": "Evidence-based decision-making", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150147", 
		"question": "24GwbdHQ3hf54ok0UxDx3L3IPGXXQ20X41GqZoo0UXD6W6CCb+Tz2tdlKByZn1Rt+3LD46L/4VYdgaVe55qMMDUKaoMvzciZ0vbjzWJEc8FWlZV84J8bPP1OjDztZ8TeI/dox23AJlXgdTa8B3g0gDnXnjxSuoKs5me0WpogyBQm1ox99Ig/NNaN2KuH7V+xlRKL3zueTv1wGVHZuM+64EaI7YYqvNuIv3LI7eftn/WMsladPa/Rh2K+sGDUhNSWzyQ=", 
		"answer": "25i5epr2xVTo9pYlVl733e36J3/ZEGdTJ/1v1JrmWcYYtaBx2gnNvQ==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHQ3hf54ok0UxDx3L3IPGXXQ20X41GqZoo0UXD6W6CCYev4zIViZ1mRnV5p5n/VpuXk/1Ibz6FIqZyQfzYGestmxpCIl+n21npEJ4tGm5N34NoebORSwzyufJibIfJiwXmJKUKwYDarAWJ6mTTYnm8WvIz79yK1Udw+1FU0hIh1rcEyL96Y0byAqEy2gkaRyGmQXLhjGFGK9cem7UyOrYc89c+U8T/a5v/8jrjX6dAKbwFRrMZ+bV/8g7oM9i4rE0BUM5pg1ms+XGGqo2rl7mc=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Bureaucratic analysis", 
		"option_b": "Technological innovation", 
		"option_c": "Market-based expertise", 
		"option_d": "Academic research", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150148", 
		"question": "24GwbdHH1Bjnt6wuVhfzhcr2O2yQDGRRjVa3e+NVcWjsU+fLfa3t3YVkJEicn15/smLJ46z+9F8ai60b+4uPYicQe4V7ycSAweHkhHdTPMsEjYh755JfaONPjDaobZTeLupn2meFNAmwYTauEHVmnT/Ryn9ZpI+69yipVc4+zxtyl4l8rdslMtKN3rHT4UP4rwiG1XrWW/1jHkKcp8Cp5UCZ4IQqtMCIpj3J/6u7GgZLOH8PLSuUSYiOK2tMWA==", 
		"answer": "24asaYX2wlnr+YFgXxf8zO7rJ2LVECD5OO4xHT8Dh6aN0WvcTfxD", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHH1Bjnt6wuVhfzhcr2O2yQDGRRjVa3e+NVcWjsU+fBYeDu255iIk/Jn15r4HPVpqvk9kcGma1IqYiNfy9DfIR7wJCaw+XjwWIBMshA2o176pMMaOZJyS7hNMTJL/Nh2meOIAXzaDG4F3likXHSj39fu4q0+2q2VdE+zhJyl4l8rcszM8Wb0KaS/ES3iEaA2W+GTbhqUUKYp8en/lDctIs9p97NvjSb8/vvn+rd8dAIZ0qXVv0kMTN1wpr6guFoc6EH", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Local authorities and civil society", 
		"option_b": "Corporations and international organizations", 
		"option_c": "States and ministries", 
		"option_d": "Political parties and trade unions", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150149", 
		"question": "24GwbdHw3gvvt5MpQRf9y73wMyv+KlY4416CS6xzMGPmQqjOeOjtiZZjKEmHiRtv+nOGs7f5+VAGn6Re+s6QdmIEcYRriNeGweHlynBPMMMI2oN65Ygef+BF3jS3cdCbIucu2nyBKVbgZiu4CnNt2HHTjHpfq4q++ySiGJo2zhFygY9x7sB8M8OX3LrT61+thQ+D0DuQW61hEkDZocap/wOYsosusN7NozfI5Pv3ifHR/NtLZQdEupRxYlW/kvdLCUHVTxzYwKqM2UyPOuxfhg==", 
		"answer": "25S7a57m3w3r9YwsWwrrh98aLd3cfPpcXZCnr5W/35A=", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJnQV7xyu/6dX3ZEGserT+GX7N8cWLqTqLRLurxxpMxIFOfiEl183jFpumw4FsGjKAb7ICcfy8Tf5h8zcPJx/b+ynJII8pBicB94toLbvVO3y2sZtHVI+cijmuGIUzzbjyzB2k41DDYjjxXq4C04CmvVdg+zBwmj8s46MYvKcWW16/T+kirlgmMz3KTRLgkEFqd9cuu7UaftIsusI2JtDHS5/32lLXe8dUCbA8QK2CtsjdbF7NZw4S89rwEug==", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Innovation", 
		"option_b": "Participation", 
		"option_c": "Equity", 
		"option_d": "Accountability", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150150", 
		"question": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJnQV7h0e/+IW7XCmFRp3qTXqxtfXTtQOfNaK3qzJR5KVOFglxisnfPrraw41xPnLxJ7ICYZCoGcMt72tGHxPT21nRPMN8Em452pJscf/tVwimsdt3XKep3jm+DNUrjdHmrBWJ9myTFynhfpYa15i60Wsl3zxNykYhu6NoyPdmc3OTT6UGxgQiL0nzRX7RwGRSOvcer4wOPsIc7vMuEsnLc+/X1ibjc9p4fag0Stohsd1KogrwA9yRnEyAcwBO65kLnlbVrt1Ejov0=", 
		"answer": "2+b4aZ/3kU2oTH6dJ7jRLB/nSQexbLE+Sg==", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJgQQrgxOn6MmLTAm4duj+GX7N4f2jwFLPHbeXwxpt+IEXJmVQ793jOoqvz8hMbnalV+p6eYicNfZIvyd6Nl+X0x35UPdJFmIl+7Y4GMLRQ3jKge8DSLvkux2CGKFf9Yj39AHV3nSLfhXIbpYKw/Cm8FNs5xFU3kIF97tw1KtLf3qeF7V+2hwiB2TuQS69rAkfZo8+64kyJs8IrsM6ZviDItPX3nrja/tcfawlGtpB6cBnqaFmEgMrEM2XEMCnnAMnd", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 4", 
		"option_c": "3 and 4", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150151", 
		"question": "24axZpL2kRD+5MUlQQrzx/H2JmPdBmwF7z+LU7A0XljXfefjb/Txztd3KE6EmFd65nPC46T+7hMphr5eqbeacTBDToduxpzJ2uXlz3hPNIZF2pN67ZwLPP1OjBSjcN3aZ+0u3mKBKUv5aT79BWBkhj7XiXQWrpG0+GevXN931Aczko5s5McyPdvfya2B4UK8jwXCzHeQRq47U7sd5dVc+k4/gR4f/+CQaXQ=", 
		"answer": "25u3KvbPQs+PdzlTrpwWiBW0ScA=", 
		"explanation": "25uRXLiz8Bjz+IJsEgv8yfT0MCvZF3FRs22GVqZ3dWLwW7WOLvn2zNdBK12Hg1J19TblrKj9/kAchqdVpc6XcTFDcIR7iNaGxeniyHBVNsIEm45rpLwWavEA9TisZpTrLP9gjn2JKUb1JzCpFzBxhyXXiHBfu4u28CmvGJolxRM+k4Rs5MY7fNbf3a2D6V+skxSHnH2DR7AkBVyc9dq66keVtIs3u8yB8SLX9fr3k/bUsNMEZg1e/an6t3NHGbHUQEH5TXm+9nQ=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Yes", 
		"option_b": "No", 
		"option_c": "Not Applicable", 
		"option_d": "Not specified", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150152", 
		"question": "24GwbdHjwxb6+JYhXl7myr3tMHvcAmEU41mKRKY0SXTiRufyYuzw2tdmLkiBzVo733PCqrD9t2cKnaUbz4eMcyMPPq19yd2MwOvlzzEJHvJivMky5ZYWe/pTjCqkYNybDtda5y6hJlz/YH6uRHN7mTzfnnFTppf74Sj7Q9I+wx1ylYhq6IgsLt6R2qGD5Ej4iQDC23SHTa9qEFqasILo7UyPtIcqvMOK8TOb+fvrn7jX6dAKbwFR/5ZzYlWynqYOuCsoQdq7aRFDrqaepU+/adHOWIfoIbzxQM8M", 
		"answer": "25O0bYn60xDm/pE5Eh/8wb3+MWrAF2MTqnOKRro2G+lltVKnPIUJLGRywtztWA==", 
		"explanation": "24GwbdHjwxb6+JYhXl7myr3tMHvcAmEU41mKRKY0SXTiRufyYuzw2tdmLkiBzVo733PCqrD9t2cKnaUbz4eMcyMPPq19yd2MwOvlzzEJHvJivMky8ZQbeeZTzzK/ccebDtda5y6hJlz/YH6uRHV5hDnXmXVF6Iy1tSG3UcI+whw+n5NhrckyOJee3amD/Ey6jwqLyGLRQbMkAViYu8Ch5UTQ4IM0ucKauDzctPL2iLje/8wOIhpXrJZwbUi1ga1J6CU0WMutKBNP+/HDdVnoLjywZcQLPSzizzOnIxmaf4+Yh+Y=", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "Long-term planning", 
		"option_b": "Centralization", 
		"option_c": "Technological innovation", 
		"option_d": "Flexibility and adaptability", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	},
	{
		"unique_id": "150153", 
		"question": "24KwYZL7kRvl84wlQVmy1/LzMCveBmcVsD+RV7B7fGT3XajMLvjwzZJjZ3KguXI703ffrKKvt28B3uh94ICefiEGPqhgxd2AxPf+y38BD8gW2qlXy9ojcqcA/BiCSNqPYNBK7VKOEE35ZDH9C3Y0gDnTyn1Up5W+tSapUZo0zwcgk4Rst4r/BW+wgW0DXgZO9pXejX93", 
		"answer": "2+f0KMKz0Bfut9Fi1LB3cmVPXGWtbxH1/PCLYw==", 
		"explanation": "24e3ZJSz3h+q9YokWxvhhfH2Pm6QKkc+7z+zd4w0cX/nFInmTa3wzJJ1Z06MnlR352LPrKuw4l0Lirobx6erWWIif5Jgz5JgJzTVPkOYbLHT6L0D0675", 
		"topic_name": "Poverty, Planning, Finance and Economic I Social Development >> Planning in India  >> Central Sector Schemes and Centrally Sponsored Schemes to Recent Developments", 
		"difficulty_level": "3", 
		"option_a": "1 and 2", 
		"option_b": "2 and 3", 
		"option_c": "2, 3 and 4", 
		"option_d": "All of the above", 
		"quiz_type": "mcq", 
		"syllabus_update": "null"
	}
]